<bill session="104" type="h" number="1120" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Employment Enhancement Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the consolidation of Federal employment assistance programs, to provide increased notice of the availability of the earned income tax credit, and to repeal the temporary FUTA surtax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411997"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400019" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="401547" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400083" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404367" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400149" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405033" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1995-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405317" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="405560" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400187" joined="1995-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400209" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407817" joined="1995-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1995-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1995-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409718" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="411214" joined="1995-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1995-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1995-03-02" withdrawn="1995-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1995-03-02" withdrawn="1995-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E501-502"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Agriculture, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>See H.R.4.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education, Training, Employment and Housing.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG26" subcommittee="Department Operations, Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSVR07" subcommittee="Education, Training, Employment and Housing" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="4"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Affordable housing"/>
    <term name="Age and employment"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Displaced homemakers"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Employment tax credits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grandparents"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in social service"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Consolidation of Federal Employment Assistance Programs Subtitle A: Block Grants to States Subtitle B: Consolidation and Repeal of Certain Federal Employment Assistance Programs Subtitle C: Effective Dates Title II: Notice of Availability of Earned Income Credit Title III: Repeal of Temporary Futa Surtax Employment Enhancement Reform Act - Title I: Consolidation of Federal Employment Assistance Programs - Subtitle A: Block Grants to States - Establishes a block grant program to prepare individuals for employment by increasing their occupational and educational skills. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to make such grants, for up to five-year periods subject to annual approval and availability of appropriations, to States to provide employment assistance to eligible individuals. Reserves funds for grants to Indian tribes and migrant and seasonal farmworker organizations. (Sec. 103) Allocates such grants to States on the basis of relative numbers of: (1) unemployed in areas of substantial unemployment; (2) excess unemployed; and (3) economically disadvantaged adults. (Sec. 104) Sets forth requirements for applications, use of grants, and conduct of State programs. Requires State programs to provide employment assistance to the following types of eligible individuals: (1) economically disadvantaged and 14 years or older; (2) certain types of dislocated workers; (3) individuals with disabilities; (4) Armed Forces members being separated under other than adverse conditions; (5) unemployed veterans; and (6) displaced homemakers. Requires States to: (1) profile and evaluate individuals to determine the employment assistance services to be provided; (2) notify individuals of other sources of supportive services; (3) provide appropriate employment assistance, within specified limits; (4) monitor rates of individuals successfully obtaining employment after separation from the program, according to specified criteria; and (5) establish one-stop-shop centers throughout the State for program information and profiling and evaluation. Authorizes certain discretionary activities under State programs. (Sec. 107) Directs the Secretary to make biennial determinations of State success in placing individuals in employment. Authorizes reduction or termination of payments when a State has not been successful, and reinstatement or increase of payments when a State implements appropriate modifications of its program. (Sec. 110) Authorizes appropriations. Subtitle B: Consolidation and Repeal of Certain Federal Employment Assistance Programs - Chapter 1: Consolidation of Programs - Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to eliminate community mental health services demonstration projects for homeless individuals who are chronically mentally ill. (Sec. 112) Amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to add requirements for State collaborative programs of supported employment services for individuals with the most severe disabilities, special recreation activities and services, and projects with industry. Repeals other provisions for special project grants for supported employment programs, special recreational programs, projects with industry, and supported employment services for individuals with severe disabilities. Chapter 2: Repeal of Programs - Repeals Higher Education Act of 1965 provisions for special programs for students whose families are engaged in migrant and seasonal farm work. (Sec. 122) Repeals: (1) the disabled veterans outreach program and the local veterans employment representative program under Federal law relating to veterans; and (2) the homeless veterans reintegration project under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act. (Sec. 123) Repeals: (1) the Foster Grandparent and Senior Companion programs under the Domestic Volunteer Service Act; (2) employment and training program provisions under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 (but allowing college students who are parents responsible for care of a dependent child under age six to be eligible for the food stamp program); and (3) the older American community service employment program under the Older Americans Act of 1965. (Sec. 124) Repeals the Job Training Partnership Act, except those provisions relating to the Job Corps. Authorizes appropriations for the Job Corps. (Sec. 125) Repeals the Appalachian vocational and other educational facilities and operations program under the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965. (Sec. 126) Repeals certain provisions relating to rules for computing the targeted jobs credit under the Internal Revenue Code. (Sec. 127) Repeals the JOBS (Job Opportunities and Basic Skills training) program provisions for recipients of AFDC (Aid to Families With Dependent Children) under the Social Security Act. (Sec. 128) Repeals: (1) the Service Members Occupational Conversion and Training Act of 1992; (2) the Adult Education Act; (3) the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act; (4) the National Literacy Act of 1991; and (5) the Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Demonstration Act of 1992. (Sec. 133) Repeals special programs relating to adult education for Indians, under the Indian Education Act of 1988. (Sec. 134) Repeals special Social Security Act provisions relating to Indian tribes and JOBS training programs. (Sec. 135) Repeals provisions for the VISTA Literacy Corps under the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973. (Sec. 136) Repeals: (1) the Wagner-Peyser Act (employment agencies); (2) the adult education for the homeless grants program and the job training for the homeless demonstration grants program under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act; (3) the trade adjustment assistance for workers program under the Trade Act of 1974; (4) FY 1993 and 1994 authorizations of appropriations for certain grants, as well as certain technical assistance conditions, under the Homeownership and Opportunity through HOPE Act; and (5) the State legalization impact-assistance grants program under the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986. Subtitle C: Effective Dates - Sets forth effective dates. Title II: Notice of Availability of Earned Income Credit - Amends the Social Security Act and the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to require that notice of availability of the earned income tax credit be provided to applicants for and former recipients of AFDC, Medicaid, or food stamps. (Sec. 202) Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to require printing of a notice of the availability of the earned income tax credit and the dependent care tax credit on W-4 forms for employee withholding exemptions. Title III: Repeal of Temporary FUTA Surtax - Repeals the temporary FUTA (Federal Unemployment Tax Act) surtax under the Internal Revenue Code.</summary>
</bill>
