<bill session="105" type="hc" number="59" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Concerning the return of or compensation for wrongly confiscated foreign properties in formerly Communist countries and by certain foreign financial institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1997-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1997-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-04-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E617-618"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-04-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="sc" number="19"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Communism"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Czech Republic"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Expropriation"/>
    <term name="Fascism"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="National socialism"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Slovakia"/>
    <term name="Warsaw Pact countries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/1997--Introduced.
Welcomes the efforts of many post-Communist countries to address the status of plundered properties. Urges: (1) countries to return plundered properties to their rightful owners or, as an alternative, to pay just compensation; and (2) post-Communist countries to pass and effectively implement laws that provide for restitution of, or compensation for, plundered property. Calls for: (1) the return of property formerly belonging to Jewish communities as a means of redressing the problems of aging and destitute survivors of the Holocaust; and (2) the Czech Republic, Latvia, Lithuania, Romania, Slovakia, and other countries to remove restrictions which require those whose properties have been wrongfully plundered by Nazi or Communist regimes to reside in or have the citizenship of the country from which they seek restitution or compensation. Calls upon foreign financial institutions, and the states having legal authority over their operation, that possess wrongfully and illegally property confiscated from Holocaust victims, from residents of former Warsaw Pact states who were forbidden by Communist law from obtaining restitution of such property, and from states that were occupied by Nazi, Fascist, or Communist forces, to assist and to cooperate fully with efforts to restore this property to its rightful owners.</summary>
</bill>
