<bill session="106" type="hc" number="230" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the strong opposition of Congress to the continued egregious violations of human rights and the lack of progress toward the establishment of democracy and the rule of law in Belarus and calling on President Alexander Lukashenka to engage in negotiations with the representatives of the opposition and to restore the constitutional rights of the Belarusian people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400585"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2416"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="sc" number="75"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Belarus"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Parliamentary government"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/16/1999--Introduced.
Condemns: (1) the current Belarusian regime; and (2) the arrests of Anatoly Lebedko, Nikolay Statkevich, and Valery Shchukin.Declares that Congress is gravely concerned about the disappearances of Viktor Gonchar, Yuri Krasovsky, Yuri Zakharenka, Tamara Vinnikova, and other members of the opposition.Calls for: (1) immediate dialogue between President Lukashenka and the Consultative Council of Belarusian opposition and the restoration of a civilian, democratically elected government in Belarus; and (2) a duly constituted national legislature, the rule of law, and an independent judiciary.Urges President Lukashenka to: (1) respect the human rights of all Belarusian citizens, including those members of the opposition who are currently being illegally detained in violation of their constitutional rights; and (2) make good on his promise to hold free parliamentary elections in 2000.Expresses support for the appeal by the Consultative Council of Belarusian opposition parties to the Government of Russia, the State Duma, and the Federation Council for a cessation of support for Lukashenka's regime.Calls on: (1) the international community to support the opposition by continuing to meet with the legitimately elected parliament; and (2) the President of the United States to continue to fund travel to the United States by the Belarusian opposition figures, to provide funding for the nongovernmental organizations in Belarus, and to support information flows into Belarus.</summary>
</bill>
