<amendment session="105" chamber="h" number="136" updated="2013-07-17T07:51:35-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="1757" sequence="8"/>
  <status datetime="1997-06-04">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <offered datetime="1997-06-04"/>
  <description>Amendments authorize certain U.S. citizen employees to perform designated consular officer duties; clarify that the Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security is responsible for diplomatic security and management; increase the authorized strength of the Foreign Service; establish the policy that the United States shall not expel, extradite, or otherwise effect the involuntary return of any person to a country in which there is a substantial danger of torture; express the sense of Congress that the Government of Turkey recognize the Ecumenical Patriarch and its nonpolitical, religious mission and reopen the Halki Patriarchal School of Theology; and require a report dealing with the repatriation of unresolved POW/MIA remains from Viet Nam.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment consisiting of several amendments, offered en bloc, to do the following: allow non-Foreign Service Government employees to perform consular functions; specify qualifications for the position of Assistant Secretary for Diplomatic Security; change the authorized strength of the Foreign Service; change the provisions of the bill concerning return of persons to countries where they may be subject to torture; and a technical amendment regarding the ecumenical patriarchate in Istanbul, Turkey.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-06-04T17:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendments (A008) offered by Mr. Gilman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-04T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Gilman amendments (A008) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Serrano demanded a separate vote on the Gilman amendments (A008).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-11T14:44:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Gilman amendments (A008) Agreed to by recorded vote: 428 - 0 (Roll no. 186).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
