<bill session="105" type="h" number="4144" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cumberland Island Preservation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To ensure the protection of natural, cultural, and historical resources in Cumberland Island National Seashore and Cumberland Island Wilderness in the State of Georgia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400221"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National seashores"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1998--Introduced.
Cumberland Island Preservation Act - Adjusts the boundaries of the Cumberland Island Wilderness, Georgia, to exclude and to include certain lands if the proposed land exchange being negotiated between the Secretary of the Interior and the Nature Conservancy and High Point, Inc., is agreed to with regard to Cumberland Island National Seashore and Cumberland Island Wilderness. Excludes the main road on Cumberland Island (as described on the register of national historic places), the spur road that provides access to Plum Orchard mansion, and such limited area on each side of these roads as necessary, from the boundaries of the Cumberland Island Wilderness and the potential wilderness area. Requires the Secretary to: (1) restore Plum Orchard mansion at Cumberland Island National Seashore so that the condition of the restored mansion is at least equal to the condition of the mansion when it was donated to the United States; and (2) submit a comprehensive plan for the repair, stabilization, and restoration of the mansion to such condition. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to: (1) identify, document, and protect archaeological sites located on Federal land within the Seashore; and (2) prepare and implement a plan to preserve designated national historic sites within the Seashore. Designates, subject to valid existing rights and pre-existing uses, a specified parcel of Federal land within Cumberland Island National Seashore as wilderness and a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Adjusts the boundaries of the Cumberland Island Wilderness to include the parcel.</summary>
</bill>
