<bill session="104" type="hr" number="134" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives concerning the receipt of gifts from lobbyists and other persons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="401310" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400070" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400099" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300040" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400517" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400649" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400244" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1995-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407465" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408839" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409718" joined="1995-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1995-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/1995--Introduced.
Amends rule XLIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives to revise provisions regarding the acceptance of gifts by Members, officers, or employees of the House. Prohibits Members, officers, or employees from accepting gifts from lobbyists registered under the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act, the Foreign Agents Registration Act, or any successor statute unless: (1) the lobbyist is a member of the immediate family of the Member, officer, or employee to whom the gift was made; or (2) the Member, officer, or employee did not have reason to know that the gift was given because of his or her official position, was given through a member of the Member's, officer's, or employee's immediate family or an entity controlled by the Member, officer, or employee, or was given by a lobbyist who was reimbursed or provided compensation for the gift's value or deducted the gift's value from his or her Federal income tax liability and the Member, officer, or employee disclosed the gift to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct. Bars House Members, officers, or employees from accepting a gift from persons other than lobbyists unless conditions described above under which gifts may be accepted from lobbyists apply to such a person or the gift: (1) consisted of a meal; (2) was a contribution to a legal defense fund established for the Member's, officer's, or employee's benefit; (3) was an extension of personal hospitality; or (4) was attendance at a charity, conference, association dinner, or other widely-attended event. Lists items that are not considered to be gifts, including: (1) informational material; (2) receptions and food and refreshments of a nominal value; (3) products from the home State of the Member which are of nominal value; (4) objects of little intrinsic value; or (5) payments or reimbursements for reasonable expenses for travel, for a period not exceeding three days within the United States or seven days outside the United States, exclusive of travel time, to events related to the Member's, officer's, or employee's official duties, subject to certain conditions. Authorizes the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to waive gift restrictions in unusual circumstances and to make such waivers public.</summary>
</bill>
