<bill session="106" type="h" number="341" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Environmental Priorities Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Fund for Environmental Priorities to be funded by a portion of the consumer savings resulting from retail electricity choice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Deregulation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/19/1999--Introduced.
Environmental Priorities Act of 1999 - Makes this Act effective for a consumer sector in any State in the first year after all of a State's regulated and nonregulated electric utilities have established retail electric service choice for customers in such sector, but no earlier than 2002. Requires providers of retail electric services to contribute to the fiscal agent for the Environmental Priorities Board (established by this Act) ten percent of the total consumer savings for the consumer sector for that calendar year. Defines: (1) "consumer savings" as the amount by which the potential rate for electric energy provided to a consumer sector exceeds the current rate for the sector, multiplied by the sector's total consumption (in kilowatt-hours) during a calendar year; and (2) "potential rate" as the average kilowatt-hour rate paid by the provider's customers in that sector during the 12-month period preceding the date on which retail electric service choice was established, adjusted for inflation. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a National Environmental Priorities Board. Directs the Board to: (1) establish regulations governing creation of an Environmental Priorities Program, to include criteria and methods of selecting State projects to receive support; and (2) enter into arrangements with a non-federal fiscal agent to receive and disburse contributions described by this Act. Authorizes States in which retail electric service choice has been established for any consumer sector to establish public purpose programs and apply for matching funding to support environmental priorities programs. Requires the fiscal agent to distribute contributions to States to carry out such programs.</summary>
</bill>
