<bill session="106" type="h" number="1356" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Freedom From Sexual Trafficking Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To end international sexual trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="1999-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1999-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1999-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1999-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1999-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400584" joined="1999-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="1999-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1999-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1999-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400219" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1999-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="1999-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="1999-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1999-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400320" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1999-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400507" joined="1999-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="1999-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="1999-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="1999-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400394" joined="1999-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1999-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1999-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sex-oriented businesses"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1999--Introduced.
Freedom From Sexual Trafficking Act of 1999 - Declares that the purpose of this Act is to eliminate international sexual trafficking in which women and children are brought across international boundaries by means of force or fraud for purposes of forced prostitution, sexual slavery, and similar practices. (Sec. 4) Sets forth minimum international standards for the elimination of sexual trafficking. (Sec. 5) Establishes in the Office of the Secretary of State an Office for the Protection of Victims of Trafficking, to be administered by a director appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require the Secretary to include in a certain human rights report, among other things, information on sexual trafficking and the efforts of a country to prevent it. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the status of international sexual trafficking, including a list of any countries that do not meet the minimum international standards for the elimination of such trafficking. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations for assistance administered through nongovernmental organizations: (1) to foreign countries in programs and activities designed to meet the minimum international standards for the elimination of sexual trafficking, including drafting of legislation to prohibit and punish acts of sexual trafficking, investigation and prosecution of sexual trafficking, and facilities, programs, and activities for the protection of victims; and (2) for programs and activities to assist victims of sexual trafficking in the United States. (Sec. 7) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish a nonimmigrant visa category for an alien (including spouse, married and unmarried sons and daughters, and parents of such alien) who the Attorney General determines: (1) is physically present in the United States; (2) is or has been a victim of sexual trafficking; (3) has not unreasonably refused to assist in the investigation or prosecution of acts of sexual trafficking (or has not attained age 14); and (4) would face a significant possibility of retribution or other hardship if removed from the United States. Denies such person eligibility for admission to the United States if there is substantial reason to believe that the person has committed an act of sexual trafficking. Directs the Attorney General to determine whether a ground for inadmissibility exists with respect to such nonimmigrant alien. Authorizes the Attorney General to waive the requirements of this Act if it is in the national interest. Authorizes the Attorney General to adjust the status of the nonimmigrant alien (and spouse, married and unmarried sons and daughters, and parents of such alien) to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States (provided such alien was not a participant in Nazi persecutions or genocide) if such nonimmigrant alien: (1) has been physically present in the United States for a continuous period of at least three years; (2) has, throughout such period, been a person of good moral character; (3) has not, during such period, unreasonably refused to provide assistance in the investigation or prosecution of acts of sexual trafficking; and (4) would face a significant possibility of retribution or other hardship if removed from the United States. (Sec. 8) Declares it to be U.S. policy not to provide nonhumanitarian foreign assistance to countries which do not meet minimum standards for the elimination of sexual trafficking. (Sec. 9) Amends Federal criminal law to subject to both civil (including forfeiture) and criminal penalties anyone who, whether inside or outside the United States, for the purpose of causing a person under age 18 (by fraud, force, or coercion) to engage in a commercial sexual act, knowingly does or attempts or conspires to: (1) transport the person across an international border; (2) recruit, entice, harbor, or engage in the purchase or sale of the person, who will then be or has been transported across an international border; or (3) own, manage, operate, or share in the proceeds of an enterprise in which the person has been transported across an international border.</summary>
</bill>
