<bill session="105" type="h" number="4278" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Benefits in Federal Contracting Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the provision of health care benefits under Federal contracts and subcontracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1998-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400227" joined="1998-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/20/1998--Introduced.
Health Benefits in Federal Contracting Act of 1998 - Requires any employer under a Federal contract or subcontract for an amount exceeding $10,000, to provide to each of his or her employees under such contract or subcontract health benefits similar (as specified) to those provided to Federal employees. Provides exemptions with respect to: (1) employers that are small business concerns or nonprofit, tax-exempt organizations; and (2) employees who are employed for less than 17.5 hours per week, who otherwise have health benefits coverage, or who are participating in a training program of not to exceed 6 months. Requires the contract or subcontract to specify such requirement. Prohibits an employer from avoiding the requirement by: (1) replacing an employee with one who is not eligible for health care benefits; or (2) reducing an employee's hours. Terminates the Federal contract or subcontract of an employer who does not provide the health benefits required. Makes such employer: (1) ineligible for any Federal contract or subcontract for five years; and (2) liable to the United States in an amount equal to the unpaid benefits and an equal amount as liquidated damages. Requires the Secretary of Labor to pay to employees who were not provided such benefits the amount recovered by the United States.</summary>
</bill>
