<bill session="107" type="h" number="37" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-11-20">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail Amendments Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">National Trails System Willing Seller Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Old Spanish Trail Recognition Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Trails System Act to update the feasibility and suitability studies of 4 national historic trails and provide for possible additions to such trails.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2001-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2001-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2001-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400142" joined="2001-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400158" joined="2001-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2001-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2001-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2001-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2001-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-02-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-89.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-06-06T10:00:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="45">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 45.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Jones (NC) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2897-2899" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:27:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-06-06T10:36:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2897-2898" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-06-06T10:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-03-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-07-31">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 107-259.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-09-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="576">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 576.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-11-20">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/19/2002 S11637-11639" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 11/19/2002 S11637-11638" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-11-20">
      <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2002-11-20" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-11-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="National Parks" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Mormons"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4974"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/20/2002--Passed Senate amended.
Title I: National Historic Trails Studies - (Sec. 101) Amends the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to revise the feasibility and suitability studies for the Oregon, Pony Express, California, and Mormon Pioneer National Historic Trails for consideration of possible additions of specified routes as components of those Trails. Directs the Secretary to undertake a study of specified shared routes of the California Trail and the Oregon Trail to determine the feasibility and suitability of designating one or more of the routes as shared components of the California National Historic Trail and the Oregon National Historic Trail.Title II: National Trails System Acquisition Authorities - National Trails System Willing Seller Act - (Sec. 203) Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of the department with jurisdiction over a national scenic or historic trail should: (1) cooperate with appropriate State and local officials and private persons with an interest in the trail to pursue development of the trail; and (2) be granted sufficient authority to purchase lands and interests in lands from willing sellers that are critical to the completion of the trail.(Sec. 204) Prohibits the Federal Government from acquiring land or interest in land outside the exterior boundaries of any federally administered area for the following trails unless the consent of the owner thereof is obtained: (1) the North Country National Scenic Trail; (2) the Ice Age National Scenic Trail; and (3) the Potomac Heritage National Scenic Trail.Title III: Old Spanish Trail National Historic Trail - Old Spanish Trail Recognition Act of 2002 - Establishes the Old Spanish National Historic Trail, which shall extend from Santa Fe, New Mexico, to Los Angeles, California, and which shall be administered by the Secretary. Prohibits the Federal Government from acquiring land or interest in land outside the exterior boundaries of any federally administered area for the trail unless the consent of the owner thereof is obtained. Allows the Secretary to designate additional routes to the trail under specified circumstances.Title IV: Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail Addition - Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail Amendments Act of 2002 - Adds an additional route to the Lewis and Clark National Historic trail, running from the Falls of the Ohio in Clarksville, Indiana, and Louisville, Kentucky, to Wood River, Illinois.</summary>
</bill>
