<bill session="107" type="h" number="4657" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to implement the Calfed Bay-Delta Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400290"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2002-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-02">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-02">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental justice"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Estuarine ecology"/>
    <term name="Estuarine pollution"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline water conversion"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/2002--Introduced.
Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act - Approves the August 28, 2000, Federal Record of Decision issued by specified Federal agencies and supported by California as a framework for addressing Calfed Bay-Delta Program components consisting of water storage, ecosystem restoration, water supply reliability, conveyance, water use efficiency, water quality, water transfers, watersheds, the Environmental Water account, levee stability, governance, and science.Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to implement Stage 1 (projects and programs planned for the first seven years) if such activity has been subject to Federal and State environmental review and approval and certified to be consistent with the Record of Decision.Requires specific congressional authorization for projects and acquisitions with a Federal share in excess of $10 million.Requires the Federal agencies to: (1) coordinate their activities with the Resources Agency of California, the California Environmental Protection Agency, and the California Department of Food and Agriculture; (2) cooperate with local and tribal governments and the public; and (3) implement the Program using the best available scientific information and scientific review.Directs the Secretary and the Federal agency heads to operate under the Calfed Bay-Delta Program Implementation Memorandum of Understanding until the Memorandum is replaced by a permanent governing structure developed with their State counterparts.Sets forth authorization and reporting requirements for construction and acquisition activities where the Federal share exceeds $10 million.Directs the Secretary to provide financial assistance for the construction of projects in: (1) the Southern California Comprehensive Water Reclamation and Reuse Study; and (2) the San Francisco Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program.Requires the Secretary to assist State and local water agencies in California in preparing studies of water projects to: (1) ensure a long-term, high quality, safe, and adequate supply of municipal water to California residents; (2) reduce dependence on less reliable water supplies; and (3) assist the State in limiting its annual use of Colorado River water to no more than 4,400,000 acre-feet per year in normal years.Directs the Secretary to review any feasibility level studies for completed seawater desalination and regional brine line projects and report to Congress for the purposes of providing design and construction assistance for such projects.</summary>
</bill>
