<bill session="105" type="h" number="2589" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-25T14:19:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-25T14:19:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Copyright Term Extension bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Copyright Term Extension Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Copyright Term Extension Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Fairness in Musical Licensing Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Sonny Bono Copyright Term Extension Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the provisions of title 17, United States Code, with respect to the duration of copyright, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="401587" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400574" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400144" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400154" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1997-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1997-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-04">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-18T14:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 105-452.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-03-18T14:45:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="258">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 258.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-24T18:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 390 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2589 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T10:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 390 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T10:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 390.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1458-1483" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T10:56:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2589 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 390 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T10:57:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Terry Everett to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T10:58:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:17:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2589.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:18:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:18:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-03-25T14:19:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Coble asked unanimous consent that the Clerk be authorized in the engrossment of the bill H.R. 2589 to insert "Sonny Bono" before "Copyright Term Extension Act" each place it appears in the bill. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25T14:19:00-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2589.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26">
      <text>For Further Action See S.505.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="390"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="789"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="505"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="s" number="505"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Copyright royalties"/>
    <term name="Direct broadcast satellites"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Electronics industry"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="License agreements"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Motion picture industry"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Phonorecords"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television relay systems"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h531"/>
    <amendment number="h532"/>
    <amendment number="h533"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/25/1998--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Copyright Term Extension Title II: Music Licensing Title I: Copyright Term Extension - Sonny Bono Copyright Term Extension Act - Amends Federal copyright provisions regarding preemption of laws concerning duration of copyrights. (Sec. 102) Prohibits the annulment or limitation of rights or remedies under State laws with respect to sound recordings fixed before February 15, 1972, until February 15, 2067 (currently, 2047). Extends the duration of copyright in a work created on or after January 1, 1978, to the life of the author and 70 (currently, 50) years after the author's death. Makes the same extension with regard to joint works created on or after such date. Extends the duration of copyright in anonymous or pseudonymous works or works made for hire on or after such date to 95 (currently, 75) years from the year of the first publication, or 120 (currently, 100) years from the year of creation, whichever expires first. Makes conforming extensions with respect to provisions regarding the presumption of an author's death. Extends from December 31, 2027, to December 31, 2047, the duration of copyright in works published on or before December 31, 2002. Extends the duration of copyrights in their renewal term at the time of the effective date of this Act to 95 years from the date such copyrights were originally secured. Permits an author or owner of a termination right, subject to certain conditions, to terminate a transfer or license of a renewal (executed before January 1, 1978) of a copyright (other than a work made for hire) subsisting in its renewal term on the effective date of this Act, for which the termination right has not been exercised, and has expired, by such date. Allows termination of a transfer or license grant at any time during the five years beginning at the end of 75 years from the date the copyright was originally secured. (Sec. 103) Revises provisions regarding termination of certain transfers and licenses granted by the author or covering extended renewal terms to provide that if the author's widow, widower, children, and grandchildren are not living, the author's executor, administrator, personal representative, or trustee shall own the author's entire termination interest. (Sec. 104) Allows, during the last 20 years of any term of copyright of a published work, a library or archives to reproduce, distribute, display, or perform in facsimile or digital form a copy or phonorecord of such work for purposes of preservation, scholarship, or research after determining that none of the following conditions apply: (1) the work is subject to normal commercial exploitation; (2) a copy or phonorecord of the work can be obtained at a reasonable price; or (3) the copyright owner or its agent provides notice that either of such conditions applies. Provides that such exemption does not apply to any subsequent uses by users other than such library or archives. (Sec. 105) Expresses the sense of the Congress that owners of copyrights for audiovisual works for which the term of copyright protection is extended by the amendments made by this title, and the screenwriters, directors, and performers of those audiovisual works, should negotiate in good faith in an effort to reach a voluntary agreement or voluntary agreements regarding the establishment of a fund or other mechanism for the amount of remuneration to be divided among the parties for the exploitation of those audiovisual works. (Sec. 106) Sets forth provisions regarding the assumption of certain contractual obligations with respect to the transfer of copyright ownership in motion pictures that are produced subject to collective bargaining agreements. Title II: Music Licensing - Fairness in Musical Licensing Act of 1998 - Revises Federal copyright law to provide that communication by electronic device of a transmission embodying a performance or display of a nondramatic musical work by the public reception of a broadcast, cable, satellite, or other transmission shall not be a copyright infringement if: (1) the rooms or areas within the establishment where the transmission is intended to be received by the general public are less than 3,500 square feet, excluding space for customer parking; (2) the areas exceed such square footage limitation but only a limited number of speakers or audio visual devices are employed; (3) no direct charge is made to see or hear the transmission; (4) the transmission is not further transmitted beyond the establishment where it is received; and (5) the transmission is licensed. Excludes as a copyright infringement the performance of a nondramatic musical work by a commercial establishment at no charge when a purpose of the performance is to promote audio, video, or other devices utilized in such performance. (Sec. 203) Specifies that if a general music user and a performing rights society are unable to agree on the appropriate fee to be paid for the user's past or future performance of musical works in the society's repertoire, the user shall be entitled to binding arbitration of such disagreement pursuant to the rules of the American Arbitration Association in lieu of any other dispute-resolution mechanism established by any judgment or decree governing the operation of such society. Requires the arbitrator to determine a fair and reasonable fee for the user's past and future performance of works in such society's repertoire and to impose a penalty for infringement if the user's past performance infringed the copyright of such works. Makes an arbitrator's determination binding on both parties. Sets forth provisions regarding civil actions for infringement that may be submitted to arbitration if the license fee for a performance is contested. (Sec. 204) Sets forth conditions under which landlords, organizers of conventions, or others making space available to another party are exempt from liability under any theory of vicarious or contributory infringement with respect to an infringing public performance of a copyrighted work by a tenant, lessee, or other user of such space.</summary>
</bill>
