<bill session="106" type="h" number="4713" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Combined Fund Stability and Fairness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to restore stability and equity to the financing of the United Mine Workers of America Combined Benefit Fund by eliminating the liability of reachback operators, to provide additional sources of revenue to the Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400327"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2000-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="2000-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2000-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2000-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-21">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Reachback Provisions Title II: Financing Provisions Subtitle A: Premiums Subtitle B: Transfers From Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund Subtitle C: Authorization Combined Fund Stability and Fairness Act - Amends chapter 99 (Coal Industry Health Benefits) of the Internal Revenue Code and the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to redefine the term "coal wage agreement" to include only the 1988 agreement which became effective on February 1, 1988, and any predecessor to the 1988 agreement. Redefines the term "signatory operator" in a similar manner (as a 1988 operator).Provides for a reduction in health benefit premiums to coal miners if there is a surplus in the Combined Benefit Fund.Provides for a refund of premiums paid to the Fund for certain small entities which are not 1988 agreement operators.Provides for the transfer of certain amounts of interest from the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund to the Combined Fund.Reduces Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund fees. Extends the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fee program for an additional six years.Authorizes appropriations for the transfer of $38 million from the 1950 United Mine Workers of America Pension Plan annually to the Combined Fund to cover any shortfall in the premium account of the Combined Fund.</summary>
</bill>
