<bill session="105" type="h" number="2724" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Helping Empower Low-income Parents (HELP) Scholarships Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title VI of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to give parents with low-incomes the opportunity to choose the appropriate school for their children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409228"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400327" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1997-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disadvantaged children"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sparsely populated areas"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/1997--Introduced.
Helping Empower Low-income Parents (HELP) Scholarships Amendments of 1997 - Amends title VI (Innovative Education Program Strategies) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to allow any State that has enacted or will enact a law establishing a voluntary public and private school parental choice scholarship program in compliance with specified ESEA requirements to reserve an additional 15 percent from its annual title IV allotment for use exclusively for such parental choice programs. Requires State educational agencies, except in the case of such programs, to distribute 90 percent (currently 85 percent) of title VI funds to local educational agencies based on criteria which gives priority to low-income families and areas. Includes such parental choice programs among State and local uses of title VI funds. Requires such parental choice programs to be located in an area that has the greatest numbers or percentages of children: (1) living in areas with a high concentration of low-income families; (2) from low-income families; or (3) living in sparsely populated areas. Requires such programs to ensure that program participation is limited to families whose family income does not exceed 185 percent of the poverty line. Directs the Comptroller General to make contracts for annual evaluation of each parental choice program. Requires the Secretary of Education to reserve certain funds for such evaluations. Provides that title VI funds to establish a parental choice program shall be considered assistance to the student and shall not be considered as assistance to any school that chooses to participate in such program. Prohibits the Secretary from exercising any direction, supervision, or control over curricula, program of instruction, administration, or personnel of any school that chooses to participate in a parental choice program. Provides that, for purposes of Federal tax laws or for determining eligibility for any other Federal program, a parental choice scholarship shall not be treated as income or assistance to the student or parents.</summary>
</bill>
