<bill session="104" type="h" number="3904" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clinical Research Enhancement Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide additional support for and to expand clinical research programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1996-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1996-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientists in government"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/25/1996--Introduced.
Clinical Research Enhancement Act of 1996 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the President to establish the President's Clinical Research Panel, as part of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), to evaluate the status of the U.S. clinical research environment. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Advisory Committee to the Director (of the National Institutes of Health (NIH)) on Clinical Research to report to the Director and to the Panel and to implement recommendations as the Committee determines necessary to remedy NIH clinical research deficiencies. Terminates the Committee five years after enactment of this Act. Requires the OSTP to review the compositions, functions, and outcomes of study section activities at all Federal agencies as such activities relate to clinical research proposals for investigator-initiated support. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Director to: (1) support and expand NIH's clinical research involvement; (2) support and expand available resources; and (3) establish certain peer review mechanisms. Mandates grants for: (1) the establishment of general clinical research centers to provide the infrastructure for clinical research training and career enhancement; (2) clinical research career enhancement awards; and (3) innovative medical science awards to support individual clinical research projects. Authorizes appropriations. Increases the maximum aggregate number of contracts that may be made under existing provisions relating to: (1) undergraduate scholarships regarding professions needed by NIH; and (2) loan repayments regarding clinical researchers (currently, clinical researchers from disadvantaged backgrounds). Authorizes appropriations for the loan repayment program. Requires that at least 50 percent of such funds for a fiscal year be used for contracts with qualified health professionals from disadvantaged backgrounds.</summary>
</bill>
