<bill session="104" type="h" number="2330" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Agricultural Competitiveness Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Agricultural Act of 1949 to extend the agricultural price support programs for certain commodities through 2002 and to modify the operation of such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403864"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400037" joined="1995-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="1995-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300021" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="405258" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406625" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400261" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408476" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1995-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400432" joined="1995-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Acreage allotments"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural colleges"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural estimating and reporting"/>
    <term name="Agricultural experiment stations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural extension work"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural policies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural production"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Cropland conversion program"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farm lands"/>
    <term name="Farm production quotas"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Feed grain program"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Peanuts"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soybeans"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Extension of Certain Commodity Programs Title II: Modification of Commodity Program Operations Title III: General Commodity Provisions Title IV: Repeal of Emergency Livestock Feed Assistance Program Title V: Federal Crop Insurance Title VI: Miscellaneous Programs Title VII: Commission on 21st Century Production Agriculture Agricultural Competitiveness Act of 1995 - Title I: Extension of Certain Commodity Programs - Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 (Act) to extend loan, payment, and acreage reduction programs for wheat (including the food security wheat reserve), feed grains, cotton (including cottonseed and cottonseed oil), and rice. Extends loan and payment programs for oilseeds. Title II: Modification of Commodity Program Operations - Amends the Act to revise specified wheat, feed grains, upland cotton, and rice deficiency payment provisions (flex acres and 0-50 and 0-85 programs). (Sec. 203) Permits: (1) alternate crops to be planted on 100 percent (currently 25 percent) of crop acreage base without penalty; and (2) planting of crops on up to 25 percent of historical soybean acreage without loss of agricultural program eligibility. (Sec. 204) Establishes an alternative marketing loan repayment provision for wheat and feed grains. (Sec. 205) Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 to revise and extend peanut poundage quota and acreage allotment provisions. Repeals the special poundage allocation for Texas. Revises poundage quota provisions. Extends: (1) marketing penalty and disposition of additional peanut provisions; and (2) experimental and research programs. Amends the Act to revise and extend peanut price supports. Limits: (1) support rate decreases to not more than five percent; and (2) entry into New Mexico area marketing association pools to New Mexico-produced peanuts. Requires imported and exported peanuts to comply with U.S. quality standards. Extends assessment provisions. Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to extend specified peanut program provisions. (Sec. 206) Amends the Act to extend and set forth sugar price support provisions. Establishes the sugarcane target price at 18 cents per pound. Provides for recourse (rather than nonrecourse) loan assistance unless tariff rates exceed specified levels. Title III: General Commodity Provisions - Amends the Act to extend authority for: (1) supplemental set-asides and acreage limitations; (2) deficiency and land diversion payments; (3) established price and price support adjustments; (4) optional price support participation; and (5) acreage base and payment fields. (Sec. 308) Amends the Food and Agriculture Act of 1977 to extend normally planted acreage provisions. (Sec. 309) Amends the Food and Agriculture Act of 1981 to extend the National Agricultural Cost of Production Standards Review Board. (Sec. 310) Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend payment limitation provisions. (Sec. 313) Amends the Options Pilot Program Act of 1990 to extend the options pilot program. Title IV: Repeal of Emergency Livestock Feed Assistance Program - Amends the Emergency Livestock Feed Assistance Act of 1988 to repeal the emergency livestock feed assistance program. Title V: Federal Crop Insurance - Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to permit a producer to decline catastrophic risk protection and maintain agricultural program eligibility if such producer waives eligibility for emergency crop loss assistance. Title VI: Miscellaneous Programs - Amends the Trade Act of 1978 to extend the export enhancement program at reduced funding levels. (Sec. 602) Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend the conservation reserve program at reduced spending levels. Title VII: Commission on 21st Century Production Agriculture - Establishes the Commission on 21st Century Production Agriculture to assess the current and future condition of U.S. production agriculture, including the appropriate agricultural role of the Government. Terminates the Commission upon submission of a required report.</summary>
</bill>
