<bill session="107" type="h" number="1259" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-11-27T19:02:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-11-27T19:02:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Computer Security Enhancement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Computer Security Enhancement Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to enhance the ability of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to improve computer security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="2001-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="2001-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2001-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2001-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2001-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2001-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T14:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Morella moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T14:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8351-8356" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T14:45:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1259.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T15:06:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T18:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8391" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-11-27T19:02:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="449" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 391 - 4 (Roll no. 449).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8351-8353" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-11-27T19:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cryptography"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Encryption"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public meetings of administrative bodies"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/27/2001--Passed House amended.
Computer Security Enhancement Act of 2001 - Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to require the Institute to provide assistance to Federal agencies in the protection of computer networks, promote Federal compliance with computer information security and privacy guidelines, and assist Federal response efforts to unauthorized access to Federal systems.(Sec. 4) Requires the Institute to develop uniform standards for the cost-effective security and privacy of sensitive information in certain Federal systems, provide a list of certified commercial computer system security products, and report annually on Federal computer system evaluations.(Sec. 5) Directs the Institute to solicit Computer System Security and Privacy Advisory Board recommendations regarding standards. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2002 and 2003 to enable the Board to identify emerging computer security, privacy, and cryptography issues.(Sec. 6) Prohibits the Institute from adopting encryption and electronic authentication standards for other than Federal computer systems.(Sec. 7) Authorizes (current law requires) the Institute to draw upon National Security Agency computer security guidelines.(Sec. 8) Amends the Computer Security Act of 1987 to require Federal computer security training to emphasize protecting information accessible through public networks.(Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2002 and 2003 for fellowships to students in computer security.(Sec. 10) Requires a National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences to: (1) conduct a study of electronic authentication technologies; and (2) report to specified congressional committees on its findings, conclusions, and recommendations for public policy related to such technologies. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2002.(Sec. 11) Directs the Under Secretary of Commerce for Technology to promote an increased use of security technologies for the nation's information infrastructure, establish a central repository of information on security vulnerability and risks, and promote the development of national infrastructures for encryption technologies.(Sec. 12) Directs the Institute's Director to develop technology-neutral electronic authentication infrastructure standards for Federal agencies, provide a list of commercially available authentication products, establish core specifications for Federal electronic certification and management technologies, provide a list of conforming systems, and report annually on infrastructure implementation.(Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2002 and 2003.</summary>
</bill>
