<bill session="104" type="h" number="694" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-14T17:37:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-14T17:37:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Minor Boundary Adjustments and Miscellaneous Park Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Minor Boundary Adjustments and Miscellaneous Park Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Minor Boundary Adjustments and Miscellaneous Park Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="reported to senate" type="short">Minor Boundary Adjustments and Miscellaneous Park Amendments Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Entitled the "Minor Boundary Adjustments and Miscellaneous Park Amendments Act of 1995".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-02-28T15:36:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 104-59.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-02-28T15:36:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T14:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hansen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3101-3103, H3115-3116" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T14:53:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T14:56:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 5, rule I, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T17:25:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-03-14T17:37:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="231" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays (2/3 required): 337 - 83 (Roll No. 231).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-03-14T17:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Parks, Preservation and Recreation.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-03-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-04-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Murkowski under the authority of the order of Apr 6, 95 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 104-50.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-04-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="72">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 72.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Department of the Interior.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Parks, Historic Preservation, and Recreation" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Art objects"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National lakeshores"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Rights of women"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Special days"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/18/1995--Reported to Senate amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Minor Boundary Adjustments Title II: Miscellaneous Specific Park Amendments Title III: General Authorizations and Repealers Minor Boundary Adjustments and Miscellaneous Park Amendments Act of 1995 - Title I: Minor Boundary Adjustments - Makes boundary adjustments with respect to the: (1) Yucca House National Monument; (2) Zion National Park; (3) Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore; (4) Independence National Historical Park; (5) Craters of the Moon National Monument; (6) Hagerman Fossil Beds National Monument; and (7) Wupatki National Monument. Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978, the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987, and the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to modify boundaries of the: (1) New River Gorge National River; (2) Gauley River National Recreation Area; and (3) Bluestone National Scenic River. Title II: Miscellaneous Specific Park Amendments - Na Hoa Pili Kaloko-Honokohau Re-establishment Act of 1995 - Re-establishes the Na Hoa Pili O Kaloko-Honokohau (the Advisory Commission for Kaloko-Honokohau National Historical Park). Women's Rights National Historical Park Advisory Commission Re-establishment Act of 1995 - Re-establishes the advisory commission for Women's Rights National Historical Park in New York. Amends the Boston National Historical Park Act of 1974 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Boston Public Library for the distribution of informational and interpretive materials relating to the Park and the Freedom Trail. Removes restrictions prohibiting the Secretary from using appropriated funds to purchase lands within the Cumberland Gap National Historical Park in Tennessee, Kentucky, and Virginia. Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to enter into cooperative agreements relating to Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area: (1) with appropriate organizations or groups to promote education concerning the natural and cultural resources of the Area and adjacent lands; and (2) in which the Secretary agrees to maintain the facilities at 2600 Franklin Canyon Drive, Beverly Hills, California, for eight fiscal years and to provide funding for programs of the William O. Douglas Outdoor Classroom (in return for which the Classroom agrees that at the end of the term of such agreement, all right, title, and interest in and to such facilities will be donated to the United States for addition to the Area). Authorizes appropriations. Makes provisions of the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987 relating to cooperative agreements and remnant lands in the Gauley River National Recreation Area applicable to the New River Gorge National River. Sets forth provisions relating to access of the Gauley River National Recreation Area by certain noncommercial recreational users. Authorizes the Secretary to construct a visitor center in the vicinity of the confluence of the New and Gauley Rivers. Extends certain provisions of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act with respect to segments of the Bluestone and Meadow Rivers that were found eligible for addition to the wild and scenic rivers system in studies completed by the Park Service in 1983 but that were not designated as part of the Bluestone National Scenic River or the Gauley River National Recreation Area. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to set forth provisions relating to public access to the Bluestone River. Title III: General Authorizations and Repealers- Repeals a limitation on the expenditure of funds for park buildings. Authorizes appropriations for the Park Service to provide transportation for children in nearby communities to and from any unit of the National Park System used in connection with the Service's organized recreation and interpretive programs. Amends the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act to permit the Secretary to use motor vehicles, fixed-wing aircraft, and helicopters in furtherance of the management of the National Park System. Authorizes the Secretary to perform specified functions with respect to the transfer of museum objects and collections determined to be no longer needed for museum purposes. Amends the Volunteers in the Parks Act of 1969 to increase the authorization of appropriations for the Volunteers in the Parks Program. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with public or private educational institutions, States and their political subdivisions, or private conservation organizations to develop cooperative research and training programs concerning the resources of the National Park System. Amends the Federal Lands Cleanup Act of 1985 to rename Federal Lands Cleanup Day or Federal Lands National Cleanup Day as Carl Garner Federal Lands Cleanup Day. Corinth, Mississippi, Battlefield Act of 1995 - Directs the Secretary to acquire lands in the vicinity of the Corinth Battlefield in Mississippi for the construction of an interpretive center to commemorate and interpret the 1862 Civil War Siege and Battle of Corinth and to be administered as part of the Shiloh National Military Park. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
