<bill session="104" type="h" number="1282" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Neighborhood Infrastructure Improvement and Inner City Job Creation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide employment opportunities to unemployed individuals in high unemployment areas in programs to repair and renovate essential community facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400422"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities. for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-04-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education, Training and Life-Long Learning" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Community facilities"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Unskilled labor"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1995--Introduced.
Neighborhood Infrastructure Improvement and Inner City Job Creation Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to make grants to eligible administrative entities for programs to provide employment opportunities to unemployed individuals through payments for labor and related costs associated with repair and renovation of essential community facilities. Makes an area eligible for such a program if it has a poverty rate above 30 percent and is: (1) a local government with a population of 50,000 or more; or (2) a Native American Indian tribe, band or group located on a Federal or State reservation, the Oklahoma Indians, and any Alaska Native village or group, having a governing body. Gives grant priority to administrative entities that assure giving priority to low-skilled workers as program participants. Requires eligible participants to have been unemployed for at least 15 weeks and have sought employment during that period. Makes secondary school-age individuals (16 to 20 years old) eligible only if they have not attended a secondary school at any time during the previous six months. Gives priority to individuals who have exhausted or are not eligible for unemployment insurance benefits, particularly those who have been unemployed for the longest periods. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
