<bill session="106" type="hc" number="397" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-01T12:41:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-11-01T12:41:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Voicing concern about serious violations of human rights and fundamental freedoms in most states of Central Asia, including substantial noncompliance with their Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) commitments on democratization and the holding of free and fair elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2000-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="2000-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-30T14:48:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bereuter moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-30T14:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11576-11580" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-30T14:49:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-30T15:15:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until Oct. 31.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01T12:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11729" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-11-01T12:41:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="589" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 362 - 3, 1 Present (Roll no. 589).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/30/2000 H11576-11577" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01T12:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Kazakhstan"/>
    <term name="Kyrgyzstan"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Tajikistan"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Turkmenistan"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/1/2000--Passed House amended.
Expresses concern about the tendency of Central Asian leaders to seek to remain in power indefinitely and their willingness to manipulate constitutions, elections, and legislative and judicial systems to do so.Urges the President, the Secretaries of State and Defense, and other U.S. officials to raise with such leaders the concern about serious violations of human rights, including noncompliance with Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) commitments on democracy and the rule of law.Urges Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, and Uzbekistan to: (1) come into compliance with OSCE commitments on human rights, democracy, and the rule of law, specifically the holding of free and fair elections that do not exclude genuine challengers; (2) permit independent and opposition parties and candidates to participate on an equal basis with representation in election commissions at all levels; and (3) allow domestic non-governmental and political party observers, as well as international observers.Calls on Central Asian leaders to: (1) establish conditions for independent and opposition media to function without constraint, limitation, or fear of harassment; (2) repeal criminal laws which impose prison sentences for alleged defamation of the state or public officials; and (3) provide access to state media on an equal basis during election campaigns to independent and opposition parties and candidates.Calls on Central Asian governments that have begun roundtable discussions with opposition and independent forces to engage in a serious and comprehensive national dialogue on institutionalizing measures to hold free and fair elections and urges those governments which have not launched such roundtables to do so.Calls on the leaders of Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan to: (1) condemn and take steps to cease the systematic use of torture and other inhuman treatment by authorities against political opponents and others; (2) permit the registration of independent and opposition parties and candidates; and (3) register independent human rights monitoring organizations.Urges the governments of Central Asia which are engaged in military campaigns against violent insurgents to: (1) observe international law regulating such actions; (2) keep civilians and other noncombatants from harm; and (3) not use such campaigns to justify further crackdowns on political opposition or violations of human rights commitments under the OSCE.Encourages the Administration to raise with the governments of other OSCE participating states the possible implications for OSCE participation of any participating state in the region that engages in clear, gross, and uncorrected violations of its OSCE commitments on human rights, democracy, and the rule of law.Urges the Voice of America and Radio Liberty to expand broadcasting to Central Asia, as needed, with a focus on assuring that the peoples of the region have access to unbiased news and programs that support respect for human rights and the establishment of democracy and the rule of law.</summary>
</bill>
