<bill session="104" type="h" number="1159" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-08T11:26:00-05:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-08T11:26:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making supplemental appropriations and rescissions for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1995, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406863"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-08T11:26:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-71, by Mr. Livingston.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-03-08T11:26:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="37">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 37.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="115"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1158"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="617"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms Control and Disarmament Agency"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Automobile repair"/>
    <term name="Botanical gardens"/>
    <term name="CIS countries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International Development Cooperation Agency"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Railroads and state"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Replacement workers"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Russian Republic"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="United States Information Agency"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/8/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Supplemental Appropriations Title II: Rescissions Title III: General Provisions Title I: Supplemental Appropriations - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY 1995 available to the Department of Agriculture for the Food Safety and Inspection Service, the Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, and the Commodity Credit Corporation Fund (through a fund transfer). Makes supplemental appropriations available to the United States Information Agency for international broadcasting operations. Makes additional funds available to the President for debt relief for Jordan. Makes an appropriation to the family trust of Dean A. Gallo, late a Representative from New Jersey. Makes additional funds available through a transfer of funds for: (1) the Botanic Garden; (2) the Federal Railroad Administration of the Department of Transportation; (3) the Department of the Treasury for department offices, the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, the Internal Revenue Service, and the United States Mint; and (4) the General Services Administration. Makes additional funds available to the Office of Personnel Management for employee life insurance benefits. Title II: Rescissions - Rescinds appropriations made to: (1) the Department of Agriculture for Public Law 480 Programs Accounts; (2) the Department of Commerce for the National Institute of Standards and Technology; (3) the Department of State for the administration of foreign affairs and international organizations and conferences; (4) the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency; and (5) the United States Information Agency. Rescinds funds made available to the President for the Agency for International Development and to the Congressional Budget Office for salaries and expenses. Title III: General Provisions - Prohibits the use of funds to issue, implement, administer, or enforce any executive order, or other rule or order, that prohibits Federal contracts with companies that hire permanent replacements for striking employees. (Sec. 302) Makes inapplicable in FY 1995 the requirement to replace each public housing dwelling unit that is disposed of or demolished. (Sec. 303) Prohibits the Environmental Protection Agency from imposing or enforcing any requirement that a State implement trip reduction measures to reduce vehicular emissions. (Sec. 304) Prohibits the Environmental Protection Agency from imposing or enforcing any requirement that a State implement an inspection and maintenance program for vehicular emissions. (Sec. 305) Rescinds any Federal implementation plan under the Clean Air Act for the South Coast, Ventura, or Sacramento areas of California. (Sec. 306) Prohibits the funding of an abortion except when necessary to save the life of the mother or when the pregnancy is the result of rape or incest. Declares that each State is and remains free to fund abortions to the extent that the State deems appropriate, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term. (Sec. 307) Establishes an emergency two-year salvage timber sale program beginning on the date of enactment of this section. Establishes expedited procedures for the Secretary concerned to prepare, advertise, offer, and award contracts during the emergency period for salvage timber sales from Federal lands to satisfy salvage timber sale volume requirements. Requires the Secretary concerned to plan and implement reforestation of each parcel of land harvested under a salvage timber sale as expeditiously as possible. Subjects such sales to judicial review only in the United States district court for the district in which the affected Federal lands are located. Excludes the following Federal lands from such sale: (1) any area included in the National Wilderness Preservation System; (2) any roadless area designated by Congress for wilderness study in Colorado or Montana; (3) any roadless area recommended by the Forest Service or Bureau of Land Management for wilderness designation in its most recent land management plan; and (4) any area on which timber harvesting for any purpose is prohibited by statute. Releases certain timber sale contracts that have been previously awarded.</summary>
</bill>
