<bill session="105" type="h" number="2824" updated="2012-11-01T22:48:44-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Balanced Budget Incentive Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide that annual pay adjustments for Members of Congress shall not be made in the year immediately following any fiscal year in which a budget deficit exists, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400593" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400398" joined="1997-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="1997-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on House Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-05">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-05">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>11/05/1997--Introduced.
Balanced Budget Incentive Act - Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to prohibit rates of pay for Members of Congress from being increased, as a result of a cost-of-living adjustment, by a percentage greater than the maximum percentage allowable for a year. Provides that the maximum percentage allowable for a year is the percentage by which benefits under title II (Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act are increased (if at all) effective December 1 of the preceding year pursuant to a cost-of-living or general benefit increase. Bars annual pay increases for Members of Congress for a calendar year if the Director of the Congressional Budget Office determines that there was a deficit in the U.S. Government budget for the last fiscal year ending before the start of such calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
