<bill session="107" type="h" number="1858" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-07-30T15:25:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-07-30T15:25:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Mathematics and Science Partnerships Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Mathematics and Science Partnerships Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Mathematics and Science Partnerships Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make improvements in mathematics and science education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400009" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400526" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400027" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400125" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400535" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400195" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400204" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400207" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400255" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="2001-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400412" joined="2001-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-06-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Science"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-07-11T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science. H. Rept. 107-134, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-11T19:29:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Education and the Workforce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 11, 2001.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-11T19:30:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Education and the Workforce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-07-11T19:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="76">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 76.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-07-30T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehlert moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-30T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4792-4802" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-30T14:50:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1858.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-07-30T15:25:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4792-4798" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-07-30T15:25:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY14" subcommittee="Research" name="House Science"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="100"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="1472"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="h" number="1693"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="1693"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="4664"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="107" type="s" number="1262"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and college"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Computer literacy"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computer-assisted instruction"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Elementary schools"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="High school students"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Kindergarten"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Learning"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority teachers"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Publishers and publishing"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School administrators"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/2001--Passed House amended.
National Mathematics and Science Partnerships Act - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish various programs relating to elementary and secondary school mathematics and science teaching and education.(Sec. 4) Requires the NSF Director to remedy any duplication of programs authorized under this Act by current or subsequent NSF education programs. Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to review, and report to specified congressional committees on, NSF education programs to ensure compliance.(Sec. 5) Authorizes the Director to establish matching fund requirements for any of the programs under this Act, except the Robert Noyce Scholarship program under title IV.(Sec. 6) Requires the NSF Director, in carrying out activities authorized by this Act, to coordinate with the Secretary of Education to ensure close cooperation with programs authorized under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.Title I: Mathematics and Science Education Partnerships - Subtitle A: Mathematics and Science Education Partnerships - Requires the Director to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit institutions for Mathematics and Science Education Partnerships with local educational agencies, which may also include State educational agencies and businesses. Sets forth authorized program activities. Requires certain enrichment program activities for girls. Allows support for secondary student research projects, and for stipends for certain teacher or student research activities.Subtitle B: Teacher Research Scholarship Program - Requires the Director to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit institutions for Teacher Research Scholarships in mathematics, science, and engineering for elementary or secondary mathematics or science teachers.Title II: National Science, Mathematics, Engineering, and Technology Education Digital Library - Requires the Director to establish a program to expand the National Science, Mathematics, Engineering, and Technology Education Digital Library program to enable timely and continuous dissemination of elementary and secondary science, math, engineering, and technology educational resources, materials, practices, and policies through the Internet and other digital technologies.(Sec. 203) Declares that nothing in this Act shall affect rights, remedies, limitations, or defenses under Federal law relating to copyrights.Title III: Strategic Education Research Program - Subtitle A: Centers - Requires the Director to: (1) award competitive grants to institutions of higher education for establishment of four multidisciplinary Centers for Research on Learning and Education Improvement; and (2) convene an annual meeting of the Centers.Subtitle B: Fellowships - Requires the Director to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit institutions for programs of education research teacher fellowships to provide research opportunities related to the science of learning to elementary and secondary school science and mathematics teachers. Requires grantee institutions to recruit and select teachers and provide them with: (1) opportunities to conduct research in specified fields; (2) mentors and programming support; (3) support for their disseminating of information to other teachers on education research and its implications for classroom practice, and for their using that information in their own classroom practice; and (4) a scholarship stipend. Allows grantees to provide room and board for participating teachers.Title IV: Robert Noyce Scholarship Program - Requires the Director to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education to provide scholarships, stipends, and programming designed to recruit and train mathematics and science teachers. Designates such grants program as the Robert Noyce Scholarship Program, and such grantee institutions as National Teacher Scholarship Centers. Provides for scholarships for certain students and stipends for certain professionals seeking teaching certification. Requires certain teaching service commitments from individuals who receive such scholarships or stipends. Directs grantee institutions to supply to the Director statistical and demographic data on scholarship recipients and stipend recipients, including information on required teaching employment. Requires the Director to report to Congress on the impact of the implementation of this title on drawing into teaching top mathematics and science students, including students from groups underrepresented in mathematics, science and engineering.Title V: Requirements for Research Centers - Requires the Director to ensure that any NSF program that awards grants for the establishment of research centers at institutions of higher education after the date of the enactment of this Act: (1) requires every center to offer programs for elementary and secondary mathematics and science teachers and students to increase their understanding of the field in which the center specializes; and (2) uses the quality of a center's proposed precollege education programs as a criterion in determining grant awards.Title VI: Educational Technologies Research - Subtitle A: Research Centers - Requires the Director to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education to establish centers to evaluate and improve the effectiveness of information technologies in elementary and secondary mathematics and science education.Subtitle B: Assistance - Amends the Scientific and Advanced Technology Act of 1992 to authorize the Director to award competitive grants to associate-degree granting colleges, bachelor-degree granting institutions, or education service agencies to establish centers to assist elementary and secondary schools in the use of information technology for mathematics, science, or technology instruction.Title VII: Miscellaneous Provisions - Requires the Director to award demonstration grants to eligible local educational agencies (LEAs) for mathematics and science proficiency partnerships.(Sec. 701) Allows grant funds to be used to: (1) provide teacher professional development in mathematics, science, or technology; (2) develop or implement mathematics, science, and information technology curricula, and purchase related equipment; and (3) carry out other activities the NSF Director determines would improve mathematics, science, or technology education. Requires LEA conditional agreements for private sector participation in such programs through: (1) donation of equipment; (2) establishment of mentoring and internship opportunities; and (3) donation of college scholarship funds for students who have participated. Requires special priority in awarding such grants to be given to eligible LEAs that demonstrate the greatest: (1) ability to obtain commitments from private sector representatives to provide such services and funds; and (2) economic need. Requires assessment, evaluation, and a report to Congress on such demonstration grants project.(Sec. 702) Requires the Director, in making awards for outreach grants (for articulation partnerships between community colleges and secondary schools) under the Scientific and Advanced-Technology Act of 1992, to give priority to proposals that involve secondary schools with a majority of students from groups that are underrepresented in the science, mathematics, and engineering workforce. Exempts awards in such cases from a matching contribution requirement.(Sec. 703) Requires the Director to review, and report to Congress on, all NSF-sponsored programs that support in-service teacher professional development for science teachers to determine: (1) the level of resources and degree of emphasis placed on training teachers in the effective use of information technology in the classroom; and (2) the allocation of resources between summer activities and follow-on reinforcement training and support to participating teachers during the school year.(Sec. 704) Requires the Director to study and report to Congress on broadband Internet access for schools and libraries.</summary>
</bill>
