<bill session="104" type="h" number="3903" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1996-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Sly Park Unit Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Sly Park Unit Conveyance Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Interior to sell the Sly Park Dam and Reservoir, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-08-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1996-08-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1996-09-04T17:17:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 104-768.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1996-09-04T17:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="413">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 413.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/4/1996--Reported to House amended.
Sly Park Unit Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, upon receipt of the payment for the original construction debt and before January 1, 1998, to: (1) sell and convey to the El Dorado Irrigation District (California) all Federal interest in the Sly Park Unit (Sly Park Dam and Reservoir, Camp Creek Diversion Dam and Tunnel, conduits and canals, and related facilities); and (2) transfer and assign to such District water rights relating to the Unit. Requires: (1) the terms of the transfer to include a commitment by the District to continue to use and operate the facility for the existing purposes following the transfer; and (2) the District to comply with all applicable laws or regulations governing changes in operations or uses. Declares that such sale and water rights conveyance are consistent with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and the Endangered Species Act of 1973 without additional environmental review and, consequently, no new environmental documentation is required. Requires the District to continue to make payments into the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund for 35 years after enactment of this Act. Exempts the District from the Reclamation Act of 1902 upon conveyance of the Unit.</summary>
</bill>
