<bill session="105" type="h" number="812" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patent Sovereignty Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 35, United States Code, to enable the Patent and Trademark Office to improve the integrity of the United States patent system and to further ensure the validity of United States patents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400017" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1997-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400582" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1997-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400343" joined="1997-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1997-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1997-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H790"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1997--Introduced.
Patent Sovereignty Act of 1997 - Amends Federal patent law to declare all examination and search duties for the grant of U.S. letters patent to be sovereign functions which shall be performed within the United States by U.S. citizens who are Government employees. Requires (current law authorizes) the Commissioner of Patents and Trademarks to revise and maintain the classification by subject matter of all U.S. letters patent. Requires such patents, and all such other patents and printed publications, to be maintained in the examiners' search files under the U.S. Patent Classification System. Requires all patent examiners to spend at least five percent of their annual duty time in training to maintain and develop legal and technical skills useful for patent examination. Directs the Patent and Trademark Office (Office) to develop an incentive program to retain patent examiners of primary examiner grade or higher to train other patent examiners who have not achieved such grade. Prohibits the Office from being subject to any administratively or statutorily imposed limitations on positions or personnel. Allows patent fees to be retained by the Office to carry out its activities, including the training of patent examiners, in such allocations as approved by the Congress. Requires the Office to make public all Office solicitations for goods and services, as well as all such contracts entered into by the Office. Requires publication in the Federal Register of notice of a proposal to change U.S. patent law that will be made on behalf of the United States to a foreign country or international body.</summary>
</bill>
