<bill session="108" type="h" number="1014" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Gateway Communities Cooperation Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require Federal land managers to support, and to communicate, coordinate, and cooperate with, designated gateway communities, to improve the ability of gateway communities to participate in Federal land management planning conducted by the Forest Service and agencies of the Department of the Interior, and to respond to the impacts of the public use of the Federal lands administered by these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400029" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2003-02-27" withdrawn="2003-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20T17:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-508, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than May 20, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-20T17:23:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="291">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 291.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hayworth moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5931-5932" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1014.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5931" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/19/2004--Passed House amended.
Gateway Communities Cooperation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture (the relevant Secretary) to: (1) solicit involvement by government officials of local gateway communities (communities, including recognized Indian tribes or Alaska Native villages, that abut or are near public lands) in the development of land use plans, programs, regulations, and decisions, transportation plans, general management plans, and any other public land plans, decisions, projects, or policies for public lands under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, the United States Forest Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Bureau of Land Management which are likely to have a significant impact; (2) facilitate such involvement, provide the appropriate officials with a summary of the assumptions, purposes, goals, and objectives of a plan, decision, project, or policy, a description of any anticipated significant impact, and information regarding the technical assistance and training available; (3) at the request of a gateway community, offer training sessions for officials for understanding and participating in agency planning processes and the methods by which they can most meaningfully participate in the development of agency plans, decisions, and policies; and (4) at the request of a gateway community, make available personnel, on a temporary basis, to assist gateway communities in the development of mutually compatible land use or management plans. Authorizes the relevant Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with gateway communities to coordinate the management of: (1) the land use inventory, planning, and management activities administered by such Secretary; and (2) the land use planning and management activities of other Federal agencies, agencies of the State in which the public lands are located, and local and tribal governments in the vicinity of such lands. Requires, when the plans of two or more Federal agencies are anticipated to have an impact on a gateway community, the consolidation and coordination of the agencies' plans and planning processes in order to facilitate the participation of affected gateway communities. Directs the relevant Secretary to allow any affected gateway communities the opportunity to be recognized as cooperating agencies under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 when a proposed action is determined to require an environmental impact statement. Allows the relevant Secretary to make grants to any gateway community with a population of 10,000 or less to carry out the purposes of this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
