<bill session="107" type="h" number="2136" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Confidential Information Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To protect the confidentiality of information acquired from the public for statistical purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400539"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400513" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400509" joined="2001-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2001-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2001-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Efficiency, Financial Management and Intergovernmental Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO16" subcommittee="Government Efficiency, Financial Management and Intergovernmental Relations" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/12/2001--Introduced.
Confidential Information Protection Act - Requires data or information acquired by executive agencies for exclusively statistical purposes to be used only for such purposes.Prohibits data or information acquired by an agency for such purposes from being disclosed in identifiable form, for any purpose other than such a purpose, without the informed consent of the respondent.Requires a statistical agency to clearly distinguish any data or information it collects for nonstatistical purposes by a rule that provides that the respondent is fully informed that the information to be collected will be used for such purposes.Requires: (1) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to coordinate and oversee such confidentiality and disclosure policies; and (2) any rules proposed by an agency pursuant to this Act to be subject to the Director's review and approval.Exempts data or information acquired for exclusively statistical purposes from mandatory disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act. Provides that this Act does not preempt applicable State law regarding the confidentiality of data collected by the States.Sets forth penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
