<bill session="106" type="h" number="1751" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Carrizo Plain National Conservation Area Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Carrizo Plain National Conservation Area Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish the Carrizo Plain National Conservation Area in the State of California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1999-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1999-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1999-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="1999-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1999-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1999-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Referred to Department of the Interior for comment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-07-26">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-07T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-831.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-07T18:38:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="489">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 489.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity conservation"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/2000--Reported to House amended.
Carrizo Plain National Conservation Area Act of 2000 - Designates the Carrizo Plain National Conservation Area in California, which the Secretary of the Interior shall manage, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management. Provides Area use restrictions for vehicles, hunting and fishing, and grazing. Authorizes the Secretary to establish appropriate interpretive sites.Requires the Secretary, in cooperation with the Director, the California Department of Fish and Game, affected landowners, and The Nature Conservancy, to review and make any necessary revisions to the existing management plan.Establishes in the Treasury a separate Carrizo Plain National Conservation Area Management Fund. Directs the Secretary to establish a Carrizo Plain National Conservation Area Advisory Council for advice and recommendations with respect to management plan preparation and implementation.Authorizes the Secretary to acquire nongovernment, privately owned lands and interests within the conservation area by donation, exchange, or purchase with the owner's consent.Withdraws all Federal lands within the conservation area, including all subsequently acquired lands or interests, from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws and from location, entry, and patent under Federal mining laws. Allows mineral development in the conservation area only to the extent consistent with the management plan.Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements or shared management arrangements with any person for management, interpretation, and research of the conservation area's resources.Directs the Secretary to ensure nonexclusive access to and use of the public lands in the conservation area by Native Americans for traditional cultural and religious purposes consistent with the American Indian Religious Freedom Act. Permits the Secretary from time to time temporarily to specific areas in such lands close to general public use in order to protect the privacy of Native American religious activities.</summary>
</bill>
