<bill session="104" type="hr" number="103" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-03-03T14:52:00-05:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-03-03T14:52:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1058) to reform Federal securities litigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400115"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T14:52:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-65, by Mr. Dreier.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-03T14:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1058 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the reort of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, if offered in the manner specified. All points of order against the amendment for failure to comply with clause 7 of rule XVI shall be waived. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the 5-minute rule, not to exceed 8 hours. The Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the amendment to be offered was printed in the Congressional Record.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-03-03T14:52:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="25">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 25.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-07T16:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 105, H. Res. 103 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="105"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="hr" number="105"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="1058"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the modified open rule for the consideration of H.R. 1058 (Federal securities litigation reform).</summary>
</bill>
