<bill session="106" type="h" number="1269" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Oil and Gas Reform Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 to strengthen sanctions for violations of that Act relating to oil or gas royalties.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="1999-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="1999-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1999-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400178" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1999-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="1999-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E543"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-04-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1999--Introduced.
Federal Oil and Gas Reform Act of 1999 - Amends provisions of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 concerning civil penalties for violation of Federal oil or gas lease (lease) requirements to include under such violations: (1) the filing of false information relating to royalty payments; (2) lease administration violations (recordkeeping, required notifications, inspections); and (3) theft of oil or gas. Makes a repeat offender under any of such violations liable for three times the amount of the otherwise applicable civil penalty and subject to certain other discretionary penalties, such as ceasing oil or gas production or not being permitted to acquire any other lease. Requires administrative appeal of a violation decision within 15 days. Revises penalty amounts for other violations. Provides that any determination that a person has violated lease requirements shall toll any applicable statute of limitations for leases held or operated by such person. Treats amounts received from underpayments of lease royalties owed to the United States as royalties paid to the United States for purposes of the Federal mineral and leasing laws and the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965. Includes trebled royalty amounts collected for certain lease violations under a provision requiring 50 percent of amounts collected resulting from activities by a State or Indian tribe pursuant to a cooperative agreement to be payable to such State or tribe.</summary>
</bill>
