<bill session="108" type="h" number="5171" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to ensure the same requirements that apply to voters who register by mail also apply to voters who do not register in person with an officer or employee of a State or local government entity, and to provide for increased penalties for fraudulent registration in cases involving 10 or more violations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Election fraud"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2004--Introduced.
Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require a State to apply the same self-identification requirements currently applicable to voters who register by mail to those voters who do not register in person with an officer or employee of a State or local government entity. Amends the Voting Rights Act of 1965 and the National Voter Registration Act to provide for increased penalties relating to fraudulent voter registration in cases involving ten or more violations.</summary>
</bill>
