<bill session="106" type="h" number="5294" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Universal Service Sufficiency Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Federal Communications Commission to completely and accurately fulfill the support requirements for universal service for high cost areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400099"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/2000--Introduced.
Universal Service Sufficiency Act of 2000 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to remove, on the date of enactment of this Act, the interim cap on total nationwide loop cost expense adjustments (interim cap) contained in Federal Communications Commission (FCC) regulations. Prohibits the FCC from enforcing or reimposing such cap after such date.Prohibits the FCC from: (1) enforcing individual caps imposed on carriers by orders of the FCC entered in connection with prior requests for study area waivers; or (2) imposing any new cap that would limit the per loop support calculated under current FCC regulations.Requires the FCC to calculate: (1) that portion of the high cost support mechanism attributable to loops having costs in excess of 115 percent of the nationwide average; and (2) the nationwide average unseparated loop cost, taking into account the elimination of the interim cap pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
