<bill session="113" type="h" number="1911" updated="2013-07-17T16:02:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2013-05-23T12:41:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2013-05-23T12:41:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Smarter Solutions for Students Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Smarter Solutions for Students Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Improving Postsecondary Education Data for Students Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Smarter Solutions for Students Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish interest rates for new loans made on or after July 1, 2013.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish interest rates for new loans made on or after July 1, 2013, to direct the Secretary of Education to convene the Advisory Committee on Improving Postsecondary Education Data to conduct a study on improvements to postsecondary education transparency at the Federal level, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400224"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400643" joined="2013-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="412401" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412540" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412310" joined="2013-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="412317" joined="2013-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-09">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2013-05-16">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 13.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T14:42:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 113-82, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-20T14:43:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Budget discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-05-20T14:43:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="57">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2013-05-22T19:12:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 232 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1911 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 232 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 232.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2926-2940" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2927" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1911 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T11:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1911.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T11:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2937" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T11:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Sinema moved to recommit with instructions to Education and the Workforce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2937-2939" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2937" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T11:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sinema motion to recommit with instructions pending a reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment adding a new section pertaining to protecting students from teaser interest rates that lead to higher long-term costs. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T12:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2938" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T12:32:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 194 - 223 (Roll no. 182).</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2013-05-23T12:41:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="183" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 221 - 198 (Roll no. 183).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2013-05-23T12:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-06-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="113" type="hr" number="232"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h76"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/23/2013--Passed House amended.
Title I: Smarter Solutions for Students Act - Smarter Solutions for Students Act - (Sec. 102) Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to set the annual interest rate on Direct Stafford loans and Direct Unsubsidized Stafford loans at the rate on high-yield 10-year Treasury notes plus 2.5%, but caps that rate at 8.5%. Sets the annual interest rate on Direct PLUS loans at the rate on high-yield 10-year Treasury notes plus 4.5%, but caps that rate at 10.5%. Limits the applicability of the preceding provisions to loans first disbursed on or after July 1, 2013. Sets the annual interest rate on Direct Consolidation loans for which an application is received on or after July 1, 2013, at the weighted average of the interest rates on the loans consolidated, rounded to the nearest higher one-eighth of 1%. (Sec. 103) Provides that the budgetary effects of this Act shall not be entered on specified PAYGO scorecards. Title II: Improving Postsecondary Education Data for Students Act - Improving Postsecondary Education Data for Students Act - (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary of Education to convene an Advisory Committee on Improving Postsecondary Education Data that: (1) is comprised of 15 members who represent economically, racially, and geographically diverse populations; and (2) includes higher education stakeholders, state officials, business representatives, college and career counselors at secondary schools, and experts in higher education policy, consumer choice, privacy, labor markets, and data policy, collection, and use. Requires the Committee to study: the types of information the federal government should collect and report on institutions of higher education (IHEs) to assist students and families in their search for an IHE, including information related to postsecondary education costs, financial assistance, student outcomes, and postgraduation earnings; how that information should be collected and reported, including how to disaggregate student outcome information by student subgroups; and ways in which the federal government could make that information more readily available to students and their families in an easily accessible and understandable format and to states, local governments, secondary schools, IHEs, and private-sector entities. Requires the Committee, in conducting the study, to: (1) review relevant research concerning the types of information students and parents seek in searching for an IHE; (2) consider the utility of the information currently reported and whether additional information would be beneficial or confusing; and (3) consult with parents, students, and a broad range of parties interested in higher education. Directs the Committee to submit an interim and final report on the study to Congress and the Secretary. Requires the Committee, after consulting with the Commissioner of Education Statistics, to include in its final report recommendations for legislative, regulatory, and administrative actions to improve the information the federal government collects and reports on IHEs.</summary>
</bill>
