<bill session="106" type="h" number="574" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Science Integrity Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require peer review of scientific data used in support of Federal regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400322"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="1999-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400113" joined="1999-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400598" joined="1999-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400288" joined="1999-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1999-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="1999-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1999-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1999-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO01" subcommittee="National Economic Growth, Natural Resources and Regulatory Affairs" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1999--Introduced.
Science Integrity Act - Requires each Federal agency that issues regulations supported by scientific data: (1) to establish procedures to ensure that the acquisition, interpretation, incorporation, and application of such data is subject to peer review by at least two but not more than five individuals from a list of peer reviewers; (2) to create, using the Federal Register, scientific and commercial journals, the National Academy of Sciences, and other similar resources, a list of individuals who are qualified and willing to perform peer review functions for the agency;(3) to select individuals from the list to peer review each proposed regulation of the agency that is supported by scientific data; and (4) upon receipt of all peer review reports for a proposed regulation, to publish in the Federal Register a notice of availability of those reports, and the scientific data reviewed therein, for public comment. Requires the head of an agency, within 30 days after the completion of the public comment period, to transmit to the Congress: (1) each peer review report; (2) all scientific data used in support of the proposed regulation or requested by a peer reviewer; (3) the response of the head of the agency to points of disagreement among the peer reviewers; and (4) all public comments received. Prohibits the proposed regulation from being issued in final form until 30 days after transmittal. Requires publication of a final peer reviewed regulation to include a summary of such reports, points of disagreement, and responses. Requires regulations issued establishing peer review procedures to include emergency exception provisions.</summary>
</bill>
