<bill session="105" type="h" number="1670" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Airline Passenger Safety Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require air carriers to establish procedures for responding to in-flight medical emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406284"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1997-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1997-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1997-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="1998-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1997-05-22" withdrawn="1998-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E959"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-02">
      <text>Hearings Held by Subcommittee on Aviation Prior to Referral (May 21, 97).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-30">
      <text>See H.R.2843.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="h" number="2843"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication satellites"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Coroners"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1997--Introduced.
Airline Passenger Safety Act of 1997 - Amends Federal aviation law to require each air carrier to establish procedures, including specified steps, to be followed in the event of an in-flight medical emergency. Requires each air carrier to provide, upon request, a copy of such procedures to each air passenger. (Sec. 2) Requires: (1) each aircraft to be equipped with certain life-saving equipment, including first-aid and medical kits; (2) each member of the flight crew to have access to such items; (3) each air carrier, with respect to cardiac emergencies, to train flight crew members in cardiopulmonary resuscitation and operation of an automated external defibrillator; (4) each air carrier to establish an in-flight emergency procedures manual, including cardiac medical emergency response procedures; (5) each aircraft to be equipped with such manual; (6) each air carrier to take certain actions in providing emergency medical care; (7) each air carrier to enter into a contract with a clinic, hospital, or other medical care provider to provide it with medical advice (including the solicitation of assistance of medically-qualified passengers) in the case of in-flight medical emergencies; and (8) the flight crew to check on any passenger who is inside an aircraft lavatory for more than ten minutes. Directs the Secretary to establish certain procedures to ensure that appropriate medical personnel, including a coroner in the event of a passenger's death, are present to meet an aircraft upon the notification of an air traffic controller of an in-flight medical emergency. Directs the Secretary to establish procedures for in-flight medical emergencies requiring an emergency landing, including: (1) establishing a medical facility to be contacted after an in-flight medical emergency; and (2) designating an airport ground crew that will meet the plane, including medical personnel assigned to the airport. Prohibits an air carrier from purchasing or leasing an aircraft that is not equipped with an emergency call button in each aircraft lavatory. Requires specified reports on in-flight medical emergencies. Directs an air carrier to notify the family of a passenger as soon as practicable after an in-flight medical emergency involving such passenger. Directs the Secretary to appoint an individual within the Department of Transportation to serve as a liaison to family members of the passenger. Directs the Secretary to review: (1) the compliance of each air carrier with the requirements of this Act; and (2) the procedures established at each airport for meeting passengers with medical emergencies. Requires the Secretary to: (1) keep statistics on the number of in-flight medical emergencies that occur each year; and (2) study the feasibility of using satellite communications of Global Position Satellites as a method of improving communications between pilots, ground medical personnel, and air traffic controllers. Limits the liability of air carriers and individuals in providing medical assistance in the case of an in-flight medical emergency.</summary>
</bill>
