<bill session="108" type="h" number="1020" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Clean Air Act requirements relating to gasoline to prevent future supply shortages and price spikes in the gasoline market, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400351"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400159" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="2003-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2003-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="6"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Farm manure"/>
    <term name="Fibers"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Oxygen"/>
    <term name="Oxygenates"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Plants"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Reformulated gasoline"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2003--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to allow the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to approve a provision in a State implementation plan controlling or prohibiting the use of a motor vehicle fuel or additive only if such control requires the use of either Federal clean burning gasoline (regarding which the Administrator is directed to establish requirements under this Act, replacing those for fuel currently called "reformulated gasoline") or low Reid Vapor Pressure (RVP) gasoline (as defined in this Act) for use during the high ozone season. Permits previously approved plan provisions effecting such controls to remain in effect for four years after enactment of this Act only if the State reevaluates the provisions and establishes that their benefits in terms of air quality improvement, consistent supply, production costs, and stable prices exceed the benefits of modifying them to require the use of Federal clean burning fuel or low RVP gasoline.Repeals reformulated gasoline oxygen content requirements.Prohibits, effective January 1, 2007, the introduction into commerce of any fuel containing methyl tertiary butyl ether.Requires that, beginning in 2004, gasoline sold in the United States be comprised of a specified percentage of renewable fuel (ethanol or biomass-derived fuel or other fuel used to reduce the quantity of fossil fuel present in gasoline). Provides for adjustment of such percentage in a State and a program of credits for use and exchange by refiners, blenders, and importers. Expresses the sense of Congress in support of the promotion of ethanol as the primary renewable fuel.Directs the Administrator to conduct a study of emissions and air quality changes attributable to this Act's amendments.</summary>
</bill>
