<bill session="108" type="h" number="5163" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-11-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Reorganization Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Reorganization Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Reorganization Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Reorganization Act</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Reorganization Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide the Department of Transportation a more focused research organization with an emphasis on innovative technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="2004-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Science, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T22:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 108-749, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T22:50:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Energy and Commerce Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 6, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T22:51:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Science Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 6, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T22:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-06T22:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Science discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-10-06T22:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="466">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 466.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T01:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. LaTourette moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T01:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8340-8344" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T01:00:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5163.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-10-07T01:05:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8340-8342" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T01:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2004-11-16" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11390" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-11-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2004-11-30" type="public" number="108-426">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-426.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF17" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2952"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic congestion"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/30/2004--Public Law.
Norman Y. Mineta Research and Special Programs Reorganization Act - (Sec. 2) Amends Federal transportation law to establish the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) in the Department of Transportation (DOT), headed by an Administrator with professional experience in pipeline safety, hazardous materials safety, or other transportation safety, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Provides for a Deputy Administrator, appointed by the Secretary of Transportation, and an Assistant Administrator for Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety (who shall also be the Chief Safety Officer), appointed in the competitive service by the Secretary. (Sec. 3) Transfers the Bureau of Transportation Statistics (BTS) to the Research and Innovative Technology Administration (established by this Act). Requires the BTS Director to be appointed in the competitive service by the Secretary, instead (as currently) by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. (Sec. 4) Replaces the Research and Special Programs Administration (RSPA) with the Research and Innovative Technology Administration (RITA), which shall be headed by an Administrator appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Transfers the powers and duties of the RSPA Administrator to the RITA Administrator. Directs the Administrator to carry out the responsibilities of the Secretary for: (1) coordination, facilitation, and review of DOT research and development programs and activities; (2) advancement of innovative technologies, including intelligent transportation systems projects and products; (3) comprehensive transportation statistics research, analysis, and reporting; (4) education and training in transportation and transportation-related fields; and (5) activities of the Volpe National Transportation Center. Declares that nothing in this Act shall grant any authority to RITA over research and other programs, activities, standards, or regulations administered by the Secretary through the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, except those provided for in highway and traffic safety programs administered under specified Federal law pertaining to highways and the National Driver Register, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act. Establishes in RITA an Office of Intermodalism. Directs the Administrator of RITA to report to Congress on DOT research activities. Requires the Administrator, in developing the report, to: (1) solicit input from a wide range of stakeholders; (2) take into account how the research and development activities of other Federal, State, private sector, and not-for-profit institutions contribute to reducing traffic congestion, improving mobility, and promoting safety; and (3) address methods to avoid unnecessary duplication of efforts in achieving such purposes. (Sec. 6) Directs the DOT Inspector General to report to the Secretary and the PHMSA Administrator a list of: (1) each statutory mandate regarding pipeline safety or hazardous materials safety that has not been implemented; and (2) each open safety recommendation made by the National Transportation Safety Board or the Inspector General regarding pipeline safety or hazardous materials safety. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on the specific actions taken to implement such mandates. Requires the Secretary to report annually to Congress on each open safety recommendation and the DOT response. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to provide for the orderly transfer of duties and powers under this Act by 90 days after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
