<bill session="104" type="h" number="164" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Trust Funds Integrity Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend titles II and XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure the integrity of the social security trust funds by reconstituting the Boards of Trustees of such trust funds by and the Managing Trustee of such trust funds to increase their independence, by providing for annual investment plans to guide investment of amounts in such trust funds, and by removing unnecessary restrictions on investment and disinvestment of amounts in such trust funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-04">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-11">
      <text>See H.R.491.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="104" type="h" number="491"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="491"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Investment analysis"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/4/1995--Introduced.
Social Security Trust Funds Integrity Act of 1995 - Amends titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to restructure the Board of Trustees of the trust funds supporting the OASDI and Medicare programs, with each Board composed of members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, on a bipartisan basis at the recommendation of House and Senate leadership and the five largest organizations representing senior citizens. Makes it the duty of the Managing Trustee chairing the Board to invest trust fund amounts according to an annual investment plan the Board is required to formulate and submit to the President and the Congress. Removes restrictions on investment and disinvestment of amounts in such trust funds.</summary>
</bill>
