<bill session="104" type="hr" number="140" updated="2013-07-14T18:46:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-05-10T13:16:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-05-10T13:16:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 961) to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408976"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-09T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 104-114, by Mr. Quillen.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-09T15:21:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 961 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation now printed in the bill. Amendments previously printed in the Congressional record shall be given priority of consideration. Before consideration of any other amendment it shall be in order to consider the amendment printed in the report accompanying this resolution, debatable for 10 minutes, and not subject to further amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-05-09T15:21:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="45">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 45.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4681-4690" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T11:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T12:57:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1995-05-10T13:16:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="311" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 414 - 4 (Roll no. 311).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T13:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="104" type="h" number="961"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/1995--Introduced.
Sets forth the open rule for the consideration of H.R. 961 (Clean Water Amendments of 1995).</summary>
</bill>
