<bill session="108" type="h" number="5182" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Protection Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to clarify the mission and responsibilities of the Department of Homeland Security with respect to the protection of civil rights and civil liberties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400402"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400230" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400270" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2004-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400356" joined="2004-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="2004-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security (Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
      <reference ref="Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence and Counterterrorism.</text>
      <committee name="House Homeland Security"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security (Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHM05" subcommittee="Intelligence and Counterterrorism" name="House Homeland Security (Select)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2536"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2004--Introduced.
Homeland Security Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Protection Act of 2004 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to include within the primary mission of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to ensure that civil rights are not diminished by efforts aimed at securing the homeland. Requires DHS's Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties to report directly to the Secretary of DHS. Includes among the Officer's responsibilities to: (1) assist the Secretary, directorates, and offices of DHS to develop, implement, and periodically review DHS policies and procedures to ensure that the protection of civil rights is appropriately incorporated into DHS programs and activities; (2) oversee compliance with requirements relating to civil rights; (3) coordinate with the DHS Privacy Officer; and (4) investigate complaints and information indicating possible abuses of civil rights unless the DHS Inspector General (IG) determines that such complaints or information should be investigated by the IG. Directs the IG to designate a senior official within the IG's Office to perform specified functions, including initiating investigations of alleged abuses by DHS employees, officials, contractors, or grantees. Requires the Privacy Officer to report directly to the Secretary. Makes the Privacy Officer responsible for coordinating with the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties to ensure that programs, policies, and procedures involving civil rights and privacy are addressed in a comprehensive manner and that Congress receives appropriate reports.</summary>
</bill>
