<bill session="105" type="h" number="1634" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To set forth certain principles that should be adhered to by any United States national conducting an industrial cooperation project in the People's Republic of China or Tibet.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1997-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia and the Pacific.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Operations and Human Rights, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asia and the Pacific" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA12" subcommittee="International Operations and Human Rights" name="House International Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Birth control"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nonviolence"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Public demonstrations"/>
    <term name="Publishers and publishing"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Trials"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/1997--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that U.S. nationals conducting industrial cooperation projects in China or Tibet should adhere to certain principles (known as the Harry Wu Principles). Declares that they should: (1) suspend the use of any merchandise that they have reason to believe was produced by convict or forced labor, and refuse to use forced labor in their projects; (2) seek to ensure that political or religious views, sex, ethnic or national background, or association with dissidents will not prohibit hiring, lead to harassment, demotion, or dismissal of an individual employed in the industrial cooperation project; (3) ensure that methods of production used in the projects do not pose unnecessary danger to workers and the surrounding neighborhoods and environment; (4) strive to use business enterprises that are not controlled by the government of China; (5) prohibit any military presence on the premises of the project; (6) promote freedom of association and assembly among the employees of the U.S. national; (7) urge the government of China to disclose a complete list of those individuals arrested since March 1989, end incommunicado detention and torture, and provide international observers access to places of detention in China and Tibet and to trials of prisoners arrested in connection with the pro-democracy events of April through June, 1989, and the pro-democracy demonstrations in Tibet since 1987; (8) discourage or prevent compulsory political indoctrination programs from taking place on project premises; (9) promote freedom of expression of all kinds; and (10) prevent harassment of workers who decide freely the number and spacing of their children, and prohibit compulsory population control activities on the premises of the project. Directs the Secretary of State to forward a copy of these principles to the member nations of the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, and encourage them to promote similar principles. Directs each U.S. national conducting an industrial cooperation project in China or Tibet to register with the Secretary and indicate whether they agree to implement such principles.</summary>
</bill>
