<bill session="107" type="h" number="1576" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-08-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-08-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">James Peak Wilderness, Wilderness Study, and Protection Area Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">James Peak Wilderness and Protection Area Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">James Peak Wilderness and Protection Area Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate the James Peak Wilderness and Protection Area in the Arapaho and Roosevelt National Forests in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-04-30">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05T13:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-316.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-12-05T13:21:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="191">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 191.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-12-11T21:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McInnis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-11T21:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9180-9184" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-11T21:02:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1576.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-12-11T21:23:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9180-9181" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-12-11T21:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Health. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 107-200.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="477">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 477.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2002-08-01" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8013-8019" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2002-08-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2002-08-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2002-08-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2002-08-21">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2002-08-21" type="public" number="107-216">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-216.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG" subcommittee="Public Health" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1711"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grassland ecology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Pipeline safety"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2001--Passed House amended.
James Peak Wilderness and Protection Area Act - Amends the Colorado Wilderness Act of 1993 to designate specified lands in the Arapaho/ Roosevelt National Forest as the James Peak Wilderness.Amends the Indian Peaks Wilderness Area and Arapaho National Recreation Area and the Oregon Islands Wilderness Area Act to add specified Federal lands in the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest to the Indian Peaks Wilderness Area.Designates specified land in the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest as the James Peak Protection Area. Provides that the Area shall be managed and administered in the same manner as the management area prescription designations identified for these lands in the 1997 Revision of the Land and Resource Management Plan for the National Forest and the Pawnee National Grasslands.Withdraws all Federal land in the Area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) the operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to complete a review and inventory of all roads and trails in the Area on which use was allowed on September 10, 2001, and to ensure that motorized and mechanized travel shall be permitted only on roads and trails identified as open to use or established as replacements, as nonpermanent roads for hazardous fuels reduction, fire, insect or disease control projects, or other management purposes, as roads for reasonable access, as a specified loop trail, or for the construction of a trail for non-motorized use following the corridor designated as the Continental Divide trail. Prohibits: (1) the establishment of any new trails or roads except for such purposes; (2) allowing any timber harvesting except as needed for management purposes specified above or protection of public health or safety; and (3) permitting motorized vehicle use on Rogers Pass trail. Requires the Secretary to allow for maintenance of rights-of-ways and access roads to the extent necessary to operate the natural gas pipeline in a manner that: (1) avoids negative impacts on public safety; and (2) allows for compliance with Federal pipeline safety requirements. Requires the Secretary to follow the laws of the State of Colorado in obtaining and holding any new water rights with respect to the Area.Sets forth provisions regarding the acquisition of lands within: (1) the Area owned by the Colorado State Land Board; and (2) the portion of the Jim Creek drainage within the Area. Requires the Secretary to submit a report to specified congressional committees on any agreement or the status of negotiations conducted to acquire such lands.Directs the Forest Supervisor of the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest to: (1) establish a trailhead and corresponding facilities and services to regulate use of National Forest System lands in the vicinity of the Fall River basin south of the communities of Alice Township and St. Mary's Glacier in Colorado; and (2) submit a report to specified congressional committees regarding any additional funding to implement such trailhead, facilities, and services.Directs the Secretary to: (1) study the suitability and feasibility of establishing a loop trail for mechanized and other non-motorized recreation connecting Rogers Pass and Rollins Pass road; and (2) establish such trail if establishment would be suitable and feasible.Directs the Secretary, if requested, to provide technical assistance and otherwise cooperate in the repair of Rollins Pass road in Grand, Gilpin, and Boulder, Colorado, Counties.Directs the Secretary, in connection with the first revision of the land and resources management plan for the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest, to evaluate and make recommendations to Congress regarding the suitability of the lands managed under the management prescription specified above for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System.</summary>
</bill>
