<bill session="104" type="h" number="1947" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Miscellaneous Fuel Tax Corrections Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to revise certain rules relating to fuel excise tax refunds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1995-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1995-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1995-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="1995-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1995-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="412001" joined="1995-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7765-7766"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Dyes and dyeing"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/1995--Introduced.
Miscellaneous Fuel Tax Corrections Act of 1995 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to mandate interest on gasoline tax refunds to wholesale distributors, if the refunds are not paid within a specified period. Limits the period in which a refund claim may be filed. Revises requirements regarding the filing of claims for refunds concerning nontaxable uses of diesel and aviation fuel. Allows a refund, with interest, to the ultimate vendor (currently, a refund, without interest, to the ultimate purchaser) for the tax paid on non-gasoline fuel used in a bus. Prohibits applying to diesel fuel used as heating oil provisions authorizing certain ultimate purchaser refunds (without interest). Makes any use of diesel fuel in a diesel-powered boat nontaxable under provisions relating to manufacturers' excise taxes. Makes dyed diesel fuel sold for use or used in a diesel-powered boat taxable if a tax is imposed under provisions relating to retail excise taxes and that tax is not paid. Allows, without penalty, the addition of kerosene to dyed fuel in certain circumstances. Considers nontaxable the accidental addition of diesel fuel on which tax has been imposed to dyed diesel fuel.</summary>
</bill>
