<bill session="105" type="hc" number="54" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Recognizing the anniversary of the proclamation of independence of the Republic of Belarus, expressing concern over the Belarusan Government's infringement on freedom of the press in direct violation of the Helsinki Accords and the constitution of Belarus, and expressing concern about the proposed union between Russia and Belarus.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1997-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1997-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Belarus"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Separation of powers"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1997--Introduced.
Recognizes the anniversary of the declaration of the independent Republic of Belarus. Calls for the U.S. Government to press the Government of President Lukashenka to: (1) abide by the provisions of the Helsinki Accords and the Constitution of the Republic of Belarus; (2) guarantee freedom of the press; (3) allow for the flowering of Belarusan culture; and (4) enforce the separation of powers. Calls for the Congress to join with Belarusans throughout the world in: (1) defending the statehood and democracy of Belarus; (2) sustaining the country's Constitution; and (3) preventing the loss by Belarus of its hard-won nationhood and its opportunity to survive as an equal and full-fledged member state among the sovereign nations of the world.</summary>
</bill>
