<bill session="106" type="h" number="3294" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Water Regulation Improvement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to exclude from stormwater regulation certain areas and activities, and to improve the regulation and limit the liability of local governments concerning co-permitting and the implementation of control measures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400037" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400118" joined="2000-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2000-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="2000-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400293" joined="2000-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400311" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400501" joined="2000-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="1999-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="2000-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1999-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="2000-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1999-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400410" joined="1999-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1706"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for water pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/10/1999--Introduced.
Water Regulation Improvement Act of 1999 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require permits for discharges from municipal storm sewers to: (1) recognize the responsibility of governmental entities to carry out specified control measures to reduce the discharge of pollutants; and (2) absolve local governmental entities of liability in cases where such an entity relies on a co-permittee or another governmental entity to comply with any requirement to implement a control measure in which the co-permittee or other entity assumes responsibility but fails to implement the measure.Prohibits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, for certain stormwater discharges for which permits are not required, from requiring a local governmental entity to obtain a permit for any stormwater discharge associated with an above-ground vegetated drainage ditch or a drainage way owned or operated in connection with a road or street under its jurisdiction. Provides that such discharges and those regulated as being associated with industrial activity or with significant violation of a water quality standard or significant contributions of pollutants shall not include stormwater discharges associated with: (1) a construction activity that disturbs no more than five acres of land; or (2) a routine maintenance activity associated with a road, street, or vegetated road ditch or drainage way.</summary>
</bill>
