<bill session="105" type="h" number="1666" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 49, United States Code, to eliminate provisions of Federal law that provide special support for, or burdens on, the operation of Amtrak as a passenger rail carrier, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1998-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1997-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2928"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW09" subcommittee="Railroads" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Dismissal wage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad abandonments"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad policy"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1997--Introduced.
Amends Federal transportation law to repeal specified authorities with respect to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak), eliminating intercity rail passenger transportation (while retaining Amtrak commuter services). Repeals a provision which provides for the judicial review of the discontinuance of a route, a train, or transportation, or the reduction in the frequency of transportation by Amtrak. Authorizes appropriations in decreasing amounts over four fiscal years. Repeals specified laws that apply to Amtrak operations, abolishing the Board of Directors. Declares that the United States relinquishes all rights held in any stock, note of indebtedness, or mortgage issued by or entered into with Amtrak. Repeals: (1) certain provisions which require Amtrak to make an agreement to avoid duplicating employee functions; (2) all authority for operation of the Amtrak route system; and (3) all authority for the Northeast Corridor improvement program. Prohibits a rail carrier employee whose employment is terminated as a result of a discontinuance of intercity rail passenger service from receiving any wage continuation or severance benefit in excess of six months pay. Authorizes a rail carrier to require an employee whose position is eliminated as a result of such discontinuance to transfer to any vacant position for which he or she can be made qualified on any part of the rail carrier's system. (Sec. 8) Amends the Federal Employers' Liability Act (or Employers' Liability Act) to declare that it shall not apply to common carriers to the extent they provide rail passenger transportation.</summary>
</bill>
