<bill session="104" type="h" number="996" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Targeted Individual Health Insurance Reform Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve portability, access, and fair rating for health insurance coverage for individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300003" joined="1995-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1995-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1995-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1995-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300047" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1995-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400267" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1995-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1995-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="409228" joined="1995-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1995-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1995-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400427" joined="1995-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1995-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E402-403"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Labor, HHS.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-03-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adopted children"/>
    <term name="Catastrophic health insurance"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health care reform"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/21/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Definitions and Special Rules Title II: Access to and Fair Rating of Health Insurance Coverage for Individuals Subtitle A: Increased Availability and Continuity of Health Insurance Coverage for Individuals Subtitle B: Establishment of Standards; Enforcement; Effective Dates Targeted Individual Health Insurance Reform Act of 1995 - Title I: Definitions and Special Rules - Sets forth definitions for this Act, including defining "medisave coverage" as consisting of: (1) coverage of expenses exceeding a catastrophic deductible amount; and (2) a cash benefit that accumulates while not used, to be used for deductibles, cost-sharing, and other expenses. Title II: Access to and Fair Rating of Health Insurance Coverage for Individuals - Subtitle A: Increased Availability and Continuity of Health Insurance Coverage for Individuals - Regulates the periods during which insurers of individuals may deny, limit, or exclude coverage based on health status or related matters. (Sec. 2002) Reduces any exclusion period by any time in continuous coverage. Considers newborns and adopted children as not having any preexisting condition. (Sec. 2003) Prohibits cancellation (or denial of renewal) except for premium nonpayment, fraud, or plan noncompliance, or if the insurer is ceasing to provide any such coverage. (Sec. 2011) Requires insurers of individuals to meet the standards of these provisions. Provides for determination by the Secretary of Health and Human Services that a private entity has established standards for provider networks. (Sec. 2012) Prohibits coverage denial on the basis of a utilization review program unless the program meets the standards determined by the Secretary to have been established by a private entity. (Sec. 2021) Requires insurers of individuals to make available general, catastrophic, and medisave coverage. (Sec. 2022) Prohibits rates from varying except for specified factors. Subtitle B: Establishment of Standards; Enforcement; Effective Dates - Provides for development: (1) by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners of standards regarding subtitle A; and (2) by a private entity regarding utilization review standards. (Sec. 2102) Allows States to elect whether to enforce standards under this Act. Directs the Secretary to enforce them if a State does not. (Sec. 2103) Preempts related State or local standards and laws, including certain State anti-managed care laws.</summary>
</bill>
