<bill session="105" type="hr" number="560" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-10-01T17:35:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-10-01T17:35:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3789) to amend title 28, United States Code, to enlarge Federal Court jurisdiction over purported class actions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400242"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-10-01T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-758, by Mr. Linder.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-10-01T17:35:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3789 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. Each section of the committee amendment in the nature of a substitute shall be considered as read. During consideration of the bill for amendment, the Chairman of the Committee of the Whole may accord priority in recognition on the basis of whether the Member offering an amendment has caused it to be printed in the Congressional Record. The Chairman may...</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-10-01T17:35:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="261">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 261.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="3789"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1998--Introduced.
Sets forth the rule (open) for the consideration of H.R. 3789 (enlarging Federal court jurisdiction over purported class actions).</summary>
</bill>
