<bill session="105" type="h" number="2901" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To improve cellular telephone service in selected rural areas and to achieve equitable treatment of certain cellular license applicants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="406431" joined="1997-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auctions"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/7/1997--Introduced.
Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), notwithstanding a certain proceeding concerning application for production of cellular radiotelephone services, to: (1) reinstate each of three specified applicants as a selectee under the covered rural service area licensing proceeding; and (2) permit application amendment, at any time before final licensing action in the covered rural service area, in order to update factual information and comply with FCC rules. Directs the FCC to: (1) award licensees under such proceeding within 90 days after enactment of this Act; and (2) require such applicant to provide cellular radiotelephone service to subscribers in accordance with FCC rules. Prohibits the FCC, during the three-year period after an applicant license is granted, from authorizing the transfer or assignment of that license.</summary>
</bill>
