<bill session="106" type="h" number="4231" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 47 of title 10, United States Code (the Uniform Code of Military Justice), to clarify and reaffirm the intent of Congress regarding the court-martial sentence of confinement for life without eligibility for parole.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400549"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Armed Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Courts-martial and courts of inquiry"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Mandatory sentences"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Presidential pardons"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/2000--Introduced.
Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice relating to the court-martial sentence of confinement for life without eligibility for parole (sentence) to: (1) repeal a provision allowing the Secretary of the military department concerned to take certain actions to set aside such a sentence; (2) state that a sentence reprieve or pardon can originate only with the President; (3) state that a military department Secretary, Under Secretary, or Assistant Secretary may not commute, remit, or suspend that part of a sentence providing for life without eligibility for parole; (4) prohibit the suspension of such part of a sentence after it is ordered executed; and (5) prohibit the granting of parole with respect to such sentences.</summary>
</bill>
