<bill session="106" type="h" number="4148" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-10-18T18:51:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-10-18T18:51:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Tribal Contract Support Cost Technical Amendments of 2000</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Tribal Contract Support Cost Technical Amendments of 2000</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Tribal Contract Support Cost Technical Amendments of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To make technical amendments to the provisions of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act relating to contract support costs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="2000-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-03-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E462"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from HHS.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12T16:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-837.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-09-12T16:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="495">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 495.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10026-10028" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T17:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4148.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-17T17:58:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Udall (NM) objected to the 20001018 vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed until Oct. 18. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-18T18:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10082" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2000-10-18T18:51:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/17/2000 H1026-10027" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2000-10-18T18:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/18/2000--Passed House amended.
Tribal Contract Support Cost Technical Amendments of 2000 - Amends the Indian Self- Determination and Education Assistance Act to provide that an Indian tribe or tribal organization administering a contract or compact shall be entitled to recover its full indirect costs associated with any other Federal funding received by such tribe or tribal organization (other than funds paid under this Act), consistent with the tribe's or tribal organization's indirect cost rate agreement with its cognizant Federal agency. Entitles such tribes or tribal organizations that employ an indirect cost pool that includes both funds paid under this Act and other Federal funds to use or expend all Federal funding received by such tribe or tribal organization in such pool in the same manner as permitted in provisions under the Act relating to allowable uses of funds without approval of the Secretary of any Federal agency providing funds to such tribe or tribal organization.Makes, within the Indian Health Service of the Department of Health and Human Services, tribal contract support cost entitlements the responsibility of the Office of Tribal Programs, subject to the tribe's or tribal organization's indirect cost rate agreement with its cognizant Federal agency.Provides that contract support costs that are eligible for the purposes of receiving funding under the Act include direct contract support costs associated with all Federal employees employed in connection with the program, service, function, or activity that is the subject of the contract, including all Federal employees paid with funds generated from third-party collections.Requires the Secretary of the Interior to pay preaward and startup costs without regard to the year in which such costs were incurred, including such costs identified by the Indian Health Service in a September 1999 report entitled "FY 1999 IHS CSC Shortfall Data."</summary>
</bill>
