<bill session="106" type="h" number="5001" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Fair Care for Seniors and Children Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for equitable payments to providers of services under the Medicare Program, and to amend title XIX of such Act to provide for coverage of additional children under the Medicaid Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400434"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400186" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400351" joined="2000-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="2000-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-08-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare managed care"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Medicare Program Subtitle A: Medicare+Choice Program Subtitle B: Inpatient Hospital Services Subtitle C: Home Health Services Title II: Medicaid Program Subtitle A: Expansion of Coverage of Children Under the Medicaid Program Subtitle B: Prospective Payment System for Federally-qualified Health Centers and Rural Health Clinics Fair Care for Seniors and Children Act of 2000 - Title I: Medicare Program - Subtitle A: Medicare+Choice Program - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for: (1) increasing the minimum payment amount in 2001 for any area in a metropolitan statistical area with a population of more than 250,000; (2) increasing the national per capita Medicare+Choice growth percentage in 2001 and 2002; (3) eliminating the budget neutrality adjustment beginning in 2002 under blended capitation rate provisions; (4) revising calculation of area-specific and national percentage capitation rates; (5) increasing the update for payment areas with only one or no Medicare+Choice contracts; (6) permitting higher negotiated rates in certain Medicare+Choice payment areas below the national average; (7) permitting reasonable cost reimbursement for payment areas with no more than one Medicare+Choice contract under certain conditions; and (8) phasing in risk adjustment methodology over a ten year period based on data from all settings.Delays from July to November 2000 the deadline for offering and withdrawing Medicare+Choice plans for 2001.Subtitle B: Inpatient Hospital Services - Amends SSA title XVIII with regard to payment to hospitals for inpatient hospital services to provide for the elimination of authority to estimate costs incurred by a hospital for wages.Subtitle C: Home Health Services - Amends SSA title XVIII with regard to the prospective payment system (PPS) for home health services to eliminate the 15 percent reduction in the cost limits and per beneficiary limits under such PPS.Title II: Medicaid Program - Subtitle A: Expansion of Coverage of Children under the Medicaid Program - Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to provide for the use of funds under the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) under SSA title XXI for an enhanced matching rate for coverage of additional children under the Medicaid program. Provides for the expansion of eligibility option for children under the Medicaid program.Provides for the expansion of the presumptive eligibility option for children under the Medicaid program.Amends SSA title XIX to provide for use of an enhanced match for expanded Medicaid child coverage.Amends SSA title XXI to provide for application of an increased proportion of the SCHIP allotment for special initiatives and similar purposes.Subtitle B: Prospective Payment System for Federally-qualified Health Centers and Rural Health Clinics - Amends SSA title XIX to provide for establishment of a PPS for Federally-qualified health centers and rural health clinics.</summary>
</bill>
