<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="937" updated="2013-07-17T08:17:20-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="3408" sequence="6"/>
  <status datetime="2012-02-15T16:46:00-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-02-15"/>
  <description>Manager's amendment changes the underlying bill's requirement that the Department of the Interior substitute two new lease blocks for each one lease block that is deferred from a lease sale at the request of the Department of Defense; to replace each deferred lease block with one new lease block; calls attention to the existing authority under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act for the President to designate National Defense Areas on the outer Continental Shelf that are restricted from exploration and operation; and also requires the North Aleutian Basin lease sale to be conducted by 2015 rather than one year after enactment of the Act.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 6 printed in Part A of House Report 112-398 to change the underlying bill's requirement that the Department of the Interior substitute two new lease blocks for each one lease block that is deferred from a lease sale at the request of the Department of Defense, to replace each deferred lease block with one new lease block. The amendment also calls attention to the existing authority under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act for the President to designate National Defense Areas on the outer Continental Shelf that are restricted from exploration and operation. The amendment also requires the North Aleutian Basin lease sale to be conducted by 2015 rather than one year after enactment of the Act.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-15T16:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H773-774" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H773" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2012-02-15T16:46:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Hastings (WA) amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
