<bill session="105" type="h" number="4631" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Value in Supporting International Tourism in the United States Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Visit USA Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To create employment opportunities and to promote economic growth in the United States by establishing a public-private partnership between the United States travel and tourism industry and every level of government to work to make the United States the premiere travel and tourism destination in the world, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400129"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="1998-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-09-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1811"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: International Visitor Initiatives Title II: International Marketing Program Value in Supporting International Tourism in the United States Act of 1998 (or the Visit USA Act) - Title I: International Visitor Initiatives - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish an Intergovernmental Task Force for International Visitor Assistance. Requires the Task Force to: (1) examine, and report to the President and the Congress its recommendation on, signage at U.S. facilities (including airports, seaports, land border crossings, highways, and bus, train, and other public transit stations); and (2) identify and suggest solutions to existing inadequacies, such as the adoption of uniform standards on international signage for use throughout the United States in order to facilitate international visitors' travel here. Requires the Task Force also to examine and report on: (1) the availability of multilingual travel and tourism information and means of disseminating such information; and (2) establishment of a toll-free, private-sector operated telephone number, staffed by multilingual operators, to provide assistance to international tourists coping with an emergency. Directs the Secretary to complete, as soon as practicable, a satellite system of accounting for the travel and tourism industry. Title II: International Marketing Program - Authorizes appropriations for U.S. National Tourism Organization international promotional activities. Prohibits the use of such funds for any purpose other than marketing, research, outreach, or any other activity designed to promote the United States as the premiere travel and tourism destination in the world. States that the Organization's general and administrative expenses shall be borne by the private sector.</summary>
</bill>
