<bill session="107" type="hr" number="311" updated="2013-07-14T18:56:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-12T13:28:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-12-12T13:28:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3295) to establish a program to provide funds to States to replace punch card voting systems, to establish the Election Assistance Commission to assist in the administration of Federal elections and to otherwise provide assistance with the administration of certain Federal election laws and programs, to establish minimum election administration standards for States and units of local government with responsibility for the administration of Federal elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-12-11T21:16:00-05:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-331, by Mr. Reynolds.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-11T21:16:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3295 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The amendment recommended by the Committee on House Administration now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-12-11T21:16:00-05:00" calendar="House" number="107">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 107.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12T12:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9254-9264" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12T12:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 311.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12T13:06:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2001-12-12T13:28:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="487" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 193 (Roll no. 487).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9254-9255" label="text as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-12-12T13:28:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="107" type="h" number="3295"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/11/2001--Reported to House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule (closed) for the consideration of H.R. 3295 (voting process reform).</summary>
</bill>
