<amendment session="104" chamber="h" number="356" updated="2013-07-17T07:50:47-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="961" sequence="1"/>
  <status datetime="1995-05-10">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400374"/>
  <offered datetime="1995-05-10"/>
  <description>Amendments make certain technical corrections and provide clarifying language; lower the definition of "small community" from 20,000 to 10,000 people for the purpose of granting permit modifications for innovative treatment technologies; eliminate the restriction that only 20 percent of any county, borough, or parish may be classified as Type A wetlands; lower the authorization for pollution prevention activities from $50 million per year to $21.2 million, and stipulates that not more than $10 million may be used each year to provide technical assistance to small and rural water treatment works; require written permission from private property owners for Federal employees to enter their property in order to identify or classify wetlands; and clarify the definition of vernal ponds.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment consisting of several amendments offered en bloc. In addition to making several technical modifications to the bill, the amendment would do the following: Lower the threshold for granting permit modifications for innovative treatment technologies from communities with populations of 20,000 to those with populations of 10,000; eliminate restrictions on classifying more than 20% of any county, borough, or parish as a Type A wetlands; lower the authorization for pollution prevention activities from $50 million per year to $21.2 million; require federal employees to obtain written permission from property owners before entering private property in order to identify wetlands; clarify the definition of vernal pools.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T15:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendments (A001) offered by Mr. Shuster.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-05-10T15:49:00-04:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Shuster amendments (A001) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
