<bill session="108" type="h" number="3584" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Regulatory Fairness and Physician Fee Update Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase the amount of payment for physicians' services under the Medicare Program and to provide regulatory relief and contracting flexibility under the Medicare Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Teleconferencing"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2003--Introduced.
Medicare Regulatory Fairness and Physician Fee Update Act - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise requirements with regard to Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) and updates for physicians' services and to add a definition of supplier. Includes a number of regulatory reduction, contracting, and administrative changes, such as adding requirements for information security for Medicare administrative contractors and increased flexibility in Medicare administration. Requires the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress with respect to advisory opinion authority. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish a small provider technical assistance demonstration program; (2) appoint within the Department of Health and Human Services a Medicare Beneficiary Ombudsman; (3) establish a beneficiary outreach demonstration program; (4) include additional information in notices of explanation of Medicare benefits; and (5) provide public information that enables hospital discharge planners, Medicare beneficiaries, and the public to identify skilled nursing facilities participating in the Medicare program. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary to develop and transmit to Congress and the Comptroller General a plan under which the functions of administrative law judges responsible for hearing cases under the Medicare program are transferred from the responsibility of the Commissioner to the Secretary and the Department. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary to implement the transition plan and transfer those administrative law judge functions from the Social Security Administration to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to assure the independence of administrative law judges performing the administrative law judge functions transferred from the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and its contractors. Directs the Secretary to establish a process for: (1) expedited access to judicial review and prompt determinations for providers, suppliers, or beneficiaries who have filed an appeal so that they may obtain access to judicial review when a review entity determines that the Departmental Appeals Board does not have the authority to decide the question of law or regulation relevant to the matters in controversy and there is no material issue of fact in dispute; and (2) expedited review of certain provider agreement determinations. Revises the Medicare appeals process. Provides for the recovery of overpayments through the use of repayment plans. Outlines an enrollment process for providers of services and suppliers. Requires the Secretary to develop a: (1) process for correction of minor errors and omissions without pursuing the appeals process; (2) prior determination process for certain items and services; and (3) program of outreach and education for beneficiaries and providers of services and other persons on the appropriate use of advance beneficiary notices and coverage policies under the Medicare program. Directs the Secretary to establish a mediation process for local coverage determinations.</summary>
</bill>
