<bill session="105" type="hr" number="244" updated="2012-11-01T22:47:16-05:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-01T00:07:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-01T00:07:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Demanding that the Office of the United States Attorney for the Central District of California file criminal charges against Hermandad Mexicana Nacional for failure to comply with a valid subpoena under the Federal Contested Elections Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400401"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-29T21:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 253 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 244 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for consideration of the resolution in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T22:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 253 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T22:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 253. (CR H8253-8262)</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8253-8262" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T22:30:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 244 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Provides for consideration of the resolution in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T22:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30T23:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-10-01T00:07:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 203, 1 Present (Roll no. 478).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01T00:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections (House)"/>
    <term name="Contempt of court"/>
    <term name="Contested elections"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hispanic Americans"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>10/01/1997--Passed House amended.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;(There is 1 &lt;a href="/cgi-bin/bdquery/z?d105:HE00244:@@@D&amp;summ1&amp;"&gt;other summary&lt;/a&gt;).
Demands that the Office of the U.S. Attorney for the Central District of California carry out its responsibility by filing, pursuant to its determination that it is appropriate according to the law and the facts, criminal charges against Hermandad Mexicana Nacional for failure to comply with a valid subpoena issued under the Federal Contested Elections Act.</summary>
</bill>
