<bill session="104" type="hr" number="514" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to reduce the number of programs covered by each general appropriation bill.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1996--Introduced.
Amends rule XXI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit any provision from being reported any general appropriation bill containing the regular appropriations for any one of 14 parts of the Government (includes the Department of Veterans Affairs as one part) for a fiscal year if the provision contains the regular appropriations for any other of such parts for the fiscal year. Amends rule X to provide that the suballocations (or subdivisions) required to be made by the House Committee on Appropriations by the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 shall be among its subcommittees, except that the Subcommittee on VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies shall receive a separate suballocation for the Department of Veterans Affairs and a separate suballocation for the Department of Housing and Urban Development and independent agencies previously included in the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act.</summary>
</bill>
