<bill session="108" type="h" number="3936" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-11-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Health Programs Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Veterans Health Programs Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the principal office of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to be at any location in the Washington, D.C., metropolitan area, rather than only in the District of Columbia, and expressing the sense of Congress that a dedicated Veterans Courthouse and Justice Center should be provided for that Court and those it serves and should be located, if feasible, at a site owned by the United States that is part of or proximate to the Pentagon Reservation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by senate" type="official">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to increase the authorization of appropriations for grants to benefit homeless veterans, to improve programs for management and administration of veterans' facilities and health care programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400045" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400162" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400167" joined="2004-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400274" joined="2004-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400336" joined="2004-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400357" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2004-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E355"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T15:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 108-574, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T15:51:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than June 25, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T15:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-06-25T15:53:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="336">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 336.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20T17:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6076-6078" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20T17:29:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3936.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-07-20T17:39:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H6076-6077" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20T17:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11007" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 2485 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2004-10-09" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 2485 with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>See also S. 2485.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T14:41:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9772-9787" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9772-9777" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T14:42:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3936.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2004-11-17T15:23:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="pingpong" where="h">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T15:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-11-17">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-11-30">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2004-11-30" type="public" number="108-422">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-422.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2485"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="108" type="s" number="2485"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="108" type="s" number="2485"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Ex-prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Explosions"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Missing in action"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sexual harassment"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4049"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>11/30/2004--Public Law.
Department of Veterans Affairs Real Property and Facilities Management Improvement Act of 2004 - Title I: Real Property and Facilities Matters - Subtitle A: Real Property and Facilities Administration - (Sec. 101) Amends Federal veterans' provisions to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to dispose of excess real property of the Department of Veterans Affairs by: (1) transfer to or exchange with another Federal department or agency; or (2) conveyance to or exchange with a State or political subdivision, Indian tribe, public entity, or private person or entity (thereby eliminating certain other transfer requirements). Sets forth disposal procedures. Requires: (1) disposal proceeds to be deposited into the Capital Asset Fund (established in this section); and (2) the Secretary to include in annual budget justification documents a report on each such disposal. Provides authorized Fund uses. Authorizes FY 2005 appropriations to the Fund. (Sec. 102) Modifies business plan-based determinations relating to the Secretary's enhanced-use lease authority by: (1) requiring consideration of the needs of the Veterans Benefits Administration or the National Cemetery Administration; and (2) allowing the Department to receive facilities, space, or services in consideration for such a lease regardless of whether the facilities, space, or services are on the leased property. (Sec. 103) Authorizes funds in a Department construction or capital account that are available for a construction or non-recurring maintenance project to be used for the construction or relocation of a surface parking lot incidental to such project. (Sec. 104) Prohibits the Secretary from implementing a mission change for a medical facility (with an exception) until 90 days after the Secretary submits to the congressional veterans' committees written notice of the mission change. (Sec. 105) Terminates the Nursing Home Revolving Fund. Transfers unobligated balances to the Capital Asset Fund. (Sec. 106) Removes congressional notice-and-wait limits on the use of Advanced Planning Fund amounts for major medical facility projects when funds for such projects have already been authorized by law. (Sec. 107) Authorizes the Secretary to lease any undeveloped land or unused or underutilized buildings or lots of the National Cemetery Administration. Allows a lease term of up to ten years. Establishes in the Treasury the National Cemetery Administration Facilities Operation Fund to cover costs incurred by such Administration in operating and maintaining its property. Subtitle B: Transfers of Property - (Sec. 111) Directs the Administrator of General Services to transfer to the Secretary specified General Services Administration property north of the Army Reserve facility in Boise, Idaho, for purposes relating to the delivery of benefits to veterans. Subtitle C: Designation of Facilities - (Sec. 121) Designates the Department medical center in the Bronx, New York, as the James J. Peters Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center. (Sec. 122) Designates the memorial to former prisoners of war and members of the Armed Forces missing in action that is under construction at Riverside National Cemetery, California, as the Prisoner of War/Missing in Action National Memorial. Subtitle D: Other Matters - (Sec. 131) Requires the Secretary, upon determining to convey, lease, or dispose of all or part of the Louisville Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Kentucky, to engage in negotiations for such conveyance, lease, or disposal solely with the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Limits the duration of such requirement to one year after the commencement of such negotiations. Requires such negotiations to address the utilization of such Center for the primary purpose of the provision of services for veterans and related activities. Title II: Benefits Matters - (Sec. 201) Exempts veterans receiving hospice care from certain Department copayment requirements. (Sec. 202) Makes permanent (currently terminates at the end of 2004) the Department's authority to provide counseling and treatment to veterans suffering from an incident of sexual trauma that occurred during service. Expands such authority to include members of the reserves suffering from an incident that occurred during training. (Sec. 203) States that Department per diem payments to States for the care of veterans in State nursing homes shall not be considered a liability of a third party or otherwise utilized to offset or reduce any other payment made to assist veterans. (Sec. 204) Authorizes the Secretary to provide up to 14 days of care following birth for the newborn child of a woman veteran receiving maternity care furnished by the Department if the child was delivered in a Department facility or a Department-contracted facility. (Sec. 205) Directs the Secretary, subject to the appropriation of funds, to establish and operate at least one and up to three centers for research, education, and clinical activities on blast injuries. Outlines requirements for proposals submitted for the designation of a center. Authorizes appropriations. Requires reports during 2006 through 2008 from the Secretary to the veterans' committees on center status and activities. (Sec. 206) Extends through: (1) 2009 required reports from the Special Medical Advisory Group on care and treatment provided to disabled veterans; and (2) 2005 a pilot program to evaluate three different models of providing long-term care to veterans. (Sec. 207) Requires an annual report from the Secretary to the veterans' committees on the waiting times of veterans for appointments for care and services from the Department.</summary>
</bill>
