<bill session="108" type="h" number="4700" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">White River National Forest Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide special authority to the Secretary of Agriculture to convey certain Forest Service administrative sites in the White River National Forest in Colorado, to reserve the proceeds from such conveyances to help resolve the facilities needs of that national forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400265"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2004--Introduced.
White River National Forest Improvement Act of 2004 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) sell, lease, exchange, or otherwise convey all right of the United States in specified parcels of real property within the White River National Forest, Colorado; and (2) accept cash, land, improvements, and operational and maintenance services related to the administrative facilities of the Forest. Directs the Secretary to utilize such parcels and the consideration received in connection with implementing the financial arrangements, including public-private partnership transactions and full solution transactional packages. Authorizes the Secretary to modify the details of the Facility Master Plan and Appendix 3 of the plan (entitled "Baseline Analysis and Strategic Recommendations") consistent with the goal of solving the facilities needs of the Forest. Requires that any appraisal of real property considered necessary or desirable by the Secretary to carry out the conveyance conform to the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions. Permits the Secretary to accept a cash equalization payment in excess of 25 percent of the value of any real property conveyed by exchange. Sets forth provisions regarding solicitations of offers, use of competitive methods, and use of brokers. Directs the Secretary to deposit the net receipts of a conveyance into the fund established by the Sisk Act.</summary>
</bill>
