<bill session="105" type="h" number="368" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Guam Land Return Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Organic Act of Guam to provide the government of Guam with a right-of-first refusal regarding excess Federal real property located in Guam.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400516"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, General Services.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1997--Introduced.
Guam Land Return Act - Amends the Organic Act of Guam to direct the Administrator of General Services to notify the Government of Guam of any excess U.S. real property there and to convey to Guam all right, title, and interest of the United States in such property, if Guam notifies the Administrator of its intention to acquire it (thus granting the Government of Guam the right-of-first refusal to such property). Amends other Federal law to repeal a specified condition on disposal by Guam of lands conveyed to it by the United States. Exempts Federal lands within the Guam National Wildlife Refuge, including those within the refuge overlay under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, from the provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
