<bill session="105" type="h" number="2996" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Partnership Rollup Efficiency Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to revise the definition of limited partnership rollup transaction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Limited partnerships"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to exclude from the definition of limited partnership rollup transaction any combination of a single limited partnership or multiple limited partnerships whose real estate assets consist solely of partial interests in the same property, with an unaffiliated issuer of securities. States that such a combination is not conditioned upon the completion of any other acquisition transaction, in exchange for securities (or a combination or alternative offer of securities and cash), if the securities issued in the combination to the limited partners in the combining partnership or partnerships represent ten percent or less of a class of securities that is, or will be upon notice of issuance, listed on the New York Stock Exchange or American Stock Exchange or the National Market System of the Nasdaq Stock Market (or any successor to such entities) and are part of a class of securities so listed for a year or more.</summary>
</bill>
