<bill session="106" type="h" number="2911" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Delta Regional Authority Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide economic development assistance and the planning and coordination needed to assist in development of the lower Mississippi Delta region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="2000-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400549" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400082" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400588" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400519" joined="1999-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="2000-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400399" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400402" joined="1999-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400516" joined="1999-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2000-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-09-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Banking and Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Opportunity" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community leadership"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Vocational education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: The Delta Regional Authority Title II: Delta Programs Part A: Programs Part B: General Provisions Title III: Authorizations and Miscellaneous Provisions Delta Regional Authority Act of 1999 - Requires public investments made in the Mississippi River Delta region (region) (parts of Arkansas, Illinois, Kentucky, Louisiana, Mississippi, Missouri, and Tennessee surrounding such Delta) to be concentrated in areas of significant and concentrated economic distress and where the impact on the region's poorest communities will be the greatest.Title I: The Delta Regional Authority - Establishes the Delta Regional Authority to: (1) develop comprehensive and coordinated plans and programs, establish priorities, and approve grants for the economic development of the region; (2) provide for research, demonstration, investigation, assessment and evaluation of such region's assets and needs; (3) encourage the formation and capacity of local development districts and private investment in industrial, commercial, and other economic development projects; and (4) provide a forum for the consideration of problems and possible solutions of the region. Provides conflict-of-interest requirements with respect to Authority members, alternates, officers, and employees.Title II: Delta Programs - Part A: Programs - Authorizes the Authority to approve grants to States and public and private entities for projects to: (1) assist the region in obtaining necessary job training or employment-related education, leadership and civic development, and business development, especially entrepreneurship for such region; (2) provide special assistance to severely distressed and underdeveloped counties within such region; and (3) fund research, demonstration, evaluations, and assessments of the region. Authorizes the Federal co-chairman of the Authority to use grant amounts as required Federal contributions to grant-in-aid programs for which the region is eligible but cannot supply the required matching share. Prohibits the Federal share of project costs for which assistance is provided under this title from exceeding 80 percent.(Sec.203) Defines a "local development district" as a certified entity having a charter or authority that includes the economic development of counties or other parts of the region. Outlines certification requirements. Authorizes the Authority to make grants to such districts for administrative expenses. (Sec. 204) Requires the Authority to: (1) annually designate distressed and economically strong counties within the region; and (2) allocate at least 50 percent of the appropriations made available under this Act for programs and projects for the distressed counties. Prohibits (with an exception) such funds from being used within economically strong counties.Part B: General Provisions - Requires each State member of the Authority to submit a development plan for the area of that State within the region.(Sec. 222) Outlines factors to be considered by the Authority in considering programs and projects for assistance under this Act and in establishing priorities among assistance requests.(Sec. 223) Requires the Authority to review for approval any State or regional development plan submitted. Outlines plan approval requirements.Title III: Authorizations and Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes appropriations to the Authority to carry out this Act.(Sec. 303) Directs the Authority to: (1) maintain appropriate records; and (2) annually prepare and submit to the President, for transmittal to Congress, a report on its activities.</summary>
</bill>
