<bill session="108" type="h" number="3181" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-21T11:31:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-21T11:31:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Predisaster Mitigation Program Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Predisaster Mitigation Program Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to reauthorize the predisaster mitigation program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400235"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2003-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Consideration and Markup Held Prior to Introduction and Referral (Sep 24, 2003).</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T14:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 108-340.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-04T14:21:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="199">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 199.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21T11:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. LaTourette moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21T11:20:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12126-12129" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21T11:20:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3181.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-11-21T11:31:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12127" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21T11:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2003--Passed House without amendment.
Predisaster Mitigation Program Reauthorization Act of 2003 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to reauthorize through FY 2006 the program of technical and financial assistance to States and local governments for cost-effective predisaster hazard mitigation measures. Increases from 7.5 to 15 percent of the estimated aggregate amount of disaster assistance grants for a particular major disaster the total contributions the President may make to the cost of hazard mitigation measures with respect to such disaster (applicable to any major disaster declared after September 30, 2002). Authorizes the President to provide additional repair assistance to an individual or household that is unable, using insurance proceeds, loans, or other financial assistance, including Small Business Administration assistance, to complete repairs of an owner-occupied private residence, utilities, or residential infrastructure (such as a private access route) damaged by a major disaster declared after enactment of this Act. Amends the Disaster Mitigation Act of 2000 to extend until September 30, 2005, the deadline for completion by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office of a study estimating the reduction in Federal disaster assistance that has resulted and is likely to result from enactment of such Act.</summary>
</bill>
