<bill session="106" type="hc" number="102" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-03">PASSED:CONCURRENTRES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Celebrating the 50th anniversary of the Geneva Conventions of 1949 and recognizing the humanitarian safeguards these treaties provide in times of armed conflict.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400206"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-10-26T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-26T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10800-10804, H10833" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-26T13:15:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 102.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-26T13:42:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-26T16:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-10-26T16:56:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="539" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 423 - 0 (Roll no. 539).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-10-26T16:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-03">
      <text>Senate Committee on Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13861" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:CONCURRENTRES" datetime="1999-11-03" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="sc" number="31"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Prisoners of war"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1999--Introduced.
Recognizes the significance of the Geneva Conventions of 1949 and celebrates the 50th anniversary of the signing of these treaties. Exhorts combatants everywhere to respect the red cross emblem by protecting innocent and vulnerable populations on every side of conflicts. Commends the International Committee of the Red Cross and the more than 175 national Red Cross and Red Crescent societies, including the American Red Cross: (1) on their continuing work in providing relief and assistance to the victims of war; and (2) for their work in educating the world's citizens about the humanitarian principles of international humanitarian law. Applauds the Promise of Humanity gathering organized by the American Red Cross in 1999 in Washington, D.C., as an important reminder of our responsibilities to educate future generations about the principles of international humanitarian law. Invites the American Red Cross during this anniversary year to assist Congress in educating its members and staff about these Conventions. Supports the anniversary theme of the International Committee that "Even War Has Limits." Calls upon the President to issue a proclamation recognizing such anniversary of these Conventions.</summary>
</bill>
