<bill session="105" type="h" number="829" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to prohibit executive agencies from awarding contracts that contain a provision allowing for the acquisition by the contractor, at Government expense, of certain equipment or facilities to carry out the contract, if the principal purpose of such provision is to increase competition by establishing an alternative source of supply for property or services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400301"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="354"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1997--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to prohibit executive agencies, in procuring property or services, from awarding a contract containing a provision allowing for the contractor to acquire, at Government expense, production, construction, or technical equipment or facilities to carry out the contract, if the principal purpose of such provision is to increase competition by establishing an alternative source of supply for property or services.</summary>
</bill>
