<bill session="106" type="h" number="2239" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Crop Insurance Equalization Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to improve crop insurance coverage and administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300021"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400026" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400044" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400522" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400127" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400194" joined="1999-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400221" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400530" joined="1999-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="1999-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1999-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1293"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-06-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Agriculture"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG28" subcommittee="Risk Management, Research and Specialty Crops" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural cooperatives"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices"/>
    <term name="Agricultural production"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Federal Crop Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Crop Insurance Coverage Title II: Administration Crop Insurance Equalization Act of 1999 - Title I: Crop Insurance Coverage - Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to provide that the Commodity Credit Corporation, with respect to prevented planting crop insurance, shall: (1) offer such coverage as an option to a crop insurance policy; (2) provide equal coverage levels for all covered commodities; and (3) permit (noninsurable) substitute plantings.(Sec. 102) Directs the Corporation to develop alternative rates and methodologies for rating insurance plans, which shall take into account nonparticipating producers and producers participating only in catastrophic risk protection. Grants priority to commodities with the largest acreage and the lowest percentage of participating producers.(Sec. 103) Directs the Corporation to: (1) offer optional quality adjustment policies; and (2) establish a low-risk producer pilot program.(Sec. 105) Increases catastrophic risk coverage. Revises related loss adjustment fee provisions.(Sec. 107) Establishes a projected-cost price level (expected market price) for production insurance plans.(Sec. 108) Directs the Corporation to provide premium discounts for qualifying risk-reducing production practices.(Sec. 109) Provides 50 percent premium subsidies for additional coverage and catastrophic risk protection (with 100 percent and 75 percent coverage for crop years 2000 and 2001, respectively).(Sec. 112) Directs the Corporation, for production history calculation purposes, to assign a producer a commodity yield equal to 85 percent of the county's transition yield for a year in which disasters have reduced yield to below such level.(Sec. 113) Prohibits the Corporation from subsidizing a plan that offers coverage for losses based on change of price.(Sec. 114) Limits underwriting gains to 50 percent of the policy.(Sec. 115) Amends the Agricultural Market Transition Act to include certain isolated producers in the noninsured crop assistance program. Revises provisions regarding: (1) area and individual loss thresholds; (2) market price-based payments; and (3) income eligibility.Title II: Administration - Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to revise the membership of the Corporation's Board of Directors.(Sec. 202) Amends the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to place the Office of Risk Management under the Board.(Sec. 203) Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish an Office of Private Sector Partnership to provide specified Board-private sector liaison functions.(Sec. 204) Increases monetary penalties for intentionally providing false insurance information. Authorizes disbarment from Department of Agriculture programs for such violations.(Sec. 206) Directs the Corporation to establish a crop insurance compliance monitoring program.(Sec. 207) Authorizes a cooperative association acting as an insurance agent to provide its members with funds received from the Corporation.(Sec. 208) Prohibits purchasing insurance for more than one crop per year on the same acreage unless the producer or the acreage has a previous history of double-cropping.(Sec. 209) Provides for State consultation.(Sec. 211) Authorizes specified insurance plan fees.(Sec. 212) Directs the Corporation to carry out a flexible subsidy pilot program to encourage private sector innovation through exclusive marketing rights and premium rate competition.</summary>
</bill>
