<bill session="104" type="h" number="2206" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Health Centers Consolidation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the consolidation and simplification of health center programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1995-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1650-1651"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Homeless children"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1995--Introduced.
Health Centers Consolidation Act of 1995 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to replace the definition of "community health center" with provisions defining "health center" to mean an entity that provides to a medically underserved population primary health services and, as appropriate, additional health services. Lists required primary and permissible additional services. Authorizes grants to plan, develop, and operate health centers that will serve medically underserved populations, and grants regarding infant mortality and childhood morbidity, for: (1) migratory and seasonal agricultural workers and their families; (2) homeless individuals, including children at risk of homelessness, requiring grant recipients, in addition to providing primary health services, to provide substance abuse services; and (3) residents of public housing. Relocates (in each case to provisions relating to health centers (currently, community health centers)) provisions relating to: (1) environmental health hazards to migratory and seasonal agricultural workers; (2) definitions relating to such workers; (3) definitions relating to homeless individuals and to substance abuse; and (4) consultation with residents of public housing by grant recipients. Declares that provisions requiring health centers to serve all residents in a catchment area do not apply to grants authorized by this Act. Revises requirements regarding the handling of certain grant overpayments. Requires community centers to have an overall plan and budget meeting requirements of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (currently, requirements of specified provisions of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act). Removes requirements that: (1) the Secretary provide each grant recipient a list of resources to improve the environmental and nutritional status of individuals in the recipient's catchment area; and (2) each grant recipient have an annual financial audit. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary to reserve a specified percentage of amounts appropriated for supplemental awards to grantees demonstrating high or improved performance. Regulates the percentages of amounts awarded to various grants. Repeals from the Public Health Service Act provisions not relocated by this Act relating to migrant health centers, health services for the homeless, and health services for residents of public housing.</summary>
</bill>
