<bill session="105" type="h" number="2259" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">King Cove Health and Safety Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">King Cove Health and Safety Act of 1997</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a transfer of land interests in order to facilitate surface transportation between the cities of Cold Bay, Alaska, and King Cove, Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1509"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-10-01">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-11-08T18:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 105-398.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-11-08T18:52:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="232">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 232.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/1997--Introduced.
King Cove Health and Safety Act of 1997 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to grant the Aleutians East Borough a perpetual right-of- way of 100 feet in width through specified land in Seward Meridian, Alaska, for the construction, operation, and maintenance of certain utility-related fixtures and of a public road between the cities of Cold Bay and King Cove, Alaska, if the King Cove Corporation transfers specified lands to the United States within six months after enactment of this Act. Requires the lands transferred to the United States to be managed in accordance with the Alaska National Lands Conservation Act. Deems such transferred land interests to be of equal value. Directs the Secretary of the Interior and the Aleutians East Borough to jointly develop and agree to reasonable terms and conditions for the use of such right of way which will protect the Federal lands, interest in lands, and resources beneath and adjacent to the right-of-way without imposing undue costs on either party.</summary>
</bill>
