<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1028" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:33-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="2830" sequence="6"/>
  <status datetime="2008-04-24T12:35:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor id="412250"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  <description>Amendment struck section 708 of the substitute amendment (maritime biometric identification) and replaced it with a requirement that the Commandant of the Coast Guard, within one year of enactment, conduct a program for the mobile biometric identification of suspected individuals, including terrorists, to enhance border security. It also required a cost analysis of expanding these capabilities to other Coast Guard and DHS vessels. The analysis may include a plan to give priority to vessels and units more likely to encounter those suspected of making illegal border crossings through the maritime environment.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 6 printed in Part B of House Report 110-604 to strike section 708 of the substitute amendment (maritime biometric identification) and replace it with a requirement that the Commandant of the Coast Guard, within one year of enactment, conduct a program for the mobile biometric identification of suspected individuals, including terrorists, to enhance border security. It also would require a cost analysis of expanding these capabilities to other Coast Guard and DHS vessels. The analysis may include a plan to give priority to vessels and units more likely to encounter those suspected of making illegal border crossings through the maritime environment.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24T12:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Bilirakis.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2719-2720" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2719" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2008-04-24T12:35:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bilirakis amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
</amendment>
