<bill session="107" type="h" number="2538" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-05T12:09:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-12-05T12:09:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Native American Small Business Development Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Native American Small Business Development Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Native American Small Business Development Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to expand and improve the assistance provided by Small Business Development Centers to Indian tribe members, Native Alaskans, and Native Hawaiians.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To amend the Small Business Act to expand and improve the assistance provided by Small Business Development Centers to Indian tribe members, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400011" joined="2001-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400066" joined="2001-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400073" joined="2001-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2001-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2001-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="2001-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2001-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-21T17:48:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Small Business. H. Rept. 107-211.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-09-21T17:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="126">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 126.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05T11:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Manzullo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05T11:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8856-8860" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05T11:52:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2538.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-12-05T12:09:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8856-8857" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05T12:09:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-05T12:09:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Joint hearings held with Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2335"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/5/2001--Passed House amended.
Native American Small Business Development Act - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize a Small Business Development Center in an eligible State to apply for an additional Small Business Administration grant to be used solely to provide specified services to assist with outreach, development, and enhancement on Indian lands of small business startups and expansions that are owned by Indian tribe members, Alaska Natives, or Native Hawaiians (members and Natives) and that are located in Alaska or Hawaii, or on Indian lands in the 48 contiguous States. Defines an eligible State as one in which such members, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians comprise at least one percent of its population. Limits each recipient to $300,000 in such grants in a fiscal year. Authorizes appropriations.Requires a State receiving a small business development center program grant to request the advice of the governing bodies of Indian tribes, corporations organized pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act and other Alaska Native entities, and Native Hawaiian organizations, as appropriate, on how best to provide assistance to such members, Alaska Natives, and Native Hawaiians and where to locate satellite centers to provide such assistance.</summary>
</bill>
