<bill session="107" type="h" number="2386" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Outfitter Policy Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Outfitter Policy Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish terms and conditions for use of certain Federal lands by outfitters and to facilitate public opportunities for the recreational use and enjoyment of such lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400059" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400088" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400116" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400172" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400305" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400317" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400319" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400330" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400335" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400376" joined="2001-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="2001-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-28">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1264"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
      <committee name="House Agriculture"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Joint Hearings held by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands, by the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health, and by the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Joint Hearings held by the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health, by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands, and by the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-07-25">
      <text>Joint Hearings held by the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans, by the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health, and by the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15T15:15:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 107-752, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Oct. 15, 2002.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-15T15:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2002-10-15T15:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="472">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 472.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII20" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSII13" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="House Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG22" subcommittee="Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition, and Forestry" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/2002--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Outfitter Policy Act of 2001- (Sec. 6) Prohibits unauthorized outfitters from conducting commercial outfitted activities on Federal land.Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service (with respect to Federal land administered by the Forest Service), and the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Commissioner of Reclamation (with respect to Federal land administered by the BLM, Fish and Wildlife Service, or Bureau of Reclamation, respectively), to establish criteria for granting outfitter permits, including the recognition of skill, experience, knowledge of the resource area, and financial capability of the person under consideration.Sets forth procedures for granting permits and describes permit requirements. Provides for a noncompetitive selection process and temporary outfitter authorizations under certain conditions.(Sec. 7) Requires fees for outfitter authorizations.(Sec. 8) Requires authorized outfitters to defend and indemnify the United States for costs or expenses associated with injury, death, or damage to any person or property caused by negligence or wanton disregard for persons or property arising out of an outfitter's activities. Makes authorized outfitters liable to the United States for costs and expenses associated with damage to U.S. property caused by negligence or wanton disregard for persons or property arising directly from such activities.Permits authorized outfitters to enter into agreements with outfitted visitors including those for assumption or allocation of risk and release or waiver related to dangerous activities if the agreement runs in favor of the United States.(Sec. 9) Requires outfitter permits to include a principal allocation of outfitter use and authorizes temporary permits to include such allocation as well.Authorizes the Secretary to adjust an allocation of use assigned to an authorized outfitter to reflect material change arising from approval of an amendment in the resource management plan for the area of operation or requirements arising under other law.Permits temporary allocations of use for a period of up to two years and the renewal, transfer, or extension of such allocations at the Secretary's discretion.(Sec. 10) Requires the Secretary to develop a process for annual evaluation of the performance of authorized outfitters.(Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary to renew an authorization at the outfitter's request if the outfitter has received no more than one unsatisfactory annual performance rating during the permit term. Authorizes revocation of a permit only if the outfitter: (1) fails to correct conditions that are considered significant; (2) is in arrears in the payment of fees and has not entered into a payment plan or sought relief; or (3) demonstrates disregard for the health and welfare of visitors or conservation of resources on which the outfitted activities are conducted. Permits suspension of all or part of a permit subject to such findings.(Sec. 12) Makes outfitter permits transferable to qualified transferees under specified conditions. Deems a transfer approved if the Secretary fails to confer approval or disapproval within a prescribed time frame (unless the transferee requests a modification of the authorization that requires environmental analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969).(Sec. 13) Sets forth recordkeeping requirements for authorized outfitters.(Sec. 14) Requires the Secretary to: (1) grant authorized outfitters full access to administrative remedies; and (2) establish an expedited procedure for consideration of appeals of Federal agency decisions to deny, suspend, fail to renew, or revoke a permit or change a principal allocation of outfitter use. Allows authorized outfitters adversely affected by a decision of the Secretary under this Act to commence civil actions.(Sec. 18) Entitles outfitters that hold existing permits, contracts, or other authorizations to issuance of permits under this Act if their recent performance was determined good, satisfactory, or acceptable, or the equivalent.</summary>
</bill>
