<bill session="108" type="hr" number="332" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to apply the layover requirements for conference reports during the last six days of a session of Congress, to require that certain matter be included in joint explanatory statements accompanying conference reports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and the House.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Rules"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Technology and the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/2003--Introduced.
Amends rule XXII of the Rules of the House of Representatives (relating to layover requirements for conference reports) to apply such requirements to conference reports during the last six days of a session of Congress, as well as to motions to dispose of Senate amendments reported in disagreement by a conference committee during such six-day period.Amends rule XIII (relating to privileged reports by the Committee on Rules) with respect to the prohibition against calling up a report by the Committee on a rule, joint rule, or the order of business on the same day it is presented to the House. Repeals the exception to such prohibition for a resolution proposing only to waive the requirement of rule XII concerning the availability of conference reports. (Thus applies such prohibition to such resolutions.)Amends rule XXII to make it out of order to consider a conference report to accompany a bill or joint resolution making or continuing appropriations unless: (1) the joint explanatory statement of the managers includes a separate part that clearly sets forth each item of appropriation added by the committee of conference to fund a new program, project, or activity and the program, project, or activity to which it relates; or (2) the chairman of the Committee on Appropriations causes such matter to be printed in the Congressional Record before consideration of the conference report.</summary>
</bill>
