<bill session="106" type="h" number="391" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-02-11T13:57:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-02-11T13:57:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Small Business Paperwork Reduction bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Paperwork Reduction Act Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Small Business Paperwork Reduction Act Amendments of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, for the purpose of facilitating compliance by small businesses with certain Federal paperwork requirements, to establish a task force to examine the feasibility of streamlining paperwork requirements applicable to small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-19">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-02-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-02-05T18:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 106-8, Part I. Filed late, pursuant to previous special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-05T18:45:00-05:00">
      <text>House Committee on Small Business Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Feb. 5, 1999.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1999-02-05T18:46:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="7">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 7.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-02-05T18:46:00-05:00">
      <text>Committee on Small Business discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-09T14:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 42 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 391 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T11:06:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 42 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 42.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H595-613" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 391 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 42 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T11:07:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jo Ann Emerson to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T11:08:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T12:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. McIntosh.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T12:28:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole is proceeding with debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Kucinich.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T13:38:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 391.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T13:39:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T13:39:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1999-02-11T13:57:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="20" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 274 - 151 (Roll no. 20).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-02-11T13:57:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-22">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Governmental Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="106" type="hr" number="42"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h6"/>
    <amendment number="h7"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/11/1999--Passed House amended.
Small Business Paperwork Reduction Act Amendments of 1999 - Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to: (1) publish annually in the Federal Register a list of requirements applicable to small business concerns with respect to collection of information by agencies (requiring the first such publication within one year after enactment of this Act); and (2) make such list available on the Internet (again within one year after enactment). Requires each Federal agency, with respect to the collection of information and the control of paperwork, to establish one agency point of contact to act as a liaison with small businesses. Requires each such agency, in the case of a first-time information collection violation by a small business, to impose no civil fine on such business unless: (1) the head of the agency determines that the violation has the potential to cause serious harm to the public, or that failure to impose a fine would impede the detection of criminal activity, or presents a danger to public health or safety; or (2) the violation concerns the collection of a tax or is not corrected within six months after violation notification. Authorizes each agency, if a violation presents a danger to public health or safety, to impose no civil fine if the violation is corrected within 24 hours after violation notification, taking into account specified factors. Prohibits a State from imposing a civil penalty on a small business for a first-time violation of Federal information collection requirements in a manner inconsistent with this Act. Requires each agency to make efforts to further reduce the paperwork burden for small businesses with fewer than 25 employees. Establishes a task force to study and report to specified congressional committee members on the feasibility of streamlining requirements with respect to small businesses regarding the collection of information.</summary>
</bill>
