<bill session="107" type="h" number="2590" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-11-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2002, Treasury, Postal Service</title>
    <title type="popular">Postal Service FY2002 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Executive Office Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Postal Service Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">Treasury Department Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Executive Office Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Postal Service Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="reported to house" partial="1" type="short">Treasury Department Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Executive Office Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Postal Service Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed house" partial="1" type="short">Treasury Department Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">9/11 Heroes Stamp Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Breast Cancer Research Stamp Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Executive Office Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Postal Service Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="passed senate" partial="1" type="short">Treasury Department Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" type="short">Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">9/11 Heroes Stamp Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Breast Cancer Research Stamp Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Executive Office Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Postal Service Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Stamp Out Domestic Violence Act of 2001</title>
    <title as="enacted" partial="1" type="short">Treasury Department Appropriations Act, 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Treasury Department, the United States Postal Service, the Executive Office of the President, and certain Independent Agencies, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400197"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2001-07-23T18:58:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-152, by Mr. Istook.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-07-23T18:58:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="88">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 88.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-07-24T21:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 206 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2590 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T11:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 206 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T11:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 206.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4553-4594" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR  H4563-4566" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H4568" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H4568-4570" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H4571-4573" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref=" CR   H4573-4574" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref=" CR H4574-4577" label="text of Title VI as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T11:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2590 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 206 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable David Dreier to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T11:30:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2590.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T12:35:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - UNLESS OTHERWISE SPECIFIED, THE COMMITTEE OF THE WHOLE WILL PROCEED WITH DEBATE ON AMENDMENTS UNDER THE FIVE-MINUTE RULE.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Obey moved to strike the enacting clause.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T13:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Obey preferential motion to strike the enacting clause.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T14:00:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to strike the enacting clause Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T14:01:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole continued with debate on the Inslee amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T14:20:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Inslee amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Istook demanded a recorded vote pending the absence of a quorum and under the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T14:34:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Hinchey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hinchey demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T15:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2590 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T15:22:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Istook asked unanimous consent that, during further consideration of the amendments numbered 5, 7, and 8 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to H. Res. 206: (1) amendment No.7 shall immediately follow amendment No. 5; (2) amendment No. 5 shall be subject only to the amendment offered by Mr. Flake; (3) amendment No. 7 shall be subject only to one substantive amendment; (4) amendments Nos. 5 and 7 shall each be debatable for 20 minutes; and (5) debate on amendment No. 8 shall be for one hour. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4594-4610" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, debate on the Wynn amendment was limited to 10 minutes, equally divided and controlled.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T16:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Smith (NJ).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T16:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the substitute amendment offered by Mr. Flake.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T17:18:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTES POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the underlying Smith of New Jersey amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T17:20:00-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the previous order of the House, the Committee proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the amendment offered by Mr. Rangel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T17:45:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Rangel amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rangel demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T17:45:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T18:20:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee is debating the amendment offered by Mr. Traficant.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T18:33:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Traficant amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Traficant demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2590 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Istook asked unanimous consent that, during consideration of H.R. 2590 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to H. Res. 206, no further amendment to the bill may be offered except: (1) pro forma amendments offered by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations; (2) the amendment numbered 8, debatable for 30 minutes; (3) the amendment offered by Mr. Filner, debatable for 30 minutes. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T18:37:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4610-4622" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T18:38:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Hastings (FL) amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the Filner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T20:03:00-04:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Filner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Filner demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T20:03:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T20:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2590.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T20:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T20:40:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-07-25T20:57:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="274" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 334 - 94 (Roll no. 274).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-07-25T20:57:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-19">
      <text>Senate Committee on Appropriations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9470-9477, S9485-9486, S9489-9490, S9491-9497" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2001-09-19" how="by Voice Vote" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/21/2001 S9661-9673" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-09-19">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Dorgan, Mikulski, Landrieu, Reed, Byrd, Campbell, Shelby, DeWine and Stevens.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-09-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-05T09:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Istook asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-05T09:04:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6383" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-05T09:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-05T09:04:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Istook, Wolf, Northup, Sununu, Peterson (PA), Tiahrt, Sweeney, Sherwood, Young (FL), Hoyer, Meek (FL), Price (NC), Rothman, Visclosky, and Obey.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-25T11:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Wolf asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on Oct. 26 to file a conference report on H.R. 2590. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-25">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-26T13:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 107-253 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/29/2001 H7337-7356" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31T10:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Istook brought up conference report H. Rept. 107-253 by previously agreed to special order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31T10:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31T11:25:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31T11:25:00-05:00">
      <text>VOTE POSTPONED - Pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed the requirement for the Yeas and Nays on the question of adoption of the conference report until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31T16:53:00-05:00">
      <text>The House proceeded to consider the conference report H.Rept. 107-253 as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7536-7545, H7557-7558" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE" datetime="2001-10-31T17:19:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="413" type="conference" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 339 - 85 (Roll no. 413).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31T17:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-31">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-01">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-11-01">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11329-11333,  S11344-11345" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:BILL" datetime="2001-11-01" how="roll" result="pass" roll="321" type="conference" where="s">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 83 - 15. Record Vote Number: 321.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="2001-11-01">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="2001-11-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2001-11-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2001-11-12">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted state="ENACTED:SIGNED" datetime="2001-11-12" type="public" number="107-67">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 107-67.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="206"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1398"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Alien property"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Alternative fuels"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arson"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Breast feeding"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Cambodians"/>
    <term name="Cancer research"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child support enforcement"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Chinese"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Committee for Purchase from People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cubans"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Dairy industry"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and government employees"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Earned income tax credit"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic forecasting"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Estonia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Expert witnesses"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal Labor Relations Authority"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Former Soviet states"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government employees' life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government internships"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Heat pumps"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Human behavior"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Income statistics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Laotians"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Latvians"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Management information systems"/>
    <term name="Mandatory retirement"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Marketing orders"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Office buildings"/>
    <term name="Office of Government Ethics"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Office of Special Counsel"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police dogs"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Postage stamps"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Postal facilities"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential compensation"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Psychology"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religion in the workplace"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Savings bonds"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School buses"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Sexual harassment"/>
    <term name="Sheltered workshops"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stress (Psychology)"/>
    <term name="Student housing"/>
    <term name="Student transportation"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax consultants"/>
    <term name="Tax courts"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Vietnamese"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="White House (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="White collar crime"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h230"/>
    <amendment number="h231"/>
    <amendment number="h232"/>
    <amendment number="h233"/>
    <amendment number="h234"/>
    <amendment number="h235"/>
    <amendment number="h236"/>
    <amendment number="h237"/>
    <amendment number="h238"/>
    <amendment number="h239"/>
    <amendment number="h240"/>
    <amendment number="h241"/>
    <amendment number="h242"/>
    <amendment number="h243"/>
    <amendment number="h244"/>
    <amendment number="h245"/>
    <amendment number="s1570"/>
    <amendment number="s1571"/>
    <amendment number="s1572"/>
    <amendment number="s1573"/>
    <amendment number="s1574"/>
    <amendment number="s1575"/>
    <amendment number="s1576"/>
    <amendment number="s1577"/>
    <amendment number="s1578"/>
    <amendment number="s1579"/>
    <amendment number="s1583"/>
    <amendment number="s1584"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/26/2001--Conference report filed in House.
Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2002 - Makes appropriations for FY 2002 for the Treasury Department, the U.S. Postal Service, the Executive Office of the President, and certain independent agencies.Title I: Department of the Treasury - Treasury Department Appropriations Act, 2002 - Makes appropriations to the Department of the Treasury for FY 2002 for: (1) departmental offices; (2) department-wide systems and capital investments programs for development and acquisition of automatic data processing equipment, software, and services; (3) the Office of Inspector General; (4) Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration; (5) repair, alteration, and improvement of the Treasury building and annex; (6) programs to expand access to financial services for low- and moderate-income individuals; (7) the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network; (8) counterterrorism measures; (9) the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, including amounts for acquisitions, maintenance, and facility improvements; (10) interagency crime and drug enforcement; (11) the Financial Management Service; (12) the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms; (13) the U.S. Customs Service, including amounts for collection of the Harbor Maintenance Fee, operation and maintenance of marine vessels and aircraft, and automation modernization; (14) the Bureau of the Public Debt; (15) the Internal Revenue Service, including amounts for tax law enforcement, the earned income tax credit compliance and error reduction initiatives, information systems and telecommunications support, and the capital asset acquisition of information technology systems; and (16) the U.S. Secret Service. Sets the aggregate amount of new liabilities and obligations incurred during FY 2002 for circulating coinage and protective service capital investments of the United States Mint. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to reimburse the Comptroller General from amounts in the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund for the cost of a study on changes necessary to maximize public interest and acceptance and to achieve a better balance in the numbers of coins of different denominations in circulation, with particular attention to increasing the number of $1 coins in circulation.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, such funds.(Sec. 120) Amends the Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 1998 to extend for an additional year the period for a personnel management demonstration project for designated critical positions in the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms.(Sec. 121) Prohibits funds made available by this Act from being used: (1) by the United States Mint to construct or operate any museum without the explicit approval of specified congressional committees; or (2) for the production of Customs Declarations that do not inquire whether the passenger had been in the proximity of livestock.(Sec. 123) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer, subject to a specified limit, such sums as are necessary to meet financial statement audit requirements of the United States Customs Service and the Financial Management Service.Title II: Postal Service - Postal Service Appropriations Act, 2002 - Makes FY 2002 appropriations for payments to the Postal Service Fund for revenue foregone on free and reduced rate mail.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, such funds.Title III: Executive Office of the President and Funds Appropriated to the President - Executive Office Appropriations Act, 2002 - Makes FY 2002 appropriations for: (1) the Executive Office of the President, including compensation of the President; (2) expenses of the Executive Residence at the White House; (3) expenses of the Vice President; (4) the Council of Economic Advisers; (5) the Office of Policy Development; (6) the National Security Council; (7) the Office of Administration; (8) the Office of Management and Budget (OMB); (9) the Office of National Drug Control Policy, including amounts for the Counterdrug Technology Assessment Center; and (10) Federal drug control programs, including amounts for the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas (HIDTA) Program and for a national anti-drug campaign for youth.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, such funds.Title IV: Independent Agencies - Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002 - Makes FY 2002 appropriations for: (1) the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled; (2) the Federal Election Commission; (3) the Federal Labor Relations Authority; (4) the General Services Administration (GSA), including amounts for the Federal Buildings Fund, Government-wide policy and operations, the Office of Inspector General, the Electronic Government Fund, and allowances and office staff for former Presidents; (5) the Merit Systems Protection Board; (6) the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation; (7) the Environmental Dispute Resolution Fund to carry out activities authorized in the Environmental Policy and Conflict Resolution Act of 1998; (8) the National Archives and Records Administration, including an amount for repairs and restoration of archives; (9) the National Historical Publications and Records Commission; (10) the Office of Government Ethics; (11) the Office of Personnel Management, including an amount for the Office of Inspector General; (12) Government contributions for health and life insurance benefits for annuitants; (13) the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund; (14) the Office of Special Counsel; and (15) the U.S. Tax Court.(Sec. 408) Requires GSA to: (1) increase by at least $5 million for FY 2002 (over FY 2001 amounts) the amount expended for the purchase of alternative fuel vehicles; and (2) maintain rental and per mile rates for buses used by schools and dormitories funded by the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) that were in effect on April 30, 2001, until appropriations for BIA funding of the Student Transportation Program for such purposes equals or exceeds three dollars per mile.(Sec. 410) Designates the Federal building and courthouse located at 100 1st Street, SW, Minot, North Dakota, as the Judge Bruce M. Van Sickle Federal Building and United States Courthouse.(Sec. 411) Revises conditions for construction of a road in Luna County, New Mexico.(Sec. 412) Directs the U.S. Government to deed a specified area of the LOCH HAVEN REPLAT, back to the city of Orlando, Florida, in accordance with specified requirements.(Sec. 413) Designates the Federal building and courthouse located at 315 S. McDuffie Street, Anderson, South Carolina, as the G. Ross Anderson, Jr. Federal Building and United States Courthouse.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, such funds.Title V: General Provisions (This Act) - Sets forth authorized and prohibited uses of funds made available under this Act.(Sec. 506) Sets forth Buy American provisions, including those providing that in the case of any equipment or products that may be authorized to be purchased with financial assistance provided by this Act, it is the sense of Congress that entities receiving such assistance should, in expending it, purchase only American-made equipment and products.(Sec. 509) Prohibits funds appropriated by this Act from being available for an abortion or the administrative expenses of any Federal employee health plan which provides benefits for abortions. Makes such prohibition inapplicable if the mother's life would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term or in cases of rape or incest.(Sec. 512) Prohibits funds made available in this Act from being used by the Executive Office of the President to request from the Federal Bureau of Investigation any official background investigation report on any individual except when: (1) such individual has given his or her express written consent for such a request not more than six months prior to the date of such request and during the same presidential administration; and (2) such request is required due to extraordinary circumstances involving national security.(Sec. 513) Exempts contracts under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program from standards promulgated under the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act by the Cost Accounting Standards Board.Title VI: General Provisions (Departments, Agencies, and Corporations) - Sets forth authorized and prohibited uses of funds appropriated for Federal departments, agencies, and corporations.(Sec. 619) Bars the use of funds made available for the Customs Service in this Act to allow the importation of any good produced or manufactured by forced or indentured child labor or the release of any good subject to a detention order on the basis that it may have been so produced.(Sec. 621) Prohibits funds made available in this or any other Act from being obligated or expended for any employee training that: (1) does not meet identified needs for knowledge, skills, and abilities bearing directly upon the performance of official duties; (2) contains elements likely to induce high levels of emotional response or psychological stress in some participants; (3) does not require prior employee notification of the content and methods to be used in the training and written end of course evaluation; (4) contains any methods or content associated with religious or quasi-religious belief systems or "new age" belief systems; or (5) is offensive to, or designed to change, participants' personal values or lifestyle outside the workplace.(Sec. 630) Authorizes the use of appropriated funds by executive agencies to provide child care services for Federal civilian employees.(Sec. 631) Permits a woman to breastfeed her child at any location in a Federal building or on Federal property if the woman and her child are otherwise authorized to be present at this location.(Sec. 632) Makes funds available for interagency funding of efforts to carry out the purposes of the National Science and Technology Council which benefit multiple Federal entities.(Sec. 634) Amends the Government Management Reform Act of 1994 to extend franchise fund pilot programs.(Sec. 635) Amends Federal law to: (1) require the Department of the Navy to provide and pay for utilities for the official residence of the Vice President without reimbursement; and (2) authorize the Secretary of the Navy to accept gifts of consumable items, or funds for them, to be accepted for use at official functions at the Vice President's residence.(Sec. 638) Requires each executive agency covered by telecommuting provisions of the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 1999 to report to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) 60 days after the close of FY 2001 concerning its efforts to implement the intent of such provisions.(Sec. 639) Prohibits funds made available in this or any other Act from being used by any Federal agency to do the following with specified exceptions: (1) collect, review, or create any aggregate list, derived from any means, that includes the collection of any personally identifiable information relating to an individual's access to or use of any Federal Government Internet site of the agency; or (2) enter into any agreement with a third party to collect, review, or obtain any aggregate list, derived from any means, that includes the collection of any personally identifiable information relating to an individual's access to or use of any nongovernmental Internet site.(Sec. 640) Revises requirements for mandatory separation of air traffic controllers to extend the deadline for such separation to the date of completion of age and service requirements for an annuity under immediate retirement provisions.(Sec. 641) Requires agencies to annually submit recommendations to OPM for awarding of ranks recognizing accomplishment to individuals serving in certain senior career positions classified above GS-15.(Sec. 643) Bars funds appropriated by this Act from being used to enter into or renew a contract which provides for prescription drug coverage, except where the contract also includes a provision for contraceptive coverage. Provides that nothing in this section shall apply to a contract with any of two specified religious plans and any existing or future plan whose carrier objects to such coverage on the basis of religious beliefs.(Sec. 644) Recognizes the United States Anti-Doping Agency as the official anti-doping agency for Olympic, Pan American, and Paralympic sport in the United States.(Sec. 645) Amends the Floyd D. Spence National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2001 (Spence Act) to deem the Executive Director and employees of the United States-China Security Review Commission to be Federal employees for purposes of leave and insurance and annuities.(Sec. 646) Mandates a 4.6 percent increase in rates of basic pay for the statutory pay systems in FY 2002 with respect to pay schedules and locality-based comparability payments under Federal civil service law. States that such increase shall be paid from appropriations made to each applicable department or agency for salaries and expenses for FY 2002.(Sec. 647) Directs each agency Inspector General to report to the Committee on Appropriations (sic) on policies and procedures in place to give first priority to the location of new offices and facilities in rural areas.(Sec. 648) Amends the Spence Act to extend the deadline for submission of annual reports to Congress by the United States-China Security Review Commission.(Sec. 650) Breast Cancer Research Stamp Act of 2001 - Amends Federal postal law to reauthorize the issuance of the breast cancer research postage stamp at a special rate of postage.(Sec. 651) Amends Federal law to authorize the U.S. Postal Service, in the exercise of its authority to contract with an air carrier for the transportation of mail by aircraft, to require an air carrier to accept as mail any shipments of day-old poultry and such other live animals as postal regulations allow to be transmitted as mail matter. Authorizes the U.S. Postal Service to assess a reasonable surcharge as postage to compensate air carriers for any additional expense incurred in handling such shipments.(Sec. 652) 9/11 Heroes Stamp Act of 2001 - Directs the U.S. Postal Service to issue a semipostal at a specified postage rate in order to provide assistance to the families of emergency relief personnel killed or permanently disabled in the line of duty in connection with the terrorist attacks against the United States on September 11, 2001. Requires transfer of all proceeds to the Federal Emergency Management Agency under arrangements with the Postal Service.Expresses the sense of Congress that such stamp should depict the efforts of emergency relief personnel at the site of the World Trade Center in New York City and the Pentagon in Arlington, Virginia.(Sec. 653) Stamp Out Domestic Violence Act of 2001 - Directs the U.S. Postal Service to issue a semipostal in order to provide funding for domestic violence programs. Requires transfer of all proceeds to the Department of Health and Human Services under arrangements with the Postal Service.</summary>
</bill>
