<bill session="106" type="h" number="4066" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Act for the Effective National Firearms Objectives for Responsible Common-sense Enforcement of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" partial="1" type="short">ENFORCE Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To enhance the enforcement of gun violence laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400001" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400007" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400008" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400021" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400518" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="2000-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400047" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2000-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400090" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400101" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400102" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="2000-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2000-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400181" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400198" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400215" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="2000-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400246" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400251" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2000-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="2000-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="2000-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400269" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2000-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400275" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400554" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400282" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="2000-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400290" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2000-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400310" joined="2000-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2000-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="2000-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400528" joined="2000-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400346" joined="2000-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2000-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="2000-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400360" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400366" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="2000-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2000-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400416" joined="2000-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2000-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400426" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="2000-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2000-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug dealers"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Pardons"/>
    <term name="Product development"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
    <term name="Youth violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: The Criminal Gun Trafficker Apprehension Act of 2000 Title II: The Criminal Gun Dealer Detection Act of 2000 Title III: The Violent Felon Gun Ban Enforcement Act of 2000 Title IV: The Intensive Gun Violence Reduction Strategy and Project Exile Implementation Act of 2000 Subtitle A: Funding Provisions Subtitle B: Ballistics Testing Act for Effective National Firearms Objectives for Responsible, Common-sense Enforcement of 2000 (ENFORCE Act) - Title I: The Criminal Gun Trafficker Apprehension Act of 2000 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (the Act) to provide that it shall be presumed that the intent underlying the sale or disposition of a firearm is predominantly one of obtaining livelihood and pecuniary gain if a person transfers more than 50 firearms in any period of 12 consecutive months, or more than 30 firearms in any period of 30 consecutive days excluding any infrequent transfer of a firearm by gift, bequest, intestate succession, or other means by an individual to a parent, child, grandparent, or grandchild.(Sec. 102) Requires that a firearms licensee, as a condition of obtaining a license to deal in firearms or ammunition (license), operate from a fixed premises primarily devoted to the sale of firearms and conspicuously designated to the public as such, other than a private residence.(Sec. 103) Prohibits a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer from storing firearms on the premises in a manner not in conformity with regulations issued by the Secretary of the Treasury. Directs the Secretary, in issuing such regulations, to take into consideration the type and quantity of the firearms to be stored, as well as the standards of safety and security recognized in the firearms industry. Authorizes the Secretary, after notice and opportunity for hearing, to suspend or revoke a license or to subject the licensee to a civil penalty of up to $10,000 for knowingly violating this prohibition. Limits review of the Secretary's actions.Requires that the firearms inventory of the business be stored in compliance with this Act and regulations issued thereunder within 30 days after the application is approved.(Sec. 104) Prohibits a common or contract carrier from failing to report the theft or loss of a firearm within 48 hours after discovery. Requires that such theft or loss be reported to the Secretary and to the appropriate local authorities. Authorizes the Secretary to impose a civil fine of up to $10,000 for knowingly violating this prohibition.Title II: The Criminal Gun Dealer Detection Act of 2000 - Amends the Act to authorize the Secretary to inspect or examine the records of a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer without reasonable cause or warrant for ensuring compliance with record-keeping requirements not more than four times (currently, once) during any 12-month period, or as otherwise specified in the Act.(Sec. 202) Provides that a personal collection of firearms of a licensed manufacturer, importer, or dealer shall be considered part of the business inventory of the licensee (thus making disposal of such collection subject to regulation), with an exception for the infrequent transfer of a firearm by gift, bequest, intestate succession, or other means from the personal collection of firearms of a licensee to a parent, child, grandparent, or grandchild.(Sec. 203) Revises penalty provisions under the Federal criminal code (the code) to authorize the Secretary to: (1) suspend a license or subject a licensee to a civil penalty of $10,000 per violation (currently, the Secretary's options are limited to license revocation) for violations; and (2) compromise, mitigate, or remit at any time the liability with respect to any willful violation.Title III: The Violent Felon Gun Ban Enforcement Act of 2000 -Denies natural persons the opportunity to seek administrative relief from prohibitions against possessing, shipping, transporting, or receiving firearms or ammunition and requires publication of additional information about such administrative relief granted to any person.(Sec. 302) Prohibits the possession of, or transactions in, firearms by any natural person convicted of a serious drug offense or violent felony, regardless of expungement of the conviction or restoration of other civil rights, subject to specified limitations.Title IV: The Intensive Gun Violence Reduction Strategy and Project Exile Implementation Act of 2000 - Subtitle A: Funding Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for the improvement of the national instant criminal background check system, including improvements to criminal justice records as specified in the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 and to records required by the Attorney General under the Brady Act for the purpose of implementing that Act.(Sec. 402) Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (VCCLEA) to authorize the Attorney General to make grants to State or local law enforcement agencies for the purpose of improving the organization of criminal records, especially records relating to convictions for crimes of domestic violence and to restraining orders relating to domestic violence, and the reporting of such records to the national instant criminal background check system. Sets forth provisions regarding permissible uses of grant funds, application and matching requirements, grant awards, and reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 403) Authorizes appropriations for the hiring of 600 agents and inspectors for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms.(Sec. 404) Amends the VCCLEA to authorize the Attorney General to make grants to State, Indian tribal, or local prosecutors for the purpose of supporting the creation or expansion of community-based justice programs for the prosecution of gun-related crimes. Sets forth provisions regarding permissible uses of grant funds, application and matching requirements, grant awards, and reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 405) Directs the Attorney General to: (1) hire 114 additional Federal prosecutors to prosecute violations of Federal firearms laws; and (2) establish in each of the jurisdictions not more than 20 areas designated by the Attorney General as having high rates of firearm-related crime a gun enforcement team.(Sec. 406) Directs the Secretary to expand: (1) to 50 the number of city and county law enforcement agencies that, through the Youth Crime Gun Interdiction Initiative (YGCII), submit to the Secretary identifying information relating to the types and origins of all firearms recovered during law enforcement investigations, including from individuals under 25; and (2) the resources devoted to law enforcement investigations of illegal youth possessors and users and of illegal firearms traffickers identified through YGCII.Directs the Secretary to: (1) select cities and counties for participation in the program; and (2) establish a system through which State and local law enforcement agencies, through on-line computer technology, can promptly provide firearms-related information to the Secretary and access information derived through YGCII as soon as such capability is available.Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 407) Amends the VCCLEA to authorize the Attorney General to make grants to public or private nonprofit entities for the purpose of supporting the creation or expansion of local anti-gun violence media campaigns. Sets forth provisions regarding permissible uses of funds, and application and matching requirements. Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 408) Directs the Attorney General to carry out a program for the research and development of smart gun technology. Authorizes appropriations.Subtitle B: Ballistics Testing - Prohibits a licensed manufacturer or importer from transferring a firearm to any person before: (1) test firing the firearm; (2) preparing forensic ballistics records of the fired bullet and cartridge casings; and (3) making the records available to the Secretary for entry in a computerized database.Authorizes the Secretary, after notice and opportunity for hearing, for each violation by a licensed manufacturer or importer, to suspend the license for up to one year or revoke the license, impose on the licensee a civil fine of not more than $10,000, or both. Limits review of the Secretary's action.Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary to assist firearm manufacturers and importers in complying with this section through: (1) the acquisition, disposition, and upgrades of computerized forensic ballistics equipment and bullet recovery equipment to be placed at the sites of licensed manufacturers and importers or at regional firearm centers established by the Secretary; and (2) the hiring or designation of personnel necessary to develop and maintain a database of forensic ballistics records, research, and evaluation.Requires the Attorney General and the Secretary to establish a system through which State and local law enforcement agencies, through online computer technology, can promptly access forensic ballistics records, as soon as the capability to do so is available. Sets forth reporting requirements.Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary to work cooperatively with representatives of the firearm industry to: (1) provide education about the role of forensic ballistics as part of a comprehensive firearm crime reduction strategy; and (2) provide for coordination among Federal, State, and local law enforcement and regulatory agencies and the firearm industry to curb firearm-related crime and illegal firearm trafficking. Sets forth provisions regarding areas of concentrated efforts and annual reports and evaluation. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary and the Attorney General to conduct mandatory forensic ballistics testing of all firearms that are or have been taken into the custody of, or procured or utilized by, their respective agencies. Authorizes appropriations. Sets forth reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
