<bill session="106" type="h" number="2018" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">International Tax Simplification for American Competitiveness Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify certain rules relating to the taxation of United States business operating abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400206" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1999-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1999-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1164"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Export trading companies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas companies"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Intangible property"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military weapons"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Ordnance"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Treatment of Controlled Foreign Corporations Title II: Provisions Relating to Foreign Tax Credit Title III: Other Provisions International Tax Simplification for American Competitiveness Act of 1999 - Title I: Treatment of Controlled Foreign Corporations - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) with respect to subpart F (Controlled Foreign Corporations) to set forth provisions concerning, among other things: (1) permanently extend the subpart F exemption for active financing income earned on business operation overseas; (2) direct the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct a study on the feasibility of treating all countries included in the European Union as a single country for purposes of applying the same country exceptions under subpart F; (3) provide for the determination of subpart F earnings and profits under generally accepted U.S. accounting principles; (4) exclude from the definition of "foreign base company oil related income" the pipeline transportation of oil or gas within such foreign country; and (5) exclude from the definition of the term "foreign base company services income" income derived in connection with the performance of services which are related to the transmission of high voltage electricity.Title II: Provisions Relating to Foreign Tax Credit - Revises section 904 (Limitation On Credit) of the (IRC) to, among other things: (1) extend the period to which excess foreign taxes may be carried; (2) define overall domestic loss and sets forth provisions for determining taxable income for any taxpayer sustaining such a loss; (3) provide an exception for interest on certain securities; (4) revise provisions concerning the of application of look-thru rules to dividends from noncontrolled section 902 corporations to provide, in general, that any dividend from a noncontrolled section 902 corporation with respect to the taxpayer shall be treated as income in a separate category in proportion to the ratio of the portion of earnings and profits attributable to income in such category to the total amount of earnings and profits; (5) repeal the 90 percent limitation on the utilization of the foreign tax credit; and (6) repeals section 907 (Special Rules In Case of Foreign Oil and Gas Income) of the IRC.Title III: Other Provisions - Applies constructive ownership rules for purposes of determining certain post-1986 undistributed U.S. earnings. Applies capitalization rules to nonresident aliens and foreign corporations. Repeals the special rule for military property with respect to exempt foreign trade income. Revises the definition of U.S. property to exclude certain assets acquired by dealers in the ordinary course of business. Exempts from the taxes on nonresident aliens and foreign corporations certain regulated investment company dividends. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, with respect to the Puerto Rico and possession tax credit, to exclude from the definition of the term "intangible property" any preliminary agreement which is not legally enforceable. Sets forth provisions concerning airline mileage awards to certain foreign persons. Repeals subpart G (Export Trade Corporations) of part III of subchapter N of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code. Prohibits the Secretary from requiring a corporation to report any information with respect to any foreign person which is a related person if the aggregate value of the transactions between the corporation and the related person does not exceed $5 million.</summary>
</bill>
