<bill session="104" type="h" number="2675" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Mom and Pop Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a grant program to install safety devices and improve safety at convenience stores.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-11-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2225"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU09" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grocery trade"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/1995--Introduced.
Mom and Pop Protection Act - Authorizes the Attorney General to provide grants to States to establish a loan program for convenience store owners (owners) to install security devices and improve safety in convenience stores. Directs the State to determine a repayment schedule of not more than five years and an interest rate not to exceed three percent for owners to cover administrative expenses for the State. Requires that, to receive a grant, the chief executive officer (CEO) of a State submit an application that includes an assurance that the State shall develop a process of certification and review to ensure that funds received are used only for the purpose of installing safety devices in convenience stores. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) owner eligibility for loans, including a requirement that a State receiving a grant receive not less than $200,000; and (2) uses of funds (for a video security system capable of 24-hour surveillance, a drop safe or cash management device with restricted access and posters indicating that not more than $50 is accessible to store personnel, a silent alarm system to alert local law enforcement officers, and height markers at store exits). Directs: (1) the Attorney General, by notice in the Federal Register, to terminate the State loan program upon determining that a sufficient number of eligible convenience stores has had the opportunity to apply for a loan from a State; (2) the State to provide notice to owners regarding such termination; and (3) that any funds, excluding the amount of interest collected, that a State receives as repayment from an owner after the date that the Attorney General terminates the State loan program be used by such State for law enforcement purposes. Requires the CEO of a State that receives a grant under this Act to submit an annual report to the Attorney General regarding the number of loans, locations, amounts, terms, and repayment record of convenience stores in such State that receive funds under this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
