<bill session="105" type="h" number="3681" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Small Business Common Sense and Fairness Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to review and adjust the size standards used to determine whether or not enterprises in certain industry categories are small business concerns for the purposes of competing for Federal contracting opportunities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400501"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400010" joined="1998-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1998-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Industrial standards"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/1998--Introduced.
Small Business Common Sense and Fairness Act of 1998 - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to review the size standards of industries with the Standard Industrial Classification Codes of 15, 16, and 17 which were excluded in the 1994 SBA inflationary adjustment and to adjust such standards for inflation for the purpose of deeming an enterprise in any such industry as a small business. Requires the Administrator, at least once every five years, to: (1) review and adjust for inflation such size standard for an enterprise deemed a small business for purposes of competing for Federal contracting opportunities based solely on annual revenues; and (2) report to the Congress and the President on findings and conclusions reached upon such review.</summary>
</bill>
