<bill session="105" type="hr" number="432" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-21T13:18:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-05-21T13:18:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives concerning the President's assertions of executive privilege.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400104"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-14T16:44:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 436 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 432 and H. Res. 433 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Providing for consideration of these resolutions in the House. After disposition of or postponement of further proceedings on H. Res. 432, it shall be in order to consider in the House the resolution H. Res. 433, debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution to final adoption without intervening motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 436.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3640-3646" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T12:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 432 and H. Res. 433 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Providing for consideration of these resolutions in the House. After disposition of or postponement of further proceedings on H. Res. 432, it shall be in order to consider in the House the resolution H. Res. 433, debatable for one hour. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution to final adoption without intervening motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>PERMISSION TO OFFER AN AMENDMENT - Mr. DeLay asked unanimous consent to amend the resolution in the form which he submitted to the desk. Objection was heard.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T12:49:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with debate on the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T12:55:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-05-21T13:18:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="176" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 259 - 157, 6 Present (Roll No. 176).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21T13:18:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hr" number="436"/>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="436"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Clinton Administration"/>
    <term name="Executive privilege"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Presidential records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1998--Introduced.
Declares that, in the interests of full disclosure consistent with principles of openness in governmental operations, all records or documents relating to any claims of executive privilege asserted by the President should be immediately made publicly available.</summary>
</bill>
