<bill session="105" type="hr" number="232" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-06T17:33:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-06T17:33:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Waiving points of order against the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 2160) making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1998, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-255, by Mr. Hastings (WA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-18T18:27:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2160. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The House shall be considered to have adopted the House Concurrent Resolution described in section 3 of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-18T18:27:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="92">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 92.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T17:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8383-8385" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T17:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1997-10-06T17:33:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="490" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 367 - 34 (Roll no. 490).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T17:33:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hc" number="167"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="105" type="hc" number="167"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="105" type="h" number="2160"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/18/1997--Introduced.
Waives points of order against the consideration of the conference report on H.R. 2160 (Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies programs appropriations). Provides that the House shall be considered to have adopted a concurrent resolution barring the use of domestic food program or food stamp program funds under such Act for studies and evaluations.</summary>
</bill>
