<bill session="107" type="h" number="4598" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-06-26T12:36:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-06-26T12:36:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Homeland Security Information Sharing Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Homeland Security Information Sharing Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the sharing of homeland security information by Federal intelligence and law enforcement agencies with State and local entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300021"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400525" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400042" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="2002-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2002-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="2002-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400168" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400173" joined="2002-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400182" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="2002-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400361" joined="2002-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400392" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400407" joined="2002-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2002-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-25">
      <text>Referred to House Intelligence</text>
      <reference ref="Permanent Select"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-04-25">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-06-13">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2002-06-25T19:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 107-534, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-25T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 458 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4598 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Rule provides for general debate, with 40 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committeeon the Judiciary. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. The rule provides that it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill (H. Rept. 107-534 Pt. 1). The rule waives all points of o...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T10:38:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 458 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 458.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3936-3948" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4598 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Rule provides for general debate, with 40 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and 20 minutes equally divided and controlled by the chairman and ranking minority member of the Committeeon the Judiciary. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. The rule provides that it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill (H. Rept. 107-534 Pt. 1). The rule waives all points of o...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 458 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Paul Ryan to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T10:56:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4598.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T12:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T12:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4598.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T12:14:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2002-06-26T12:36:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="258" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 422 - 2 (Roll no. 258).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2002-06-26T12:36:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-06-27">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="107" type="hr" number="458"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Grand jury"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House Intelligence"/>
    <term name="House Judiciary"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Information leaking"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Mayors"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Security clearances"/>
    <term name="Senate Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Senate Judiciary"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h508"/>
    <amendment number="h509"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/25/2002--Reported to House amended.
Homeland Security Information Sharing Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that Federal, State, and local entities should share homeland security information to the maximum extent practicable, with special emphasis on hard-to-reach urban and rural communities.(Sec. 3) Directs the President to prescribe procedures under which Federal agencies determine: (1) how homeland security information may be shared with State and local personnel, how to identify and safeguard information that is sensitive but unclassified, and how to remove classified information (as appropriate); and (2) with which personnel such information may be shared.Requires all appropriate agencies, including the intelligence community, to share homeland security information, along with assessments of its credibility, with State and local personnel through information sharing systems, in accordance with such procedures. Requires such procedures to limit the re-dissemination of shared information to ensure that it is not used for an unauthorized purpose, to ensure the security and confidentiality of such information to protect the rights of covered individuals, to provide data integrity through the timely removal and destruction of obsolete or erroneous names and information, to ensure that the information sharing system used includes existing information sharing systems, and to ensure that appropriate State and local personnel are authorized to use such information sharing systems. Requires that each appropriate Federal agency have access to each information sharing system and the information within it.Directs the President to prescribe procedures under which Federal agencies may share classified homeland security information with State and local personnel, including through non-disclosure agreements and increased use of information sharing partnerships.Provides that information obtained by a State or local government from a Federal agency shall remain under the control of the Federal agency and shall not be subject to a State or local information disclosure law.(Sec. 4) Directs the President to report to congressional intelligence and judiciary committees on Act implementation and recommendations to increase the effectiveness of information sharing.(Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 6) Amends Rule 6 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to permit the sharing of grand jury information that pertains to foreign intelligence or counterintelligence with State or local law enforcement personnel, and with foreign officials, consistent with such guidelines as the Attorney General and the Director of Central Intelligence shall jointly issue.(Sec. 7) Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize the sharing of intercepted electronic, wire, and oral communications or derived information by the government with: (1) foreign investigative or law enforcement officers for the performance of official duties; and (2) Federal, State, local, or foreign government officials if such information reveals a threat of an attack or other hostile act by a foreign power, sabotage, terrorism, or clandestine intelligence gathering activity by a foreign power, for the purpose of preventing or responding to such a threat.(Sec. 8) Amends the Uniting and Strengthening America by Providing Appropriate Tools Required to Intercept and Obstruct Terrorism Act (USA PATRIOT ACT) of 2001 to authorize the disclosure to Federal, State, local, and foreign government officials of information obtained as part of a criminal investigation that reveals such a threat, for the purpose of preventing or responding to such a threat.(Sec. 9) Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to allow Federal officers who conduct electronic surveillance or physical searches to acquire foreign intelligence information to consult with State or local officials to coordinate efforts to investigate or protect against attacks, sabotage, or clandestine intelligence activities by a foreign power.</summary>
</bill>
