<bill session="106" type="h" number="4804" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Gas Price Equity Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require that fines paid to the United States as a result of motor fuel price investigations shall be rebated to consumers in the form of reductions in Federal motor fuel excise taxes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Price discrimination"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Tax cuts"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/2000--Introduced.
Gas Price Equity Act of 2000 - Requires any fine paid by a person to the United States as a result of any investigation into motor fuel prices to be rebated to consumers as provided by this Act.Reduces tax rates on motor vehicle fuel by the amount (and for the period) determined necessary by the Secretary of the Treasury to carry out this Act. Requires the fuel tax rate reduction to be the amount which will result in a reduction in revenues to the United States equal to the amount of fines paid. Directs the Secretary to provide for tax rate reductions in any region which are proportional to the extent of the conduct (to which the fine relates) which occurred in the region.Requires the Secretary to take steps to ensure that reductions under this Act are reflected in the retail price of the fuel.</summary>
</bill>
