<bill session="105" type="h" number="1703" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-06T14:57:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1997-10-06T14:57:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Department of Veterans' Affairs Employment Discrimination bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Department of Veterans Affairs Employment Discrimination Prevention Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Department of Veterans Affairs Employment Discrimination Resolution and Adjudication Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Department of Veterans Affairs Employment Discrimination Resolution and Adjudication Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for improved and expedited procedures for resolving complaints of unlawful employment discrimination arising within the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400056" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1997-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400163" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1997-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400301" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400309" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400610" joined="1997-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1997-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-07-17">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1997-09-30">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-02T10:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 105-292.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1997-10-02T10:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="166">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 166.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stump moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8369-8373" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:41:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1997-10-06T14:57:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-06T14:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Sexual harassment of women"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1997--Passed House amended.
Department of Veterans Affairs Employment Discrimination Resolution and Adjudication Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide that the employment discrimination complaint resolution system within the Department of Veterans Affairs be established and administered so as to encourage timely and fair resolution of concerns and complaints and that the system is administered in an objective, fair, and effective manner as perceived by Department employees. Directs the Secretary to impose appropriate disciplinary measures for Department employees who engage in unlawful employment discrimination, including retaliation against employees asserting equal employment opportunity (EEO) rights. Limits to 40 the number of Department employees whose duties include EEO counseling functions as well as other unrelated functions. Allows such splitting of functions only at Department facilities located in remote geographic locations. Directs the Secretary to submit to the Congress reports on the implementation and operation of the EEO system within the Department. Establishes in the Department an Office of Employment Discrimination Complaint Adjudication headed by a Director who shall be responsible for making final agency decisions on the merits of any unlawful employment discrimination complaints filed by a Department employee. Requires the Director to report to the Secretary or Deputy Secretary of Veterans Affairs when the Director has reason to believe that there has been retaliation against an employee asserting EEO rights. Requires the Director to submit to the Secretary and the Congress reports on the implementation and operation of the Office. Establishes an independent panel to review and report to the veterans' committees on the EEO and sexual harassment practices and procedures within the Department and to make recommendations on improvements.</summary>
</bill>
