<bill session="105" type="h" number="3091" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require a two-thirds vote on the passage of legislation that repeals, increases, or waives the discretionary spending limit or repeals or waives the pay-as-you-go provisions of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 if the current year budget was not in surplus or the budget for the fiscal year immediately preceding such year was not in surplus.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-01-27">
      <text>Referred to House Budget</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/1998--Introduced.
Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require, if the budget for the current year or the fiscal year preceding such year was not in surplus, a vote of at least two-thirds of the Members voting for passage of any legislation that repeals, increases, or waives any discretionary spending limit set forth in the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) or repeals or waives pay-as-you-go sequestration of such Act.</summary>
</bill>
