<bill session="105" type="h" number="3845" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Joint Forces Command Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish in the Department of Defense a new unified command for joint forces to have responsibility for providing ready joint forces to the commanders of regional combatant commands and to conduct joint experimentation to further develop joint military forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400404"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E847-848"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-06-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on National Security"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House National Security" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military maneuvers"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1998--Introduced.
Joint Forces Command Act of 1998 - Directs the President to establish a unified combatant command for joint forces which shall: (1) integrate elements of the various service branches into joint forces, prepare such forces for their assigned mission, and provide such forces as required by combatant commanders; and (2) design, develop, and carry out joint experimentation to assist in determining the future capabilities, organization, and operational concepts of the joint military force. Provides for: (1) joint forces command assignments; (2) authorities and responsibilities of the combatant commander; (3) the establishment within such command of a joint experimentation force; (4) annual reports from the joint commander to the Secretary of Defense describing joint experimentation activities conducted (requiring such reports to be transmitted to the Congress, along with the Secretary's comments); (5) the establishment by the Secretary of a separate major force program budget category for joint experimentation activities; (6) funding determinations for joint force experimentation; and (7) joint command staffing. Requires the: (1) joint force command to be established no later than October 1, 1999; and (2) Secretary to submit an implementation plan and initial budgeting request for such command.</summary>
</bill>
