<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="539" updated="2013-07-17T08:16:57-04:00">
  <amends type="h" number="4173" sequence="23"/>
  <status datetime="2009-12-11">offered</status>
  <sponsor id="400010"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-12-11"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute, as modified, sought to provide an alternative bill that establishes a new chapter of the bankruptcy code to resolve certain non-bank financial institutions; creates a consumer protection council comprised of existing Federal regulators to revise and promulgate model regulations to enhance consumer protection and improve disclosure; strengthens anti-fraud provisions; regulates over-the-counter derivatives markets; addresses executive compensation; removes statutory reliance on credit ratings; reforms the Government Sponsored Enterprises (Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac); and creates a Federal Insurance Office.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 36 printed in House Report 111-370 to provide an alternative bill that establishes a new chapter of the bankruptcy code to resolve certain non-bank financial institutions; creates a consumer protection council comprised of existing Federal regulators to revise and promulgate model regulations to enhance consumer protection and improve disclosure; strengthens anti-fraud provisions; regulates over-the-counter derivatives markets; addresses executive compensation; removes statutory reliance on credit ratings; reforms the Government Sponsored Enterprises (Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac); and creates a Federal Insurance Office.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-11T12:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A023) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Bachus.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14776-14797, H14799-14800, H14803-14804" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H14776-14792" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-11T12:07:00-05:00">
      <text>Bachus amendment (A023) modified by the order of the House of December 10, 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-11T13:50:00-05:00">
      <text>On agreeing to the Bachus amendment (A023) as modified Failed by recorded vote: 175 - 251 (Roll no. 966).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
