<bill session="104" type="h" number="4271" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Primary Care Promotion Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to continue full-time-equivalent resident reimbursement for an additional one year under Medicare for direct graduate medical education for residents enrolled in combined approved primary care medical residency training programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-09-27">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Obstetricians"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1996--Introduced.
Primary Care Promotion Act of 1996 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to direct graduate medical education for residents enrolled in combined approved primary care medical residency training programs. Provides for full-time-equivalent resident reimbursement for the minimum number of years of formal training required to satisfy the requirements for initial board eligibility in the longest of the individual programs plus one additional year. Declares that a resident enrolled in a combined medical residency training program that includes an obstetrics and gynecology program qualifies for the period of board eligibility under this Act if the other programs such resident combines with such obstetrics and gynecology program are for training a primary care resident.</summary>
</bill>
