<bill session="104" type="h" number="3484" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">FAA Research, Engineering, and Development Reform Act of 1996</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize the Federal Aviation Administration's research, engineering, and development programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="411247" joined="1996-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Science</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-16">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
      <committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/16/1996--Introduced.
FAA Research, Engineering, and Development Reform Act of 1996 - Amends Federal transportation law to: (1) authorize appropriations for FY 1997 for specified aviation programs; and (2) instruct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to consider the advice of a certain research advisory committee in establishing research and development priorities. Earmarks the research and development appropriations authorized for the support of all FAA research and development activities falling within the categories of basic and applied research and development, including the design and development of prototypes in accordance with specified classifications. Mandates that: (1) the President's annual FAA budget request include all research and development activities within a single budget category; and (2) all FAA activities within the categories of basic and applied research and development be placed within such category. Directs the research advisory committee in the FAA to review annually the Administrator's appropriation allocation among major research and development activities, and give advice and recommendations on whether such allocation is appropriate to meet certain needs and objectives. Amends the guidelines for the national aviation research plan with respect to the goals, priorities, and resources of research and development activities. Directs the FAA to develop, implement, and maintain a disciplined acquisition management system, based on specified operational principles. Authorizes the FAA to implement its own proposed acquisition management system which the Congress recognizes as substantially compatible with such principles.</summary>
</bill>
