<bill session="104" type="h" number="2289" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-12T18:49:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-12-12T18:49:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Housing, Employment Programs, and Employment Rights Benefits Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Housing, Employment Programs, and Employment Rights Benefits Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to extend permanently certain housing programs, to improve the veterans employment and training system, and to make clarifying and technical amendments to further clarify the employment and reemployment rights and responsibilities of members of the uniformed services, as well as those of the employer community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400514" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400030" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400048" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400075" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300151" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400545" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="409618" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1995-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400422" joined="1995-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1995-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-09-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-09-20">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-12-11T13:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 104-397.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1995-12-11T13:24:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="203">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 203.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-12-12T18:37:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Stump moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-12T18:38:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H14336-14340" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-12T18:38:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1995-12-12T18:49:00-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1995-12-12T18:49:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-12-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
      <committee name="Committee on Veterans"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1632"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="1941"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="s" number="1711"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/12/1995--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Veterans' Housing Programs Title II: Veterans' Employment and Training Title III: Employment and Reemployment Rights of Members of the Uniformed Services Veterans Housing, Employment Programs, and Employment Rights Benefits Act of 1995 - Title I: Veterans' Housing Programs - Extends permanently the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) negotiate interest rates charged to veterans on housing loans which are guaranteed or insured by the Department of Veterans Affairs; (2) guarantee loans made to veterans for the acquisition of an existing dwelling and the cost of making energy efficiency improvements to the dwelling or for energy efficiency improvements to a dwelling owned and occupied by a veteran; (3) allow lenders of guaranteed loans to review home appraisals; and (4) enter into specified agreements with States, their political subdivisions, and nonprofit organizations for the provision of housing assistance for homeless veterans. Authorizes the Secretary to approve the issuance of, and guarantee timely payment of principal and interest on, certificates or other securities evidencing an interest in a pool of mortgage loans representing Department of Veterans Affairs-guaranteed housing loans, as long as such securities are issued on or before December 31, 2000 (currently, December 31, 1995). (Sec. 102) Requires specified veterans' housing loan information to be included in a current annual Department budget report required to be submitted to the Congress. Repeals superseded reporting requirements under the Veterans Home Loan Program Amendments of 1992. (Sec. 103) Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to: (1) extend through FY 1998 the authorization of appropriations for homeless veterans' reintegration projects; (2) revise the amount of appropriations authorized for FY 1997 and 1998; and (3) extend through FY 1998 the general authorization of appropriations and the authority under such Act. Title II: Veterans' Employment and Training - Directs the Secretary of Labor to assign regional administrators for the Veterans' Employment and Training Service (Service) in at least five geographic regions of the United States. (Currently, such representatives are required for each region for which the Secretary operates a regional office.) (Sec. 202) Authorizes the hiring of other support personnel for Directors and Assistant Directors for the Service. Revises eligibility requirements for persons appointed as Directors and Assistant Directors in any State for at least two years. (Sec. 204) Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to conduct a pilot program under which the primary responsibilities of local veterans' employment representatives will be case management and the provision and facilitation of direct employment and training services to veterans. Limits the pilot program to no more than five States. Requires reports to the Congress and the Senate and House Veterans' Affairs Committees. Terminates pilot program authority on October 1, 1998. Title III: Employment and Reemployment Rights of Members of the Uniformed Services - Requests the prompt reemployment of persons upon completion of any military service. (Currently, such request is limited to those who completed such service under honorable conditions.) Revises generally: (1) provisions prohibiting discrimination or acts of reprisal against persons who exercise certain employment or reemployment rights provided under current law, whether or not such person has performed military service; and (2) provisions guaranteeing reemployment rights to persons who serve in the armed forces. (Sec. 306) Prohibits an employer from requiring a person engaged in military service to use vacation, annual, or similar leave during such period of service. (Sec. 309) Allows a person to submit a complaint against the Office of Personnel Management for the enforcement of any employment or reemployment right. (Sec. 313) Empowers the Secretary, in conducting investigations concerning employment and reemployment rights of former military personnel, to interview persons with information relevant to such investigation. (Sec. 314) Provides transition rules and effective dates.</summary>
</bill>
