<bill session="104" type="h" number="1843" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">District of Columbia Sports Arena Financing Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit a designated authority to borrow funds for the development and construction of a sports arena in the District of Columbia, to permit the District of Columbia to pledge certain revenues as security for the borrowing of such funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on District of Columbia.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1510"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSGO10" subcommittee="District of Columbia" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Municipal finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal taxation"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Stadiums"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/1995--Introduced.
District of Columbia Sports Arena Financing Act of 1995 - Authorizes an agency or instrumentality to borrow funds to develop and construct a sports arena in the District of Columbia if it is granted such authority by the District government. Prohibits such debt from: (1) being considered a general obligation debt of the District for any purpose; (2) constituting the lending of the public credit for private undertakings for purposes of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act; and (3) being a pledge of, or involve the full faith and credit of, the District. Permits the District and such agency or instrumentality to pledge as security for any borrowing undertaken pursuant to this Act any District revenues which are attributable to the sports arena tax. Excludes such pledged revenues from the formula used to calculate the annual aggregate limit on the District's debt. Allows the following activities to be carried out without the enactment of appropriations by the Congress: (1) proceeds of any borrowing conducted pursuant to this Act; (2) pledging of revenues as security for such borrowing; and (3) payment of principal, interest, or other costs associated with such borrowing.</summary>
</bill>
