<bill session="106" type="h" number="2671" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-06-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2000-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Yankton Sioux Tribe and Santee Sioux Tribe of Nebraska Development Trust Fund Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for the Yankton Sioux Tribe and the Santee Sioux Tribe of Nebraska certain benefits of the Missouri River Basin Pick-Sloan project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-08-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-05-16">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2000-06-28">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2000-07-17T16:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 106-735.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2000-07-17T16:46:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="416">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 416.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="106" type="s" number="1148"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1999--Introduced.
Yankton Sioux Tribe and Santee Sioux Tribe of Nebraska Development Trust Fund Act - Establishes in the Treasury the Yankton Sioux Tribe Development Trust Fund and the Santee Sioux Tribe of Nebraska Development Trust Fund. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) deposit a specified amount into each Fund; (2) invest such amounts and deposit resulting interest in the Funds; and (3) withdraw the aggregate amount of interest deposited into the Funds each fiscal year and transfer that amount to the Secretary of the Interior to use for making payments to the Yankton Sioux Tribe and the Santee Sioux Tribe, as requested by each Tribe pursuant to tribal resolution, for carrying out projects and programs under each Tribe's Tribal Plan. Permits each Tribe to enter into an agreement under which it pledges future payments as security for a loan or other financial transaction, but only in connection with the purchase of land or other capital assets, and only for an amount less than 40 percent of any payment for that year.Directs the tribal council of each Tribe to prepare a Tribal Plan for using payments for carrying out projects and programs to promote: (1) economic development; (2) infrastructure development; or (3) the educational, health, recreational, and social welfare objectives of the Tribe and its members.Prohibits any payment made to either Tribe pursuant to this Act from: (1) resulting in the reduction or denial of any service or program to which the Tribe or any member of the Tribe is otherwise entitled because of federally recognized status; (2) being subject to any Federal or State income tax; or (3) affecting Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin power rates.Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
