<bill session="106" type="h" number="4333" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for fairness and accuracy in student testing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400364"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400063" joined="2000-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2000-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="2000-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2000-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400289" joined="2000-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400312" joined="2000-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="2348"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of disabled students"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Spanish language"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/13/2000--Introduced.
Establishes certain requirements relating to the use of standardized tests by State and local educational agencies (SEAs and LEAs) that receive funds under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA).Prohibits standardized test performance from being the sole determinant of any decision about an individual student's retention, graduation, tracking, or within-class ability grouping. Allows test performance to be considered in making such decision only if specified criteria are met. Requires such tests to: (1) meet professional standards of validity and reliability for the purpose for which its results are being used; (2) allow users to make score interpretations related to a functional performance level, and be based on State or local content or performance standards, and be aligned with curriculum and classroom instruction; (3) be administered in accordance with written guidance from the test developer or publisher; and (4) not be used to decide promotion or placement in special education for a child below age eight or grade three. Requires that: (1) multiple measures of student achievement be used, including grades and evaluations by teachers, so that scores from large-scale assessments are never the only source of information used nor assigned determinative weight in making a high-stakes decision about an individual student; and (2) multiple opportunities to demonstrate proficiency in the subject matter covered by the test be provided to students tested. Requires SEAs and LEAs to: (1) have evidence that the test is of adequate technical quality for each purpose for which it is used; (2) provide appropriate accommodations and alternate assessments for students with disabilities that provide such students with a valid opportunity to show what they know and can do; and (3) provide appropriate accommodations for students with limited English proficiency, including specified arrangements.Requires evaluations of the impact of standardized tests use in high stakes decisions on students' education and educational outcomes, particularly on individuals and subgroups disaggregated by socioeconomic status, race, ethnicity, limited English proficiency, disability, and gender, to be carried out by: (1) SEAs receiving ESEA funds; (2) LEAs receiving ESEA funds located in States that do not do such evaluations; and (3) the Secretary of Education.</summary>
</bill>
