<bill session="104" type="h" number="2528" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To require the Secretary of the Interior to renew to the heirs of permittees permits for historic cabins located in the Mineral King Addition of the Sequoia National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400330"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1995-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400505" joined="1996-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="402858" joined="1995-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1996-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400129" joined="1996-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1995-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="409718" joined="1995-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-05-23">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3534.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="104" type="h" number="3534"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/25/1995--Introduced.
Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 to delete provisions which require the Secretary of the Interior to review leases or permits before their renewal or extension on Federal land within the Mineral King Addition of the Sequoia National Park, California. Requires such leases to be renewed or extended under their original terms and conditions. Grants renewal or extension of leases and permits to persons who held the leases or permits on November 10, 1978, or their heirs (currently, such persons). Allows the Secretary to terminate such lease or permit only for a breach of the specific conditions detailed in it. Directs the Secretary to grant the heirs of the person a renewal or extension of a lease or permit that was continued under the Act, that was held by a person who died after November 10, 1978, and that expired on or before this Act's enactment without being renewed or extended in the same manner as leases and permits are otherwise renewed or extended under the Act and under the same terms and conditions applicable to such leases or permits.</summary>
</bill>
