<bill session="108" type="h" number="4779" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Clinical Research Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for clinical research support grants, clinical research infrastructure grants, and a demonstration program on partnerships in clinical research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400427"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="2004-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400092" joined="2004-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400114" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400153" joined="2004-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400164" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400183" joined="2004-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1346"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="2924"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/2004--Introduced.
Clinical Research Act of 2004 - Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health to award clinical research support grants to eligible academic health centers to: (1) defray the costs of unfunded Federal requirements for the protection of human research costs; and (2) support activities leading to innovative ways to meets such requirements in an efficient and cost-effective manner. Requires that health centers receive a proportionate share of the total grant money awarded based on the amount invested by the grantee in clinical research compared to the total clinical research investment of all grantees. Allows the Director to award clinical research infrastructure grants to eligible academic health centers for: (1) necessary infrastructure to facilitate the transfer of new understandings of disease mechanisms gained in the laboratory into the development of new methodologies for diagnosis, therapy, and prevention; (2) the initial testing of human subjects; and (3) addressing obstacles impeding the expeditious application of new science, including a lack of up-to-date information technology systems and a shortage of willing participants. Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make up to five grants to eligible academic health centers to form partnerships between the centers involved and health care providers for carrying out clinical human subject research to demonstrate how academic research centers may collaborate with the practicing health care community in such research.</summary>
</bill>
