<bill session="104" type="hc" number="209" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1996-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1996-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the territorial integrity, unity, sovereignty, and full independence of Lebanon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1996-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404142" joined="1996-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1996-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="405560" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1996-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="1996-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1996-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1996-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aggression"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Disengagement"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1996--Introduced.
Reaffirms the U.S. commitment to preserve the territorial integrity, unity, sovereignty, and full independence of Lebanon. Urges the President to take the necessary steps to activate the Consultative Group for Lebanon's Reconstruction, which was established by the April 26, 1996, Understanding between Lebanon and Israel. Calls for the withdrawal of all non-Lebanese forces from Lebanon. Calls upon: (1) the President to negotiate directly with officials of the Government of Lebanon on issues pertaining to Lebanon; (2) Lebanon to assert more independence to assure the international community that it has the political will and military capability to guarantee security along its borders for itself and its neighbors and disarm all militias upon the withdrawal of non-Lebanese forces from Lebanon; and (3) Lebanon's parliamentary elections to proceed unimpeded in a fair, open, and equitable manner. Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the President should use such guidelines in formulating U.S. policy toward Lebanon and consider resolving the presence of non-Lebanese forces in Lebanon without relying exclusively upon a comprehensive peace in the region to resolve this issue; and (2) insofar as Lebanon's neighbors require security from Lebanon, Lebanon must be secure from interference from its neighbors.</summary>
</bill>
