<bill session="108" type="h" number="968" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Maggie's Law: National Drowsy Driving Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide incentives to States for the development of traffic safety programs to reduce crashes related to driver fatigue and sleep deprivation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400067" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="2004-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2004-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2003-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW12" subcommittee="Highways, Transit and Pipelines" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Driver education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Sleep disorders"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/27/2003--Introduced.
Maggie's Law: National Drowsy Driving Act of 2003 - Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to enter into agreements with, and make grants to, State highway offices and other driving safety organizations to obtain and distribute national, State, and local drowsy driving education programs and supporting materials.Directs that grant funds be used to: (1) implement programs designed to prevent deaths and injuries due to drivers who are impaired by fatigue and sleep deprivation; (2) develop a standardized curriculum on the risks and prevention of drowsy driving and fall-asleep motor vehicle crashes; (3) collaborate with national drowsy driving campaigns to distribute information and educational messages and to review existing State model programs; (4) adopt policy statements and work plans for the installation and expansion of continuous shoulder rumble strips for interstate highways; (5) adopt codes on accident report forms to report fatigue-related or fall-asleep crashes; (6) provide training in the detection and reporting of drowsy driving as a factor in motor vehicle crashes; and (7) provide education programs to the police and the courts regarding the sanctions available for drowsy driving accidents.Directs the Secretary to study the scope of the problem of fatigue-related automobile crashes.</summary>
</bill>
