<bill session="106" type="h" number="3243" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Open and Accountable Campaign Financing Act of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide meaningful campaign finance reform through requiring better reporting, decreasing the role of soft money, and increasing individual contribution limits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400400"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Commerce, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-05">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="1816"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army posts"/>
    <term name="Campaign contributors"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Computers in politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Naval bases"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Soft money"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Disclosure Title II: Soft Money of National Political Parties and Contribution Limits Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions Open and Accountable Campaign Financing Act of 2000 - Title I: Disclosure - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to revise reporting requirements, including: (1) changing from quarterly to monthly the additional reports required to be filed with regard to the principal campaign committee of a candidate for the House of Representatives or the Senate in any calendar year during which there is a regularly scheduled election for which such candidate is seeking nomination or election; (2) requiring a national committee of a political party to file the same monthly reports designated for all political committees other than authorized committees of a candidate; (3) requiring the national committee of a political party, any national congressional campaign committee of a political party, and any subordinate committee of either, to report all receipts and disbursements during the appropriate reporting period; and (4) directing the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to make report information available on the Internet and at FEC offices.Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a licensee to maintain and make available for public inspection a complete record of certain requests to purchase broadcast time that are related to legally qualified candidates.Title II: Soft Money of National Political Parties and Contribution Limits - Amends FECA to limit to $60,000 aggregate (indexed for inflation) per calendar year per contributor the amount of soft money a national committee of a political party, a congressional campaign committee of a national party, or an entity directly or indirectly established, financed, maintained, or controlled by such committee may accept. Provides for judicial review with respect to such amendment.Increases individual, political committee, and multicandidate political committee contribution limits. Revises indexing provisions.Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit solicitation of soft money in any room or building occupied in the discharge of official duties by an officer or employee of the United States or any department or agency thereof, or a person receiving any salary or compensation for service from the Treasury.Amends FECA to provide for the indexing of certain penalty and other amounts under enforcement provisions.</summary>
</bill>
