<bill session="108" type="h" number="1982" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title III of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to provide to contracting officers of the civilian agencies the same authorities available to Department of Defense contracting officers to competitively evaluate products offered by Federal Prison Industries, Inc., to assure that such products represent the best value for the taxpayer dollars being expended, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="2003-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal Prison Industries, Inc."/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Prices"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Real property"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/2003--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to require the head of an executive agency: (1) before purchasing a product listed in the latest edition of the Federal Prison Industries (FPI) catalog, to conduct market research to determine whether the Industries' product is comparable to products available from the private sector that best meet the agency's needs in terms of price, quality, and time of delivery; and (2) if an FPI product is not comparable, to use competitive procedures for the procurement of the product or to make an individual purchase under a multiple award contract, considering any timely offer from FPI; and (3) to ensure that FPI performs its contractual obligations to the same extent as any other agency contractor..Prohibits: (1) a contractor or potential contractor of an agency from being required, by any means, to use FPI as a subcontractor or supplier of products or provider of services for the performance of an agency contract; or (2) an agency head from entering into a contract with FPI under which an inmate worker would have access to specified classified or sensitive information.</summary>
</bill>
