<bill session="108" type="h" number="2342" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Medicare Chronic Care Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to expand Medicare benefits to prevent, delay, and minimize the progression of chronic conditions, and develop national policies on effective chronic condition care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400208" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400262" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400268" joined="2003-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="2003-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400358" joined="2003-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1122"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF14" subcommittee="Health" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1179"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Cervical cancer"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Colon cancer"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Eye care"/>
    <term name="Eye diseases"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Hepatitis"/>
    <term name="Influenza"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Living wills"/>
    <term name="Mammography"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Osteoporosis"/>
    <term name="Ovarian cancer"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Prostate cancer"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/2003--Introduced.
Medicare Chronic Care Improvement Act of 2003 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from requiring the payment of deductibles and coinsurance for certain existing preventive benefits under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance). Directs the Secretary to contract with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences to study and report to the President on current literature and best practices in the field of health promotion and disease prevention among Medicare beneficiaries, including specified issues. Requires the Institute to develop recommendations in legislative form that prioritize Medicare preventive health benefits and modify them, adding new ones based on such study. Authorizes the Secretary by regulation to adopt any or all of such recommendations. Applies the elimination of cost-sharing for preventive benefits under this Act to any Medicare furnished items and services incorporated by such regulation. Provides for: (1) Medicare coverage of an initial preventive physical examination and care coordination and assessment services furnished by a care coordinator as a Medicare part B medical service; and (2) care coordination and assessment services and quality improvement program in Medicare+Choice plans under Medicare part C (Medicare+Choice). Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to enable them to develop, implement, or train personnel in the use of standardized clinical information technology systems designed to: (1) improve the coordination and quality of care furnished to Medicare beneficiaries with chronic conditions; and (2) increase administrative efficiencies of such entities. Directs the Secretary to: (1) review appropriate regulations, policies, and procedures, including those of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMMS), with respect to determinations of whether an item or service is reasonable and necessary for the diagnosis or treatment of illness or injury for purposes of payment under Medicare; and (2) take appropriate corrective measures to ensure that the proper standard for making such determinations is applied, if it is found that CMMS, a fiscal intermediary, or a carrier has misapplied the coverage standard by requiring that the item or service improve the condition of the patient with respect to such illness or injury. Directs the Secretary to contract with the Institute of Medicine to study and report to the Secretary and Congress on factors of the Medicare program that facilitate or impede effective care for Medicare beneficiaries with chronic conditions.</summary>
</bill>
