<bill session="107" type="h" number="2359" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the payment of National Service Life Insurance and United States Government Life Insurance proceeds to an alternate beneficiary when the first beneficiary cannot be identified, to improve and extend the Native American veteran housing loan pilot program, and to eliminate the requirement to provide the Secretary of Veterans Affairs a copy of a notice of appeal to the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2001-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR06" subcommittee="Benefits" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/2001--Introduced.
Authorizes the payment of proceeds following the death of the insured under the National Life Insurance Program and the United States Government Life Insurance Program: (1) to another beneficiary designated by the insured, if the first beneficiary does not make a claim for such insurance within two years; or (2) to any person designated by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to be equitably entitled to such proceeds, if no claim has been filed by any designated beneficiary within four years.Extends through December 31, 2005, the Native American Veteran housing loan pilot program. Authorizes the Secretary to make a direct housing loan to such a veteran if the tribal organization having jurisdiction over such veteran has entered into a memorandum of understanding with any Federal department or agency with respect to such loans. Revises the loan assumption notice requirement.Eliminates the requirement of providing the Secretary with a copy of a notice of appeal of a decision by the Court of Veterans Appeals.</summary>
</bill>
