<bill session="105" type="h" number="4434" updated="2013-07-14T18:51:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Graton Rancheria Restoration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To restore Federal recognition to the Indians of the Graton Rancheria of California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400436"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-08-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian gambling operations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/1998--Introduced.
Graton Rancheria Restoration Act - Restores Federal recognition and associated rights, privileges, and eligibility for Federal services and benefits to the Indians of the Graton Rancheria of California (the Tribe). Requires the Secretary of the Interior, upon application by the Tribe, to accept in trust for the Tribe any real property located in Marin or Sonoma County, California, after the property is conveyed to the Secretary if there are no adverse legal claims to such property. Provides that any such property shall: (1) be part of the Tribe's reservation; (2) not be exempt from the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act; and (3) be exempt from all local, State, and Federal taxation. Directs the Secretary to compile a membership roll of the Tribe not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act. Provides for: (1) an Interim Tribal Council to be the Tribe's governing body; (2) an election to ratify a Tribal constitution; and (3) the election of Tribal officials under such constitution.</summary>
</bill>
