<bill session="106" type="h" number="5154" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Transportation Information Recall Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 18, United States Code, to impose criminal and civil penalties for false statements and failure to file reports concerning defects in foreign motor vehicle products, and to require the timely provision of notice of such defects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400579" joined="2000-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2000-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400605" joined="2000-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-09-12">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="h" number="5190"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="106" type="s" number="3012"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobile parts"/>
    <term name="Automobile parts industry"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/12/2000--Introduced.
Transportation Information Recall Enhancement Act - Declares it is the purpose of this Act to ensure that defects in motor vehicles or replacement equipment in foreign countries are quickly, accurately, and truthfully reported to the Secretary of Transportation in cases in which: (1) motor vehicles or replacement equipment are manufactured for export to the United States; or (2) such vehicles or equipment are manufactured in the United States using a manufacturing process that is the same as, or similar to, the manufacturing process used in the foreign country, with the result that U.S. manufactured motor vehicles or replacement equipment may also be defective.Amends Federal transportation law to require a manufacturer, not later than 48 hours after determining, or learning that a government of a foreign country has determined, that a foreign motor vehicle product contains a defect that could be related to motor vehicle safety, to report such determination to the Secretary of Transportation. Sets forth similar requirements with respect to the reporting of possible defects in such vehicle or equipment that have resulted in a significant number of serious injuries or fatalities in a foreign country. Sets forth both criminal and civil penalties for manufacturers of foreign motor vehicle products who falsify information with respect to, or otherwise violate, the reporting requirements contained in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
