<bill session="104" type="h" number="917" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-02-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1995-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Product Liability Reform Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Common Sense Product Liability Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish procedures for product liability actions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-13">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-15">
      <text>Referred for a period ending not later than February 21, 1995, (or for a later time if the Chairman so designates) to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-02-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1995-02-23">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 17.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1995-03-01T20:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Commerce. H. Rept. 104-63, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSIF11" subcommittee="Commerce, Trade, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Biomedical materials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indemnity"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Raw materials"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/1/1995--Reported to House amended, Part I.
Common Sense Product Liability Reform Act - Declares that this Act governs any product liability action in State or Federal court against a manufacturer or seller, except for: (1) actions for commercial loss; (2) issues not covered by this Act; and (3) actions under title XXI (Vaccines) of the Public Health Service Act. (Sec. 3) Establishes seller liability if the seller failed to exercise reasonable care, made an express warranty (independent of any express manufacturer's warranty), or engaged in intentional wrongdoing as determined under State law. Declares that the seller shall not be considered to have failed to exercise reasonable care based on a failure to inspect the product where there was no reasonable opportunity to inspect. Makes the seller liable as if the seller were the manufacturer if: (1) the manufacturer is not subject to service of process under the laws of the State of the action; or (2) the court determines that the claimant would be unable to enforce a judgment against the manufacturer. (Sec. 4) Makes it a complete defense if the claimant, as a result of the influence of alcohol or a controlled substance, was more than 50 percent responsible for causing the event that resulted in the harm. (Sec. 5) Reduces the manufacturer's or seller's liability by the percentage of responsibility for the harm attributable to misuse or alteration of a product. (Sec. 6) Prohibits a product liability action unless filed within 15 years of the date of delivery of the product to its first purchaser or lessee, unless there was an express warranty longer than 15 years. States that the preceding sentence applies only if: (1) the claimant is eligible for workers' compensation; and (2) the harm from the product did not cause a chronic illness. (Sec. 7) Allows punitive damages if it is established by clear and convincing evidence that the harm resulted from conscious, flagrant indifference to safety, subject to various limitations and requirements. (Sec. 8) Allows several but not joint liability for noneconomic damages in direct proportion to the defendant's percentage of responsibility. (Sec. 9) Declares that the district courts of the United States shall not have jurisdiction, under provisions of Federal law relating to Federal questions, commerce and antitrust, and amounts in controversy, over actions under this Act. (Sec. 10) Establishes sanctions for frivolous pleadings. (Sec. 12) Allows biomaterials suppliers to be liable only if certain matters are shown by a preponderance of the evidence.</summary>
</bill>
