<bill session="108" type="h" number="3998" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Au Pair Program Expansion Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To expand au pair exchange visitor programs to include the provision of in-home independent living services for adults with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400087" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400136" joined="2004-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400291" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400344" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="2004-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Household workers"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/2004--Introduced.
Au Pair Program Extension Act - Directs the Secretary of State to establish a pilot program under which current Department of State-designated au pair program sponsors may place foreign nationals in positions that require in-home independent living services to an adult with disabilities rather than child care services. (Terminates such pilot program not earlier than five years after the date it begins.) Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) define in-home independent living services to include only home support services such as personal care, homemaker services, and performance of routine household chores, and to exclude medical care or other services to be delivered by licensed health professionals or under the direction of a physical or occupational therapist; (2) ensure that all cultural exchange and educational aspects of the existing au pair exchange programs are unimpaired; and (3) establish standards to ensure that pilot program participants receive appropriate training. Authorizes the Secretary to expand the age range of pilot program candidates.</summary>
</bill>
