<bill session="105" type="h" number="3858" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Border Protection and Infrastructure Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To assure drug-free borders by increasing penalties for certain drug-related offenses, to enhance law enforcement efforts for counterdrug activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400570" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400091" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400157" joined="1998-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1998-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400601" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="1998-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400421" joined="1998-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400541" joined="1998-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Life imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Seizure of vessels and cargoes"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/1998--Introduced.
Border Protection and Infrastructure Act of 1998 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit and set penalties for committing (or attempting to commit) a crime of violence during and in relation to: (1) eluding customs, immigration, or agriculture inspection or failing to stop at the command of an officer of customs, immigration, or animal and plant and health inspection services; or (2) an intentional violation of specified arrival, reporting, entry, or clearance requirements (provides for imposition of a death sentence if death results). Specifies that if two or more persons conspire to commit such an offense, and one or more of such persons do any act to effect the object of the conspiracy, each shall be punishable as a principal, except that the death sentence may not be imposed. (Sec. 3) Increases the penalty for entry of goods by means of false statements. (Sec. 4) Prohibits the master, operator, or person in charge of a vessel of, or subject to the jurisdiction of, the United States from failing to obey an order to heave to that vessel upon being ordered to do so by an authorized Federal law enforcement officer. Prohibits any person on board from knowingly or willfully: (1) failing to comply with an order of such an officer in connection with the boarding of the vessel; (2) impeding or obstructing a boarding, arrest, or other law enforcement action authorized by Federal law; or (3) providing false information to such an officer during a boarding regarding the vessel's destination, origin, ownership, registration, nationality, cargo, or crew. Prohibits the pilot, operator, or person in charge of an aircraft which has crossed the U.S. border, or an aircraft subject to U.S. jurisdiction operating outside the United States, from knowingly failing to obey an order to land by such an officer who is enforcing U.S. laws relating to controlled substances or money laundering. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to prescribe regulations governing the means by, and circumstances under which, such an officer may communicate an order to land. Authorizes a foreign nation to consent or waive objection to such enforcement of U.S. law by the United States by international agreement or, on a case-by-case basis, by radio, telephone, or similar oral or electronic means. Sets penalties for intentional violations. Authorizes seizure and forfeiture to the United States of an aircraft or vessel used in violations. (Sec. 5) Establishes civil penalties for failure to comply with vessel boarding. (Sec. 6) Directs the Attorney General to increase the number of positions for full-time, active-duty border patrol agents within the Immigration and Naturalization Service to achieve a level of 20,000 positions by FY 2003. (Sec. 7) Prohibits a U.S. Border Patrol agent, within ten miles of the U.S. international border, from ceasing pursuit of an alien suspecting of unlawfully entering the United States, or of an individual suspected of unlawfully importing a narcotic into the United States, until State or local law enforcement authorities are in pursuit of the alien or individual and have the alien or individual in their visual range. (Sec. 8) Authorizes: (1) the Border Patrol to interdict the importation of narcotics; and (2) the Attorney General to install multi-layered barriers and roads in the U.S. border vicinity to deter drug trafficking in high drug trafficking areas. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
