<bill session="105" type="h" number="3546" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-04-29T18:47:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-04-29T18:47:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Social Security Dialogue bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Dialogue on Social Security Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">National Dialogue on Social Security Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">National Dialogue on Social Security Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a national dialogue on Social Security and to establish the Bipartisan Panel to Design Long-Range Social Security Reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="1998-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1998-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1998-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400332" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409087" joined="1998-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1998-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E471"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-04-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-23T19:50:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 105-493.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-04-23T19:51:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="284">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 284.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-04-28T20:39:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 410 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3546 with 3 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the House. Measure will be read by section. A specified amendment is in order. It shall be in order to consider an amendment printed in the Congressional Record, if offered by Rep Rangel. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, as modified by the amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted. amendment is in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 410 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 410.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2487-2510" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T16:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3546 with 3 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except one motion to recommit. Providing for the consideration of the bill in the House. Measure will be read by section. A specified amendment is in order. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, as modified by the amendments printed in the report accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted. It shall be in order to consider an amendment printed in the Congressional Record, if offered by Rep. Rangel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>By unanimous consent, the time for general debate was reduced to 2 hours.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T16:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 410 and the preceeding unanimous consent agreement, the House proceeded with 2 hours of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T18:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pomeroy moved to recommit with instructions to Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T18:03:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T18:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T18:34:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 223 (Roll No. 115).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2509" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-04-29T18:47:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="116" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 413 - 8 (Roll No. 116).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-04-29T18:47:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-04-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="410"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Constituent relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h566"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/29/1998--Passed House amended.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: National Dialogue on Social Security Title II: Bipartisan Panel to Design Long-Range Social Security Reform National Dialogue on Social Security Act of 1998 - Title I: National Dialogue on Social Security - Directs the President, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Majority Leader of the Senate to jointly convene a National Dialogue (ND) on the Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance (OASDI) program under title II of the Social Security Act. Makes ND's stated purpose to engage the American public, through regional conferences and national Internet exchanges, in understanding OASDI, its problems, and the need for workable solutions and to generate public comments and recommendations for social security reform. Establishes a Dialogue Council to advise the two national Facilitators appointed to administer and coordinate ND in its development and operations, the final plans for such to be transmitted to the President and the Congress by the Facilitators. Requires ND to operate by means of private sponsorship. Authorizes each Member of Congress, to the extent practicable, to develop with grassroots organizations and other constituency groups within the Member's district ongoing systems of communication through the Internet to assure the widest possible degree of receipt of public opinion. Establishes an Internet Advisory Board to advise the Internet Dialogue Coordinator appointed by the Facilitators to assist Members in establishing such systems of communication with regard to the most appropriate and effective means of employing the Internet to generate constituency input. Requires the Coordinator to establish a national dialogue web site. Authorizes appropriations from the general fund of the Treasury. Title II: Bipartisan Panel to Design Long-Range Social Security Reform - Establishes the Bipartisan Panel to Design Long-Range Social Security Reform, which shall design, and report to the President and specified congressional committees, a single set of legislative and administrative recommendations for long-range reforms for restoring the solvency of the social security system and for maintaining retirement income security. Expresses the sense of the Congress that, pending the Panel's report, the Federal unified budget surplus should be dedicated to reducing the Federal debt held by the public, increasing the retirement income security of individuals, and insuring the solvency of the social security system. Authorizes appropriations from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
