<bill session="106" type="h" number="3285" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Federal Asset Management Improvement Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To authorize public-private partnerships to rehabilitate Federal real property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1999--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Improved Property Management Title II: Public-Private Partnerships Federal Asset Management Improvement Act of 1999 - Title I: Improved Property Management - Directs the: (1) Administrator of General Services to establish performance measures to determine the effectiveness of Federal property management; (2) head of each executive agency to monitor their agency's performance against such measures and report results to Congress; and (3) Administrator to submit to Congress a Federal property management plan.Title II: Public-Private Partnerships - Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to authorize the Administrator to enter into agreements for the creation of one or more public-private partnerships to: (1) lease Federal real property; and (2) develop, rehabilitate, or renovate facilities on such property for use by executive agencies. Requires the Administrator to prepare and submit to Congress at least 30 days before entering into such an agreement a business plan regarding each agreement.</summary>
</bill>
