<bill session="106" type="h" number="5283" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Telemarketing Victims Protection Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Telemarketing and Consumer Fraud and Abuse Prevention Act to authorize the Federal Trade Commission to issue new rules regulating telemarketing firms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400606"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF12" subcommittee="Telecommunications, Trade, and Consumer Protection" name="House Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/2000--Introduced.
Telemarketing Victims Protection Act - Amends the Telemarketing and Consumer Fraud and Abuse Prevention Act (the Act) to require the Federal Trade Commission to include in rules respecting abusive telemarketing acts or practices requirements that telemarketers: (1) notify consumers who are called that they have the right to be placed on either the telemarketer's do-not- call list or the appropriate State do-not-call list; and (2) shall regularly obtain and reconcile with their own list the appropriate State list.Directs the Commission to study and report to Congress on violations of the Act, especially of repeated violations by a single telemarketer and of the provisions for penalizing telemarketers for such violations, including new provisions which would allow Federal action against telemarketers.</summary>
</bill>
