<bill session="108" type="h" number="4768" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-29T17:31:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-29T17:31:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Veterans Medical Facilities Management Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Veterans Health Programs and Facilities Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Veterans Health Programs and Facilities Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into certain major medical facility leases, to authorize that Secretary to transfer real property subject to certain limitations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into certain major medical facility leases, to authorize that Secretary to transfer real property subject to certain limitations, otherwise to improve management of medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400020" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400279" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400339" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400388" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400411" joined="2004-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1315-1316"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>Report amended to the House. H. Rept. 108-663.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08">
      <text>-Provisions incorporated. See H. R. 4248, as amended, Sections 203, 303, 401, 403, 411, 412, 413, 415, 416, 417, and 603.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Veterans' Affairs"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-08T17:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 108-663.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-08T17:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="403">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 403.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29T17:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NJ) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7790-7796" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29T17:04:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4768.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2004-09-29T17:31:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7790-7792" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29T17:31:00-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Health" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="4248"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/2004--Passed House amended.
Veterans Health Programs and Facilities Enhancement Act of 2004 - Title I: Medical Facilities Management - (Sec. 101) Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into contracts for major medical facility leases at specified locations. Authorizes appropriations for FY 2005 for the Medical Care account, to cover such leases. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a lease for real property at the Fitzsimons Campus of the University of Colorado for a period of up to 75 years. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer Department of Veterans Affairs real property to another department or agency of the United States, to a State, or to any public or private entity, including Indian tribes. Terminates such authority seven years after the enactment of this Act. Establishes in the Treasury the Department of Veterans Affairs Capital Asset Fund, which may be used for costs associated with: (1) current or future real property transfers under this Act; (2) the improvement of patient care facilities for veterans; and (3) the transfer, lease, or adaptive use of properties listed on the National Register of Historic Places. Authorizes appropriations for the Fund. Terminates the nursing home revolving fund. Transfers unobligated balances to the Capital Asset Fund. (Sec. 103) Requires a report from the Secretary to the congressional veterans' committees, in each of 2005 through 2007, on historic properties administered or controlled by the Secretary. (Sec. 104) Authorizes the use of certain Department funds for the construction or relocation of surface parking lots incidental to construction or maintenance projects. (Sec. 105) Removes the congressional review requirement otherwise applicable to the obligation of funds for major medical facilities where funds have been authorized by law. (Se. 106) Specifies that the construction, alteration, repair, remodeling, or improvement of property under an enhanced-use lease is not subject to State or local land use laws unless otherwise provided by the Secretary. (Sec. 107) Amends the Veterans Millennium Health Care and Benefits Act to extend through 2005 the authority for long-term care pilot programs established under such Act. Title II: Other Matters - (Sec. 201) Makes eligible for use of the Veterans' Canteen Service veterans enrolled in the Department's patient enrollment system. (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary, within 90 days after the enactment of this Act, to establish a peer review panel to assess the scientific and clinical merits of various proposed sites for designation as Department medical emergency preparedness centers. Requires the: (1) Secretary to solicit proposals for such designation within 60 days after enactment of this Act; and (2) peer review panel to complete proposal review within 60 days thereafter. Authorizes appropriations for such centers for FY 2005 through 2007. Requires the Under Secretary for Health to allocate certain other Department funds for such centers.</summary>
</bill>
