<bill session="107" type="h" number="5420" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Port Protection Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title 46, United States Code, to require inspection of cargo destined for the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400289"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-19">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical weapons"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Container ships"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transport aircraft"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/2002--Introduced.
Port Protection Act of 2002 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to require the inspection, contents verification, and sealing by personnel of the Department of Homeland Security, at ports or airports outside the United States, of any cargo containers destined for the United States. States that the Customs Service shall not allow the entry of any noncontainerized cargo by any means other than a vessel or airplane until it has verified that it does not contain a chemical, biological, or nuclear weapon.Directs the Commandant of the Coast Guard to inspect, at least 200 miles from the United States, any cargo vessel carrying cargo destined for the United States and verify that it does not have a chemical, biological, or nuclear weapon.Requires the Secretary to deny entry into the United States to cargo vessels that: (1) are carrying cargo not in compliance with this Act; or (2) are not inspected by the Commandant of the Coast Guard in accordance with this Act or that fail such an inspection.</summary>
</bill>
