<bill session="105" type="h" number="3848" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Foreign Sovereign Immunity Technical Corrections Act of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To permit certain claims against foreign states to be heard in United States courts where the foreign state is a state sponsor of international terrorism or where no extradition treaty with the state existed at the time the claim arose and where no other adequate and available remedies exist.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411947"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Claims.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration and Claims" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Extradition agreements"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Hostages"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immunities of foreign states"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International claims"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Sabotage"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1998--Introduced.
Foreign Sovereign Immunity Technical Corrections Act of 1998 - Amends the Federal judicial code to revise the exemption from foreign sovereign immunity when money damages are sought against a foreign state for personal injury or death caused by a specified kind of violent act engaged in or materially supported by an official, employee, or agent of such foreign state. Extends the exemption from foreign sovereign immunity to foreign states which are not designated state sponsors of terrorism, but which have no treaty of extradition with the United States at the time the act occurred, and no adequate and available remedies conforming with fundamental fairness and due process. Sets forth a statute of limitations for actions against such a state, declaring that no action may be brought for a cause of action that arose more than 20 years before the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
