<bill session="108" type="h" number="3617" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="2003-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Presidential Funding Act of 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reform the system of public financing for presidential elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400269"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="2003-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1913"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Election candidates"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Political conventions"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Primaries"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/21/2003--Introduced.
Presidential Funding Act of 2003 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (including the Presidential Election Campaign Fund Act and the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account Act) and the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to, among other things: (1) increase the presidential primary $250 one-to-one match to a four-to-one match; (2) increase the presidential primary qualifying threshold of $5,000 in 20 States to $15,000 in 20 States; (3) require candidates to be eligible to receive funding under the Presidential Election Campaign Fund Act to have received payments under the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account Act; (4) revise candidate expenditure limits, including permitting the national committee of a political party to make expenditures in connection with the general election campaign of any candidate for President of the United States who is affiliated with such party in an amount of up to four (currently, two) cents multiplied by the U.S. voting age population and permitting an eligible candidate for the office of President of the United States to receive payments from the Secretary of the Treasury of up to $75,000,000 with respect to a campaign for nomination for election or of up to $75,000,000 with respect to a campaign for election to such office; and (5) double the three dollar presidential campaign tax return check-off to six dollars.</summary>
</bill>
