<bill session="105" type="h" number="3143" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1998-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Comprehensive Holocaust Accountability in Insurance Measure</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit foreign insurance companies from doing business in the United States unless they disclose any financial dealings they had with individuals who survived or died in the Holocaust, to prohibit an insured depository institution from transacting any business with or on behalf of any such foreign insurance company, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1998-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400553" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400057" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400133" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400138" joined="1998-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1998-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1998-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400213" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400594" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400263" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400371" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400430" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400436" joined="1998-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1998-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H245"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Hazardous Materials.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF13" subcommittee="Finance and Hazardous Materials" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA15" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Branch banking"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/1998--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Provisions Applicable with Respect to Certain Foreign Insurance Companies Title II: Provisions Applicable to United States Banking Institutions Comprehensive Holocaust Accountability in Insurance Measure - Title I: Provisions Applicable with Respect To Certain Foreign Insurance Companies - Identifies those foreign insurance companies which, as a prerequisite to conducting any form of business in the United States (or with a U.S. bank), must first disclose to the Attorney General the name of any individual with whom such companies had any financial dealing and who is on the list of Jewish Holocaust Survivors maintained by the United States Holocaust Museum in Washington D.C., or the list of individuals who died in the Holocaust maintained by the Yad Veshem of Jerusalem in its Hall of Names. Directs the Attorney General to designate an office in the Department of Justice: (1) to which such disclosures shall be made; and (2) which shall make such names public. Title II: Provisions Applicable To United States Banking Institutions - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the International Banking Act of 1978 to prohibit insured depository institutions and foreign bank-controlled commercial lending companies (with a limited exception for affiliates of foreign insurance companies) from engaging in specified financial transactions with or on behalf of a foreign insurance company listed under title I (including any affiliate) during a specified period until the Attorney General publishes in the Federal Register that such company has complied with the disclosure requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
