<bill session="106" type="h" number="4010" updated="2013-07-14T18:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act Amendments of 2000</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize and amend the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400128"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2000-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E342"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-03-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, Commerce.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII15" subcommittee="Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife, and Oceans" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Plants"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/2000--Introduced.
National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act Amendments of 2000 - Amends the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act to expand the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation's authority to accept and administer private gifts within the Departments of Commerce and the Interior.(Sec. 3) Increases the Foundation's Board of Directors from 15 to 25 members, including the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Foundation to have its principal offices in Washington, D.C. (as currently provided), or in the bordering counties of Maryland or Virginia.Sets forth conditions for the Foundation to: (1) acquire and convey property, including agency approval; and (2) invest and deposit Federal funds.Revises provisions relating to agency approval of acquisitions of property and of conveyances and grants. Sets forth limitations relating to the Foundation's: (1) reconveyance of real property; and (2) expenditures for printing services or capital equipment.(Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2001 through 2006 for the Departments of Commerce and the Interior to carry out activities under the Act (conservation or management of fish, wildlife, plants, and other natural resources). Authorizes the Foundation to accept funds from a Federal agency under any other Federal law to further its conservation and management activities. Sets forth matching funds requirements.Prohibits Foundation grants from being used for litigation expenses or for lobbying Congress.Declares that nothing in this Act authorizes the Foundation to perform any function for which authority is provided to the National Park Foundation by specified Federal law.</summary>
</bill>
