<bill session="108" type="h" number="663" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Medical Mistakes bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act</title>
    <title as="passed senate" type="short">Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend title IX of the Public Health Service Act to provide for the improvement of patient safety and to reduce the incidence of events that adversely affect patient safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400028"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400054" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400062" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400106" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400122" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400124" joined="2003-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400160" joined="2003-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400161" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400166" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2003-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400258" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400296" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400342" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400390" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400391" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400400" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400431" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400438" joined="2003-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06T17:19:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 108-28.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-03-06T17:19:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="19">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bilirakis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:08:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1766-1774" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:08:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 663.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T13:22:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T17:26:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1777-1778" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2003-03-12T17:32:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="60" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 418 - 6 (Roll no. 60).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H1766-1771" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12T17:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8632-8633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 720 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_BACK:SENATE" datetime="2004-07-22" how="by Unanimous Consent" result="pass" type="vote2" where="s">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Gregg; Frist; Enzi; Alexander; Kennedy; Dodd; Jeffords.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>See also S. 720.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="720"/>
    <bill relation="supersedes" session="108" type="s" number="720"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="s" number="720"/>
    <bill relation="included-in" session="108" type="s" number="720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Accreditation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Drug adulteration"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Product coding"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/2004--Passed Senate amended.
Patient Safety and Quality Improvement Act of 2004 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to designate patient safety data as privileged and not subject to: (1) a subpoena, discovery, disclosure, or admission as evidence in any Federal, State, or local civil, criminal, or administrative proceeding; (2) disclosure pursuant to a Freedom of Information Act request; or (3) use in a disciplinary proceeding against a provider. Defines "patient safety data" as any data, reports, records, memoranda, analyses, or statements that could result in improved patient safety, health care quality, or health care outcomes. Designates patient safety data as confidential, but permits the disclosure of patient safety data by a provider or patient safety organization (PSO) if such disclosure is a voluntary disclosure of non-identifiable data or if such data: (1) contains evidence, to be used in a criminal proceeding, of a wanton and criminal act to directly harm the patient; (2) is disclosed to a provider or patient safety organization to carry out patient safety organization activities; (3) is disclosed to carry out authorized patient safety research; (4) is disclosed to an accrediting body of a provider; or (5) is voluntarily disclosed for public health surveillance with the consent of each provider who provided or who is identified in such data. Defines "patient safety organization" as an organization certified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services that conducts efforts to improve patient safety and the quality of health care delivery through the collection and analysis of patient safety data. Declares that privilege and confidentiality of patient safety data continues for disclosures under this Act, except for data that is disclosed in open court or that is non-identifiable. Prohibits any action against a PSO to compel disclosure of information, unless such information is specifically identified, is not patient safety data, and cannot otherwise be obtained. Prohibits an accrediting body from: (1) taking any accrediting action against a provider based on the provider's good faith participation in collecting, developing, reporting or maintaining patient safety data; or (2) requiring a provider to reveal its communications with any PSO. Prevents a provider from taking an adverse employment action against an individual based upon the good faith reporting of information. Allows the Secretary to impose and collect fines for the negligent or intentional disclosure of patient safety data in violation of the confidentiality provisions of this Act. Allows civil actions for violations of this Act. Provides that the privilege provided for under this Act does not apply to States or State entities, unless such State has consented to be subject to such civil actions. Declares that this Act does not: (1) limit other privileges available that provide greater confidentiality protections under Federal, State, or local laws; (2) affect the requirements of Federal, State, or local law pertaining to patient-related data that is not privileged or confidential under this Act; (3) affect the implementation of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 or the Social Security Act; (4) limit the authority of providers or PSOs from contracting to require greater confidentiality or delegate the authority to make permitted disclosures; or (5) prohibit a provider from reporting crime to law enforcement authorities, so long as the provider does not disclose patient safety data in making such a report. Requires the Secretary to maintain a patient safety network of databases that has the capacity to accept, aggregate, and analyze non-identifiable patient safety data voluntarily reported and that provides an interactive resource for providers and PSOs. Allows the Secretary to determine common formats for reporting to the databases. Provides that such formats shall be consistent with the administration simplification provisions of the Social Security Act. Requires PSOs to submit an initial certification to the Secretary and to renew their certification every three years. Requires the Secretary to: (1) compile and maintain a current list of certified PSOs; and (2) remove from the list entities whose certification expires or is revoked. Makes provisions for the patient safety data if a PSO's certification is expired or revoked. Allows the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, to provide technical assistance to PSOs. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop or adopt voluntary national standards, within three years, to promote the electronic exchange of health care information; (2) provide for the ongoing review and periodic updating of these standards; and (3) disseminate these standards and updates. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to contract with a research organization to study: (1) the extent to which labor and technological advances have contributed to increased national spending on health care; (2) the extent to which the early introduction and integration of innovative medical technologies and therapies may affect the overall productivity and quality of health care; and (3) the relationship of such technologies and therapies to patient safety, patient benefit, health care quality, and health care costs. Sets forth reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
