<bill session="105" type="h" number="2883" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-03-12T13:22:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-03-12T13:22:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Government Performance and Results bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Government Performance and Results Act Technical Amendments of 1997</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Government Performance and Results Act Technical Amendments of 1998</title>
    <title as="passed house" type="short">Government Performance and Results Act Technical Amendments of 1998</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend provisions of law enacted by the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 to improve Federal agency strategic plans and performance reports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400506" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1997-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300096" joined="1998-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1998-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-03-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 12.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-10T12:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Government Reform. H. Rept. 105-429.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1998-03-10T12:51:00-05:00" calendar="Union" number="244">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 244.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-03-11T17:52:00-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 384 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2883 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T11:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 384 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T11:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 384.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1122-1135" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T11:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2883 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight now printed in the bill. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T11:23:00-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 384 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T11:23:00-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Kevin Brady to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T11:23:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T12:33:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE ON AMENDMENTS - The Committee of the Whole will proceed with debate on all amendments under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2883.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T12:59:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12T13:22:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="1998-03-12T13:22:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="50" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 242 - 168 (Roll No. 50).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-03-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="105" type="hr" number="384"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h524"/>
    <amendment number="h525"/>
    <amendment number="h526"/>
    <amendment number="h527"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/12/1998--Passed House amended.
Government Performance and Results Act Technical Amendments of 1998 - Amends provisions of Federal law enacted by the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 to require the annual strategic plans of agencies to: (1) be explicitly linked to their statutory or other legal authorities; (2) identify agency functions that are similar to those of either more than one component of the agency or to those of other agencies and explain coordination efforts; (3) describe certain major management problems and measures to resolve such problems; (4) assess the reliability of the agency's data sources; (5) set forth requirements concerning the format of the plan; and (6) apply plan requirements to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Reserve banks, but only with respect to operations and functions that are not directly related to the establishment and conduct of U.S. monetary policy. Prohibits the Federal Reserve Board and banks from being required to submit strategic plans to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget. Requires the Director to prepare and submit to the Congress an annual integrated Federal Government performance report which shall include actual results and accomplishments from the previous fiscal year. Sets forth provisions for inspector general review of annual performance plans and annual program performance reports of agencies. Requires the full costs of each program activity to be used as performance indicators with respect to such performance plans. Prohibits the Federal Reserve Board and banks from being required to submit annual performance plans to the Director. Requires the Board and banks to submit to the Congress such performance plans containing the information required, but only with respect to operations and functions that are not directly related to the establishment and conduct of U.S. monetary policy. Prohibits the Board and banks from being required to submit program performance reports to the President. Prohibits the Director from exempting the Council on Environmental Quality from agency requirements of the Act relating to performance plans, program performance reports, and strategic plans. Amends provisions of Federal law enacted by the Chief Financial Officers Act of 1990 to: (1) extend the deadline for agencies to submit the first of annual audited financial statements; and (2) require that such statements be submitted to the Congress (in addition to the Director).</summary>
</bill>
