<bill session="105" type="h" number="2708" updated="2013-07-14T18:50:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1997-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1997-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1997-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Enhancement of Trade, Security, and Human Rights through Sanctions Reform Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide a framework for consideration by the legislative and executive branches of unilateral economic sanctions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404996"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400568" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400033" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400036" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400037" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400046" joined="1998-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400500" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400058" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400573" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="402516" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400532" joined="1998-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400548" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400084" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300030" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400094" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400112" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1998-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400121" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400581" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404280" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404375" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400148" joined="1997-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400170" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400171" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400502" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400199" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400201" joined="1997-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400203" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="406343" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400218" joined="1998-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400228" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400229" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400245" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400529" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400508" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400252" joined="1997-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400597" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400599" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400283" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400284" joined="1998-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400292" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400294" joined="1998-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400298" joined="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400601" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400308" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400602" joined="1998-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400316" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400323" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400325" joined="1998-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1998-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="409087" joined="1998-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400520" joined="1998-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400348" joined="1998-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="1998-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400607" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400367" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400373" joined="1998-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400381" joined="1998-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400382" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410136" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400383" joined="1997-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300093" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1998-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300095" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1998-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400396" joined="1998-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400404" joined="1998-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1998-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400540" joined="1998-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400429" joined="1998-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Banking and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-23">
      <text>Referred to House Banking and Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2080-2081"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-10-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy.</text>
      <committee name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1997-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
      <committee name="House International Relations"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House International Relations"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking and Financial Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="Domestic and International Monetary Policy" name="House Banking and Financial Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="105" type="s" number="1413"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Federal mandates"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/1997--Introduced.
Enhancement of Trade, Security, and Human Rights Through Sanctions Reform Act - Declares that it is the purpose of this Act to establish an effective framework for consideration by the legislative and executive branches of unilateral economic sanctions. (Sec. 3) Declares that it is U.S. policy to: (1) pursue U.S. interests through vigorous and effective diplomatic, political, commercial, charitable, educational, cultural, and strategic engagement with other countries, while recognizing that U.S. national security interests may sometimes require the imposition of economic sanctions on other countries; (2) foster multilateral cooperation on vital matters of U.S. foreign policy, including promoting human rights and democracy, combating international terrorism, proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, and international narcotics trafficking, and ensuring adequate environmental protection; (3) promote U.S. economic growth and job creation by expanding exports of goods, services, and agricultural commodities, and by encouraging investment that supports the sale abroad of U.S. products and services; (4) maintain the reputation of U.S. businesses and farmers as reliable suppliers to international customers of quality products and services; (5) avoid the use of restrictions on exports of agricultural commodities as a foreign policy weapon; and (6) oppose policies of other countries designed to discourage economic interaction with countries friendly to the United States or with any U.S. national, and to avoid use of such measures as instruments of U.S. foreign policy. States that when economic sanctions are necessary, it is U.S. policy to: (1) target them as narrowly as possible on those foreign governments, entities, and officials that are responsible for the conduct being targeted, thereby minimizing unnecessary or disproportionate harm to individuals who are not responsible for such conduct; and (2) to the extent feasible, avoid any adverse impact of economic sanctions on the humanitarian activities of the United States and foreign nongovernmental organizations in a country against which sanctions are imposed. (Sec. 5) Provides that any bill or joint resolution imposing or authorizing the imposition of a unilateral economic sanction by the executive branch, and considered by the House of Representatives or the Senate, should: (1) state the U.S. foreign policy or national security objective; (2) terminate after two years unless specifically reauthorized; (3) provide for contract sanctity; (4) provide presidential authority to adjust or waive the sanction in the national interest; (5) target the sanction as narrowly as possible against the parties responsible for the conduct being targeted; and (6) provide for expanded export promotion programs if sanctions are likely to target an export market for American farmers. (Sec. 6) Sets forth a procedure for congressional consideration of any bill or joint resolution that imposes, or authorizes the imposition of, any unilateral economic sanction by the executive branch. Requires the committee of primary jurisdiction reporting such a bill or joint resolution to timely request specified reports: (1) from the President assessing the likelihood that the proposed unilateral economic sanction will achieve its stated objective within a reasonable period of time, as well as the impact of the proposed unilateral economic sanction on U.S. foreign policy, national security, and humanitarian activities; and (2) from the Secretary of Agriculture assessing the extent to which any country or countries proposed or likely to be sanctioned are markets that accounted for more than three percent of all U.S. agricultural export sales in the preceding calendar year, as well as the likelihood that U.S. agricultural exports will be affected by the proposed sanction or by retaliation by any country proposed or likely to be sanctioned, and specific commodities which are most likely to be affected. Considers any bill or joint resolution that imposes any unilateral economic sanction to include a Federal private sector mandate for purposes of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995. Requires the Congressional Budget Office, in its report pursuant to such Act, to assess the likely short- and long-term costs of the proposed sanction to the U.S. economy. Authorizes the President to implement a unilateral economic sanction under any provision of law not less than 60 days after announcing his intention to do so. Requires any executive sanction to include a clear finding that the sanction is likely to achieve a specific U.S. foreign policy or national security objective within a reasonable and specified period of time. Requires, before imposition of a unilateral economic sanction, that the President and the Secretary of Agriculture report to appropriate congressional committees the same assessments required in connection with any bill or joint resolution imposing or authorizing the imposition of a unilateral economic sanction by the executive branch. Requires the President to request a report by the U.S. International Trade Commission on the likely short- and long-term costs of the proposed sanction to the U.S. economy, including the potential impact on U.S. competitiveness. Provides, in the case of a national emergency, for allowing the President temporarily to waive most of the requirements for executive action in order to act immediately, generally requiring the waived requirements to be met within 60 days after imposition of the sanction (which shall terminate after 90 days if such requirements are not met). Directs the President to establish an interagency Sanctions Review Committee to coordinate U.S. policy regarding unilateral economic sanctions and provide appropriate recommendations to the President.</summary>
</bill>
