<bill session="108" type="hr" number="645" updated="2013-07-14T19:00:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-05-18T11:52:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-18T11:52:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2728) to amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to provide for the adjudicative flexibility with regard to an employer filing of a notice of contest following the issuance of a citation by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2729) to amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to provide for greater efficiency at the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission; for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2730) to amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to provide for an independent review of citations issued by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2731) to amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to provide for the award of attorney's fees and costs to very small employers when they prevail in litigation prompted by the issuance of citations by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; and for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2432) to amend the Paperwork Reduction Act and titles 5 and 31, United States Code, to reform Federal paperwork and regulatory processes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 108-497, by Mr. Sessions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T22:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2728, H.R. 2729, H.R. 2730, H.R. 2731 and H.R. 2432.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-05-17T22:24:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="178">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 178.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T10:29:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3099-3106" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T10:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 645.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T11:27:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3105" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="2004-05-18T11:52:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="180" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 195 (Roll no. 180).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3099-3100" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T11:52:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2432"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2432"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2728"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2728"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2729"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2729"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2729"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2730"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2730"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2730"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2731"/>
    <bill relation="ruled-by" session="108" type="h" number="2731"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="2731"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/2004--Passed House without amendment.
Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 2728 (filing of a notice of contest by an employer following the issuance of a citation by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA)), H.R. 2729 (concerning the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission), H.R. 2730 (relating to review of citations issued by OSHA), H.R. 2731 (awarding of fees and costs to very small employers when they prevail in litigation prompted by such citations), and H.R. 2432 (revising Federal paperwork and regulatory processes).</summary>
</bill>
