<bill session="107" type="hc" number="482" updated="2013-07-14T18:59:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Encouraging improved cooperation with the Russian Federation on energy development issues, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400428"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House International Relations</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-09-24">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Former Soviet states"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum engineering"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/24/2002--Introduced.
Calls for the Governments of the Russian Federation and the United States, in proceeding with an energy dialogue, to consult widely with the governments of other independent states of the former Soviet Union and with other interested parties to promote exchanges and to seek support from the broadest cross-section of business and civil societies.Declares that Congress is committed to: (1) terminating the application of the Jackson-Vanik Amendment to Russia; and (2) authorizing the extension of normal trade relations to Russian products.Expresses support for: (1) the actions of the Russian Government and Duma to reform the structure of the Russian energy sector to attract international investment and to permit full implementation of energy projects on Sakhalin Island and in the Timan-Pechora region; and (2) continued high level and sustained exchanges on energy development between the U.S. and Russian Governments and between businesses in the two countries.Encourages: (1) regulatory and investment framework in the Russian Federation to expand Russia's oil and gas export capacities; and (2) Russia to work toward accession to the World Trade Organization in a manner that promotes meaningful market access opportunities for U.S. workers, businesses, and farmers.</summary>
</bill>
