<bill session="107" type="h" number="2100" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Twenty-First Century Distance Learning Enhancement Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend chapter 1 of title 17, United States Code, relating to the exemption of certain performances or displays for educational uses from copyright infringement provisions, to provide that the making of copies or phonorecords of such performances or displays is not an infringement under certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400196" joined="2001-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400271" joined="2001-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1076"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on the Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Copyright infringement"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Phonorecords"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/2001--Introduced.
Twenty-First Century Distance Learning Enhancement Act - Revises Federal copyright law to extend the exemption from infringement liability for instructional broadcasting to: (1) digital distance learning or distance education; and (2) nonprofit libraries (as well as governmental bodies and accredited nonprofit educational institutions, as at present). Excludes from such exemption (thus subjecting to infringement liability) any work produced or marketed primarily for performance or display as part of mediated instructional activities transmitted via digital networks, or a performance or display given by means of a copy or phonorecord that is not lawfully made and acquired, and the transmitting government body, accredited nonprofit educational institution, or nonprofit library knew or had reason to believe was not lawfully made and acquired. Allows under specified instructional conditions the performance and display of reasonable and limited portions of any copyrighted work in an amount comparable to that which is typically displayed in the course of a live classroom session, by or in the course of a transmission.Exempts from infringement liability, under specified conditions, governmental bodies, accredited nonprofit educational institutions, and nonprofit libraries by reason of the transient or temporary storage of material carried out through the automatic technical process of a digital transmission of the performance or display of that material.Extends the current ephemeral recording exemption, under specified conditions, to copies or phonorecords embodying a performance or display in digital and analog form for use in making transmissions authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
