<bill session="108" type="h" number="3813" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">George R. Brown Near-Earth Object Survey Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for a Near-Earth Object Survey program to detect, track, catalogue, and characterize certain near-earth asteroids and comets.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400343"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Science"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY16" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" name="House Science"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Asteroids"/>
    <term name="Astronomy"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/11/2004--Introduced.
George R. Brown Near-Earth Object Survey Act - Requires the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to plan, develop, and implement a Near-Earth Object Survey program to detect, track, catalogue, and characterize the physical characteristics of near-Earth asteroids and comets at least 100 meters in diameter in order to assess the threat of such near-Earth objects striking the Earth. Amends the National Aeronautics and Space Act to declare that the general welfare and security of the United States requires that the unique competence of NASA in science and engineering systems be directed to provide warning and mitigation of the potential hazard of near-Earth objects impacting the Earth.</summary>
</bill>
