<bill session="105" type="hr" number="525" updated="2013-07-14T18:49:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1998-09-11T12:00:00-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1998-09-11T12:00:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1998-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Impeachment Review resolution</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Providing for a deliberative review by the Committee on the Judiciary of a communication from an independent counsel, and for the release thereof, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1998-09-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7581"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1998-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1998-09-10T21:33:00-04:00" calendar="House" number="245">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 245.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1998-09-10T21:33:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 105-703, by Mr. Solomon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T09:07:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7587-7607" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T09:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the order of the House of Sept. 10, 1998, the House proceeded with two hours of debate on the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T11:39:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1998-09-11T12:00:00-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="425" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 363 - 63 (Roll No. 425).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1998-09-11T12:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Origin, Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Clinton Administration"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="House Judiciary"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Impeachments"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Presidential ethics"/>
    <term name="Special prosecutors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/10/1998--Introduced.
Provides for a review by the House Committee on the Judiciary of the communication received on September 9, 1998, from an independent counsel, transmitting a determination that substantial and credible information received by the independent counsel in carrying out his mandated responsibilities may constitute grounds for an impeachment of the President, and related matters, to determine whether sufficient grounds exist to recommend to the House that an impeachment inquiry be commenced. Provides for certain portions of such transmitted material to be printed as a House document. Deems the balance of such material to have been received in executive session and requires its release from such status on September 28, 1998, except as otherwise determined by the Committee. Requires the released material to immediately be printed as a House document. Deems additional material compiled by the Committee during the review as received in executive session unless it is received in an open session of the Committee. Restricts access to executive-session material of the Committee relating to the review to members of the Committee, and to such employees of the Committee that are designated by the chairman after consultation with the ranking minority member. Requires each meeting, hearing, or deposition of the Committee relating to the review to be conducted in executive session unless otherwise determined by an affirmative vote of the Committee, a majority being present. Limits attendance at such session to members of the Committee and to such employees of the Committee that are designated by the chairman after consultation with the ranking minority member.</summary>
</bill>
