<bill session="106" type="h" number="102" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">National Youth Crime Prevention Demonstration Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide grants to grassroots organizations in certain cities to develop youth intervention models.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1999-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Youth and Families.</text>
      <committee name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Crime Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED11" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Youth and Families" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Delinquency prevention"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Indiana"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Police-community relations"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Youth violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1999--Introduced.
National Youth Crime Prevention Demonstration Act - Directs the Attorney General to make a five-year national youth crime prevention demonstration project grant to the National Center for Neighborhood Enterprise, a not-for-profit organization incorporated in the District of Columbia. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Center to award grants to grassroots organizations to develop youth intervention models in the following cities: (1) Washington, D.C.; (2) Detroit, Michigan; (3) Hartford, Connecticut; (4) Indianapolis, Indiana; (5) Chicago (and surrounding metropolitan area), Illinois; (6) San Antonio, Texas; (7) Dallas, Texas; and (8) Los Angeles, California. (Sec. 4) Requires eligible grassroots entities to: (1) be not-for-profit community organizations with demonstrated effectiveness in mediating and addressing youth violence by empowering at-risk youth to become agents of peace and community restoration; and (2) submit grant applications to the Center to fund intervention models that establish violence-free zones. Requires the Center to consider the grassroots entity's: (1) track record (and that of its key participating individuals) in youth group mediation and crime prevention; (2) engagement and participation with other local organizations; and (3) ability to enter into partnerships with local housing authorities, law enforcement agencies, and other public entities. (Sec. 5) Authorizes use of grant funds for youth mediation, youth mentoring, life skills training, job creation and entrepreneurship, organizational development and training, development of long-term intervention plans, collaboration with law enforcement, comprehensive support services and local agency partnerships, and activities to further community objectives in reducing youth crime and violence. Directs the Center to identify local lead grassroots entities in each designated city which include: (1) the Alliance of Concerned Men of Washington in the District of Columbia; (2) the Hartford Youth Peace Initiative in Hartford, Connecticut; (3) the Family Help-Line in Los Angeles, California; (4) the Victory Fellowship in San Antonio, Texas; and (5) similar grassroots entities in other designated cities. Requires the Center, in cooperation with the Attorney General, also to provide technical assistance for startup projects in other cities. (Sec. 6) Directs the Center to evaluate and report to the Attorney General on the effectiveness of grassroots agencies and other public entities involved in such demonstration project. (Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
