<bill session="108" type="h" number="4663" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-25T00:14:00-04:00">FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-25T00:14:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Spending Control Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend part C of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to establish discretionary spending limits and a pay-as-you-go requirement for mandatory spending.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400298"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T08:00:00-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 692 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4663 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T14:05:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 692 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T15:58:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 692.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4898-4908" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 6/25/2004 H6970-6972" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4663 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 692 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T15:59:00-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4663.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:13:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:22:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brady (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Brady (TX) demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Chocola amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:32:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Chocola amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Chocola demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:33:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castle amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:44:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Castle amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Spratt demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Spratt demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T17:57:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T18:10:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Spratt demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:04:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4663 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:09:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Dreier asked unanimous consent that during futher consideration of H.R. 4663 pursuant to H. Res. 692, amendment number 18 in House Report 108-566 may be considered out of sequence in the Committee of the Whole, and that amendment may be withdrawn by its proponent after debate thereon. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/25/2004 H4961-5066"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:13:00-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:14:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Young (FL) substitute amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:45:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kirk amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:52:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kirk amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Kirk demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T19:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions in H. Res. 692 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T20:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Spratt demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T20:07:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions in H. Res. 692 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T20:18:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ryan (WI) demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T20:19:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T20:32:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ryan (WI) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ryan (WI) demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T20:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Spratt amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Spratt amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Spratt demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T21:05:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T22:02:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T22:37:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T22:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 692, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Kirk amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:06:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kirk amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kirk demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:07:00-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:37:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4663.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/25/2004 H5064" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:40:00-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Stenholm moved to recommit with instructions to The Budget.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/25/2004 H5064-5065" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stenholm motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment adding a new section which extends the Pay-As-You-Go Requirement, as specified in the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, until 2009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24T23:49:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T00:07:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 218 (Roll no. 317).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T00:14:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="FAIL:ORIGINATING:HOUSE" datetime="2004-06-25T00:14:00-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="318" type="vote" where="h">
      <text>On passage Failed by recorded vote: 146 - 268 (Roll no. 318).</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="108" type="hr" number="692"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="3973"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="108" type="h" number="4649"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Budget reconciliation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway use tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h609"/>
    <amendment number="h610"/>
    <amendment number="h611"/>
    <amendment number="h612"/>
    <amendment number="h613"/>
    <amendment number="h614"/>
    <amendment number="h615"/>
    <amendment number="h616"/>
    <amendment number="h617"/>
    <amendment number="h618"/>
    <amendment number="h619"/>
    <amendment number="h620"/>
    <amendment number="h621"/>
    <amendment number="h622"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/23/2004--Introduced.
Spending Control Act of 2004 - Amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) to: (1) revise for FY 2004 discretionary spending limits (spending caps) for the highway and mass transit categories; (2) set forth for FY 2005 and 2006 new budget authority and outlays for the general purpose discretionary category, outlays for the highway category and new budget authority and outlays for the mass transit category; and (3) set forth for FY 2007 through 2009 outlays for the highway category and new budget authority and outlays for the mass transit category. Revises the requirement that the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) make adjustments to the highway category to conform to estimated levels of highway receipts. Sets forth the level of obligation limitations (sum of budget authority and obligation limitations) for the highway and mass transit categories for FY 2004 through 2009. Provides that, in any of FY 2005 through 2006, discretionary advance appropriations provided in appropriation Acts in excess of $23,558 billion shall be counted against the discretionary spending limits for the fiscal year for which the appropriation Act containing the advance appropriation is enacted. Extends PAY-AS-YOU-GO requirements through FY 2009 to provide for an offsetting sequestration for direct spending (currently, direct spending and receipts) legislation that is enacted before October 1, 2009, that causes a net increase in direct spending (currently, net deficit increase). Provides, under specified conditions, for additional new budget authority in FY 2005 or 2006 for fire suppression and for an adjustment in the discretionary spending limit for FY 2005 for appropriations for the global war on terrorism. Excludes from Congressional Budget Office (CBO) and OMB estimates certain extending provisions in the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 and the Jobs and Growth Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2003. Requires the estimates set forth in the discretionary sequestration preview and final reports issued by OMB and CBO to include the current year and each subsequent year through FY 2006 (or FY 2009 solely to enforce the discretionary spending limits for the highway and mass transit categories). Extends: (1) certain budget enforcement requirements through FY 2006 (or 2009 for enforcement of spending caps for highway and mass transit categories); and (2) PAY-AS-YOU-GO requirements through FY 2013.</summary>
</bill>
