<bill congress="106" type="hr" number="5373" updated="2012-10-31T13:25:22-05:00">
  <status datetime="2000-10-12">REFERRED</status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Social Security Guarantee Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To guarantee the right of individuals to receive Social Security benefits under title II of the Social Security Act in full with an accurate annual cost-of-living adjustment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor state="CO" title="Rep" thomas_id="1592" district="6" name="Tancredo, Thomas G."/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor name="Aderholt, Robert B." district="4" title="Rep" state="AL" sponsored_at="2000-10-10" thomas_id="1460"/>
    <cosponsor name="DeMint, Jim" district="4" title="Rep" state="SC" sponsored_at="2000-10-16" thomas_id="1605"/>
    <cosponsor name="Jones, Walter B., Jr." district="3" title="Rep" state="NC" sponsored_at="2000-10-03" thomas_id="612"/>
    <cosponsor name="McCollum, Bill" district="8" title="Rep" state="FL" sponsored_at="2000-10-03" thomas_id="761"/>
    <cosponsor name="Schaffer, Bob" district="4" title="Rep" state="CO" sponsored_at="2000-10-05" thomas_id="1524"/>
    <cosponsor name="Toomey, Patrick J." district="15" title="Rep" state="PA" sponsored_at="2000-10-10" thomas_id="1594"/>
    <cosponsor name="Vitter, David" district="1" title="Rep" state="LA" sponsored_at="2000-10-05" thomas_id="1609"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <referral datetime="2000-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </referral>
    <referral datetime="2000-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </referral>
  </actions>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary date="2000-10-03" status="Introduced">Social Security Guarantee Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to issue to each individual receiving benefits under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) and, thereafter, to each individual who applies for such benefits, a certificate representing a legally enforceable guarantee: (1) of the monthly amount of benefits that the individual will receive under that title, as determined on the certificate's date of issuance; and (2) that the benefits will be adjusted at least annually on the basis of an accurate determination of the increase in the individual's cost-of-living, and as a result in a change in the eligibility status of the individual under that title.States that any certificate issued under the authority of this Act constitutes budget authority in advance of appropriations Acts and represents the obligation of the Federal Government to provide for the payment to the individual to whom the certificate is issued OASDI benefits in the amounts set forth in the certificate and subsequently adjusted.</summary>
</bill>
