<bill session="106" type="h" number="5628" updated="2013-07-14T18:55:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="2000-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2000-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2000-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Common Sense Patients' Bill of Rights Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a patients' bill of rights, patient access to information, and accountability of health plans, and to expand access to health care coverage through tax incentives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400368"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400004" joined="2000-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400576" joined="2000-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400606" joined="2000-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2000-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Education and the Workforce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-03">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
      <committee name="House Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2000-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Ambulances"/>
    <term name="Business income tax"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cancer research"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Class actions (Civil procedure)"/>
    <term name="Clergy"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Flexible benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health counseling"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Health insurance industry"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Personal income tax"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
    <term name="Physician-patient privilege"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Psychotherapy"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religion and medicine"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
    <term name="Terminally ill"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/2000--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: Patients' Bill of Rights Subtitle A: Right to Advice and Care Subtitle B: Right to Information About Plans And Providers Subtitle C: Right to Hold Health Plans Accountable Subtitle D: State Flexibility in Applying Requirements to Health Insurance Issuers Subtitle E: Effective Dates; Coordination in Implementation; Miscellaneous Provisions Title II: Remedies Title III: Health Care Coverage Access Tax Incentives Title IV: Health Care Paperwork Common Sense Patients' Bill of Rights Act - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), the Public Health Service Act (PHSA), and the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to: (1) provide for a patients' bill of rights, patient access to information, and accountability of health plans; and (2) expand access to health care coverage through tax incentives.Title I: Patients' Bill Of Rights - Subtitle A: Right Advice and Care - Establishes patients' rights to medical advice and care (under ERISA, PHSA, and IRC).Subtitle B: Right to Information About Plans And Providers - Establishes patients' rights to information about plans and providers.Subtitle C: Right To Hold Health Plans Accountable - Establishes patients' rights to hold health plans accountable.Subtitle D: State Flexibility in Applying Requirements to Health Insurance Issuers - Provides for State flexibility in applying requirements to health insurance issuers.Subtitle E: Effective Dates; Coordination in Implementation; Miscellaneous Provisions - Provides for coordination in implementation.Title II: Remedies - Amends ERISA to provide for: (1) availability of, and limitations on, court remedies relating to medically reviewable determinations and timely review of claims; and (2) expanded court remedies relating to group health plan determinations that are not medically reviewable.Title III: Health Care Coverage Access Tax Incentives - Amends the IRC with respect to medical savings accounts (MSAs) to: (1) repeal certain limitations on availability; (2) expand availability beyond employees of small employers and self-employed individuals; (3) increase the amount of allowable tax deduction for contributors; (4) allow both employers and employees to contribute; (5) reduce permitted deductibles under high-deductible heath plans, but provide for cost-of-living adjustments; (6) allow MSAs to be offered under cafeteria plans; and (7) direct the Comptroller General to study and report on the impact of MSAs on the cost of conventional insurance.Allows a tax deduction for 100 percent of the health insurance costs of self-employed individuals.Title IV: Health Care Paperwork - Establishes the Health Care Panel to Devise a Uniform Explanation of Benefits to devise a single form for use by third-party health care payers for remittance of claims to providers.</summary>
</bill>
