<bill session="108" type="h" number="4690" updated="2013-07-14T19:02:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Cle Elum River Corridor Act of 2004</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To transfer certain lands along the Cle Elum River in the State of Washington to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior, to support a land exchange involving a portion of such lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1254"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/2004--Introduced.
Cle Elum River Corridor Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain lands along the Cle Elum River corridor, Washington, to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary). Directs the Secretary: (1) to accept certain private lands along that corridor from MountainStar Resort Development, LLC, if offered to the Secretary within 90 days of this Act's enactment, provided that MountainStar conveys acceptable title and that there is no hazardous material on the property to be acquired by the United States; and (2) upon acceptance of title, to convey certain lands to MountainStar. Requires the exchange to be consummated on an equal value basis, except that the Secretary and MountainStar may agree to equalize the agreed-upon values of the Federal and non-Federal lands involved in the exchange through the inclusion of monetary consideration, provided that any adjustment agreed does not exceed 25 percent of the value of the Federal lands to be conveyed.</summary>
</bill>
