<bill session="106" type="hr" number="59" updated="2013-07-14T18:52:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-11-02T18:31:00-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1999-11-02T18:31:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States remains committed to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1999-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400571" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400034" joined="1999-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1999-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400150" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400156" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1999-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400265" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400603" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1999-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400395" joined="1999-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1999-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="1999-03-17">
      <text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on International Relations"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T10:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Gilman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T10:54:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11212-11218, H11339-11340" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T10:54:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T11:43:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T18:21:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASSED:SIMPLERES" datetime="1999-11-02T18:31:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="554" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 278 - 133, 1 Present (Roll no. 554).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1999-11-02T18:31:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House International Relations" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Central Europe"/>
    <term name="Collective security agreements"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crisis management"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Eastern Europe"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="NATO enlargement"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Summit diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/2/1999--Passed House amended.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) is to be commended for its pivotal role in preserving trans-Atlantic peace and stability; (2) the new NATO strategic concept, adopted by the Allies at the Summit meeting held in Washington, D.C., in April 1999 articulates a concrete vision for the Alliance in the 21st century; (3) the Alliance should as a fundamental task identify crisis management operations outside the NATO treaty area, based on case-by-case consensual Alliance decisions; (4) the Alliance must recognize and act upon the threat posed by the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction and terrorism by intensifying consultations among political and military leaders, and deploying comprehensive capabilities to counter such threats to the international community; (5) the Alliance should welcome efforts by European Union (EU) nations to strengthen their military capabilities and enhance their role within the Alliance through the European Security and Defense Identity; (6) it is essential that security arrangements elaborated under the EU's Common Foreign and Security Policy (CFSP) complement rather than duplicate NATO efforts and provide for full involvement of all European Allies; (7) the Alliance should remain prepared to extend invitations for accession negotiations to any European democracy meeting NATO membership criteria on the same conditions as applied to the Czech Republic, Hungary, and Poland; (8) NATO should seek to strengthen its relations with Russia and Ukraine as partners in building long-term peace in the Euro-Atlantic area; and (9) the Alliance should fully support the North Atlantic Assembly's activities in enhancing and stabilizing democracy in Central and Eastern Europe nations.</summary>
</bill>
