<bill session="104" type="hj" number="133" updated="2013-07-14T18:48:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400420"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Continuing resolutions"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Gay marriage"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Homosexuality"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Lesbians"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Municipal budgets"/>
    <term name="Unmarried couples"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/1995--Introduced.
Makes continuing appropriations for FY 1996, at a level that is to be no more than the current level, for the District of Columbia. (Sec. 106) Makes appropriations in this joint resolution available, unless otherwise provided for in this joint resolution or an applicable appropriations Act, until the first of the following events: (1) enactment of an appropriation for any project or activity of this joint resolution; (2) enactment of the applicable appropriations Act without any provision for such project or activity; or (3) December 27, 1995. (Sec. 107) Prohibits the expenditure of funds for any abortion except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term or where the pregnancy is the result of an act of rape or incest. (Sec. 111) Provides that if funding is not provided for an ongoing project or the projects's rate of operations is significantly reduced, it may be continued at a minimal level. Defines minimal level as the current rate reduced by 25 percent. (Sec. 116) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated under this joint resolution to implement any system of registration of unmarried cohabiting couples, whether homosexual, lesbian, or heterosexual.</summary>
</bill>
