<bill session="107" type="h" number="5614" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Energy Markets Fraud Prevention and Consumer Protection Act of 2002</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To prohibit fraudulent, manipulative, or deceptive acts in electric and natural gas markets, to provide for audit trails and transparency in those markets, to increase penalties for illegal acts under the Federal Power Act and Natural Gas Act, to reexamine certain exemptions under the Federal Power Act and the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935, to expand the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to order refunds of unjust and discriminatory rates, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="2002-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400050" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400103" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400185" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400193" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400217" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400237" joined="2002-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400259" joined="2002-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400295" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400350" joined="2002-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="2002-10-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2002-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2002-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Air Quality" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporate collapse"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Gas companies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Holding companies"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Market manipulation"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Perjury"/>
    <term name="Postal crimes"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Robbery"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2002--Introduced.
Energy Markets Fraud Prevention and Consumer Protection Act of 2002 - Declares unlawful practices that are fraudulent, manipulative, deceptive, or a contrivance in contravention of Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) regulations governing: (1) transmission and sales of electric energy; or (2) transportation and sales of natural gas. Subjects such practices to certain Federal Power Act sanctions.Amends the Federal Power Act to require FERC to promulgate criteria governing waivers and exemptions from requirements regarding: (1) issuance of securities; (2) accounts and recordkeeping; and (3) officials dealing in securities (including any prospective blanket order).Places a moratorium upon such waivers and exemptions until the criteria mandated for promulgation become effective. Directs FERC to review previously issued waivers. Vitiates such waivers after a specified deadline unless they comply with such criteria.Amends the Federal Power Act and the Natural Gas Act to expand reporting requirements for transactions regarding transmission or sales of electric energy and of natural gas.Sets forth prohibitions on the distribution or publication by an electric power or natural gas information processor of quotations and transactions of electric energy and natural gas in contravention of FERC rules.Prohibits any person who owns, controls, or is under the control or ownership of a public utility, a natural gas company, or a public utility holding company from owning, controlling, or operating any electronic computer network or other multilateral trading facility utilized to trade electricity or natural gas.Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act.Mandates review by: (1) the Securities and Exchange Commission of certain exemptions granted under the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935 to determine if they should continue in force and effect; and (2) the Financial Accounting Standards Board of accounting for contracts in energy trading and risk management activities.Amends the Federal Power Act to instruct FERC to adopt rules and procedures to protect electric consumers from harmful actions taken by persons owning or controlling public utilities.Mandates annual FERC review of market-based rates for electric energy sales by a public utility. Grants FERC revocation authority for violations and for rates found to be unjust, unreasonable, unduly discriminatory, or preferential.</summary>
</bill>
