<bill session="106" type="h" number="1790" updated="2013-07-14T18:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1999-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1999-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1999-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Chemical Safety Information and Site Security Act of 1999</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To provide for public disclosure of accidental release scenario information in risk management plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400571"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health and Environment.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-05-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Commerce"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1999-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
      <committee name="House Judiciary"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU08" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative responsibility"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Industrial parks"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Risk management"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/1999--Introduced.
Chemical Safety Information and Site Security Act of 1999 - Prohibits off-site consequence analysis information (portions of risk management plans submitted by certain stationary sources under the Clean Air Act evaluating worst-case or alternative scenario accidental releases of extremely hazardous substances) from being available under Federal freedom of information provisions. Bars Federal employees from making such information available in an electronic form, except as otherwise provided by this Act. Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to make such information available in an electronic form to State or local government employees for official use only. Directs the Administrator, in response to any request for such information, including requests for risk management plans, to provide such information but only in paper form. Permits the Administrator, at the request of a State or local government officer, to provide information submitted for the stationary sources in the State in which such officer serves for official use only. Allows State or local employees to make such information available to the same extent as Federal employees are so allowed. Requires the Administrator to ensure that all risk management plans are publicly available in paper or electronic form for inspection, but not copying, during normal business hours. Permits such plans to be available in electronic form only if such form does not provide an electronic means of ranking stationary sources based on off-site consequence analysis information. Authorizes appropriations. Permits the Administrator to make such information publicly available in an electronic form that excludes information concerning the identity or location of the sources for which the information was submitted. Prohibits Federal, State, or local government employees from making such information publicly available in such form except as authorized by the Administrator. Imposes criminal penalties on Federal, State, or local government employees who knowingly violate a restriction or prohibition established by this Act. Permits the Administrator to collect and maintain records that reflect the identity of persons seeking access to information under this Act only to the extent that such actions are relevant and necessary to accomplish an EPA purpose required to be accomplished by statute or executive order. Prescribes a parallel provision for records collected by State or local agencies. Permits off-site consequence analysis information to be available in any form for official use of Federal contractors. Makes contractors subject to the same restrictions and sanctions applicable to Federal employees under this Act. Sets forth parallel provisions regarding State and local government contractors. Authorizes the Administrator to withhold, or prevent the release of, off-site consequence analysis information if the release may present an imminent and substantial endangerment to human health or welfare or the environment. (Sec. 3) Permits the Attorney General, subject to the availability of appropriations, to review industry practices regarding site security and the effectiveness of this Act. Authorizes the Attorney General to submit periodic recommendations to Congress relating to the enhancement of site security practices and the need for continued implementation or modification of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
