<bill session="104" type="h" number="2588" updated="2012-11-01T22:44:47-05:00">
  <state datetime="1995-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To nullify the 25 percent pay increase afforded to Members of Congress by the Ethics Reform Act of 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400100"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committees on House Oversight, Rules, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-07">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO09" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" subcommittee="Civil Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSHA" name="House Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSRU" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, In Committee" code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Deficit reduction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
  </subjects>
  <summary>11/07/1995--Introduced.
Declares that the basic rate of pay for Members of the House of Representatives and of the Senate shall be equal to the rate which would be payable for such positions if certain provisions of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 and the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1992 had never been enacted (thus nullifying the 25 percent pay raise provided by the former Act). Declares that if a balanced budget is achieved by the Government with respect to any fiscal year ending after the effective date of this Act, rates of pay shall be determined as if this Act had never been enacted.</summary>
</bill>
