<bill session="108" type="h" number="3176" updated="2013-07-14T19:01:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="2004-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Ojito Wilderness Act</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Ojito Wilderness Act</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To designate the Ojito Wilderness Study Area as wilderness, to take certain land into trust for the Pueblo of Zia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400434" joined="2003-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1874-1875"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2003-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Resources"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T12:10:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-717.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-10-04T12:11:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="440">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 440.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSII10" subcommittee="National Parks, Recreation, and Public Lands" name="House Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="108" type="s" number="1649"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Actions and defenses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/2004--Reported to House amended.
Ojito Wilderness Act - (Sec. 3) Designates certain public land known as the Ojito Wilderness in New Mexico (Wilderness) as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Requires that the map and a legal description of the Wilderness be filed by the Secretary of the Interior with the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the House Committee on Resources, and be made available for public inspection in offices of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM). Requires that the Wilderness by managed by the Secretary in accordance with the Wilderness Act. Provides for the addition of specified land in New Mexico to the Wilderness if such land is acquired by the Federal Government. Permits grazing of livestock in the Wilderness where grazing rights were established before the enactment of this Act. Provides that nothing in this Act affects: (1) the jurisdiction or responsibilities of New Mexico with respect to fish and wildlife in the State; or (2) any existing valid water right. Directs the Secretary to seek an exchange for State land within the boundaries of the Wilderness within three years after enactment of this Act. (Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to hold in trust certain public lands for the Pueblo of Zia (Pueblo) and include such lands as part of the Pueblo's Reservation. Requires the Pueblo to pay the Secretary the fair market value (determined by an appraisal) of such public lands placed in trust. Authorizes the Secretary to use funds paid by the Pueblo to acquire non Federal lands in New Mexico. Preserves public access to Pueblo trust lands for recreational, scenic, scientific, educational, paleontological, and conservation uses. Authorizes a civil action in the U.S. District Court for the District of New Mexico to enforce right of public access. Preserves existing rights-of-way in the trust lands. Requires the Pueblo to grant any reasonable request for rights-of-way for utilities and pipelines in the such lands.</summary>
</bill>
