<bill session="107" type="h" number="5605" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="2002-10-10T20:38:00-04:00">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2002-10-10T20:38:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2002-10-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2003</title>
    <title as="reported to house" type="short">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2003</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">Making appropriations for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and for sundry independent agencies, boards, commissions, corporations, and offices for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400420"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2002-10-10T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 107-740, by Mr. Walsh.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2002-10-10T20:38:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="460">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 460.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="2797"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="American Battle Monuments Commission"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Computers and government"/>
    <term name="Congregate housing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Early retirement"/>
    <term name="Earth movements and building"/>
    <term name="Earthquake engineering"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal home loan banks"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buyouts"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste site remediation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing policy"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Liability for toxic substances pollution damages"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Long-term care facilities"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Selective Service System"/>
    <term name="Self-help devices for the disabled"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Underground petroleum tanks"/>
    <term name="Unfunded mandates"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/10/2002--Reported to House without amendment.
Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2003 - Makes appropriations for FY 2003 for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and of Housing and Urban Development and for sundry independent agencies.Title I: Department of Veterans Affairs - Makes appropriations for the Department of Veterans Affairs for: (1) the Veterans Benefits Administration for veterans' compensation and pensions, readjustment benefits, veterans' insurance and indemnities, and veterans' housing, education, and vocational rehabilitation loan accounts; (2) the Veterans Health Administration for veterans' medical care, the Medical Care Collections Fund, medical and prosthetic research, and medical administration; and (3) departmental administration, including for the National Cemetery Administration, the Office of Inspector General, construction, the parking revolving fund, and grants to States for construction of extended care facilities and cemeteries.Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds made available under this title.(Sec. 111) Requires approval by the congressional appropriations committees of any new lease of real property by the Department of Veteran Affairs exceeding $300,000.(Sec. 112) Denies availability of Department of Veterans Affairs appropriations for hospitalization or treatment of certain veterans unless they disclose current, accurate third-party reimbursement and annual income information.(Sec. 113) Prohibits the availability of appropriations under this Act to implement certain amendments to Federal veterans law by the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Care Programs Enhancement Act of 2001 which provide for: (1) seventh priority in the patient enrollment system for certain low-income veterans; and (2) a copayment for care only 20 percent of the copayment that would otherwise be charged.(Sec. 114) Prohibits the availability of appropriations under this Act for disability compensation claims filed after enactment of a new concurrent receipt law entitling certain veterans to be paid both veterans' disability compensation and military retired pay without regard to the prohibition on duplication of benefits or the requirement to waive a specified amount of retired pay.(Sec. 115) Repeals Federal law establishing the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Services Improvement Fund. Transfers the remaining balance in such Fund to the Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Care Collections Fund.(Sec. 116) Earmarks funds for information technology initiatives to support the enterprise architecture of the Department of Veterans Affairs.(Sec. 117) Prohibits the use of funds to implement the Department of Veterans Affairs Emergency Preparedness Act of 2002 as passed by the House of Representatives on September 18, 2002.(Sec. 118) Restricts the amount of funds to be used for security training and equipment from those made available in Medical care and the Medical care collections fund.Title II: Department of Housing and Urban Development - Makes FY 2003 appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) for: (1) public and Indian housing; (2) the Public Housing Capital and Operating Funds; (3) revitalization of severely distressed public housing (HOPE VI); (4) Native American housing block grants; (5) Indian and Native Hawaiian housing loan guarantees; (6) housing opportunities for persons with AIDS; (7) Office of Rural Housing and Economic Development; (8) empowerment zones and enterprise communities; (9) community development block grants and loan guarantees; (10) brownfields redevelopment; (11) the HOME investment partnerships program; (12) homeless assistance grants; (13) housing for special populations; (14) flexible subsidy fund; (15) manufactured housing fees trust fund; (16) the Federal Housing Administration; (17) the Government National Mortgage Association; (18) housing policy development and research; (19) fair housing activities; (20) the Office of Lead Hazard Control; (21) management and administration; (22) the Office of Inspector General; (23) Working Capital Fund; and (24) the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight.Rescinds specified amounts: (1) of recaptured rental housing assistance budget authority; and (2) from the consolidated fee fund.(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used during FY 2003 to investigate or prosecute under the Fair Housing Act any otherwise lawful activities aimed at achieving or preventing government or court action.(Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (Secretary) to make housing for persons with AIDS grants to any State that qualified in FY2002 but does not qualify in FY 2003 due to decreased AIDS cases in non-metropolitan areas of the State.(Sec. 204) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2000 to extend through FY 2003 certain housing for persons with AIDS grant allocation provisions between Philadelphia and New Jersey.Requires: (1) the Secretary to allocate to Wake County, North Carolina, certain FY 2003 housing for persons with AIDS funds that would otherwise be allocated to Raleigh, North Carolina, on behalf of the Raleigh-Durham-Chapel Hill, North Carolina, Metropolitan Statistical Area; and (2) that the allocation be used in such Area.(Sec. 205) Declares, with respect to FY 2003 assisted living facility section 8 rental payments, that a family residing in an assisted living facility in Oakland, Macomb, Wayne, and Washtenaw Counties, Michigan, may be required to pay rent in an amount exceeding 40 percent of its monthly adjusted gross income.(Sec. 206) Requires HUD to grant awards on a competitive basis.(Sec. 207) Makes HUD funds subject to the Government Corporation Control Act or other restrictions available, without regard to limitations on administrative expenses, for legal services and services and facilities of the Federal National Mortgage Association, Government National Mortgage Association, Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, Federal Financing Bank, Federal Reserve banks, Federal Home Loan banks, and any insured bank within the meaning of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.(Sec. 208) Limits HUD spending to amounts set forth in budget estimates submitted to Congress.(Sec. 209) Authorizes HUD corporations and agencies subject to the Government Corporation Control Act to make necessary FY 2003 expenditures without regard to fiscal year limitations. Limits the use of collections of these corporations and agencies (with specified exceptions) to new loan or mortgage purchase commitments only to the extent expressly provided for in this Act, unless they are in support of other forms of assistance provided in this or prior appropriations Acts.(Sec. 210) Prohibits the obligation or expenditure by HUD of funds provided in this title for technical assistance, training, or management improvements unless HUD provides to the Committees on Appropriations a description of each proposed activity and detailed budget estimates of the costs associated with each program, project, or activity.Title III: Independent Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 2003 for: (1) the American Battle Monuments Commission; (2) the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board; (3) the Department of the Treasury, Community Development Financial Institutions Fund Program Account; (4) the Consumer Product Safety Commission; (5) the Corporation for National and Community Service; (6) the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; (7) the Department of Defense-Civil for cemeterial expenses, Army; (8) the Department of Health and Human Services, National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences; (9) the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry; (10) the Environmental Protection Agency; (11) the Hazardous Substance Superfund, including transfers of funds; (12 ) the Executive Office of the President, Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Council on Environmental Quality, and the Office of Environmental Quality; (13) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, Office of Inspector General; (14) the Federal Emergency Management Agency; (15) the General Services Administration, General Citizen Information Center Fund; (16) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); (17) the National Credit Union Administration; (18) the National Science Foundation; (19) the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation; and (20) the Selective Service System.Title IV: General Provisions - Sets forth conditions and limitations on the obligation and expenditure of funds appropriated or made available under this Act.(Sec. 409) Expresses the sense of Congress that, to the greatest extent practicable, all equipment and products purchased with funds made available in this Act should be American-made.(Sec. 415) Encourages all Departments and agencies funded under this Act, within the limits of existing statutory authorities and funding, to expand their use of "E-Commerce" technologies and procedures in the conduct of their business practices and public service activities.(Sec. 417) Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to reduce from 15 percent to 7.5 percent of the estimated aggregate amount of repair and replacement grants the total amount of contributions the President may make for hazard mitigation measures for a major disaster.(Sec. 418) Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to allow the Consumer Product Safety Commission to promulgate new or amended requirements for low-speed electric personal assistive mobility devices.(Sec. 419) Amends the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Act of 1958 to: (1) establish a NASA working capital fund; (2) permit NASA to enter into enhanced-use leases of real property; and (3) authorize the NASA Administrator to convey utility systems to a municipal, private, regional, district, or cooperative utility company or other qualified entity.(Sec. 422) Amends the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Federal Employment Reduction Assistance Act of 1996 to extend the NASA voluntary separation incentive program from FY 2002 through 2005.(Sec. 423) Declares that amounts provided in the Department of Defense and Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Recovery from and Response to Terrorist Acts on the United States Act, 2002 (P.L. 107-117) and subsequent appropriations Acts for the construction of emergency operations centers (or similar facilities) shall only require a 25 percent non-Federal cost share (making the mandatory Federal cost share 75 percent).</summary>
</bill>
