<bill session="107" type="h" number="1843" updated="2013-07-14T18:57:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2001-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to local educational agencies for teacher recruitment, retention, and training, and to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to expand the program of loan forgiveness for teachers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400158"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Education and the Workforce"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED13" subcommittee="21st Century Competitiveness" name="House Education and the Workforce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher salaries"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/2001--Introduced.
Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a new program for teacher recruitment, retention, and training. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to local educational agencies to recruit, retain, and train high-quality teachers through one or more specified types of activities.Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise student loan forgiveness for teachers under the Federal Family Education Loan and Federal Direct Loan programs. Expands forgiveness eligibility by: (1) eliminating requirements allowing only certain new borrowers to participate; and (2) increasing the types of eligible teaching locations and subjects. Eliminates a service requirement that an individual teach at least five consecutive complete school years before being eligible for program benefits. Increases to $20,000 the aggregate amount of an individual teacher's student loan obligation which may be forgiven, and revises the rate of repayment.</summary>
</bill>
