<bill session="107" type="h" number="3008" updated="2013-07-14T18:58:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="2001-12-06T11:47:00-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2001-12-06T11:47:00-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2001-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Import Competition bill</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To reauthorize the trade adjustment assistance program under the Trade Act of 1974.</title>
    <title as="amended by house" type="official">To reauthorize the trade adjustment assistance program under the Trade Act of 1974, and for other purposes</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400117" joined="2001-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400123" joined="2001-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400337" joined="2001-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="2001-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-10-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </action>
    <calendar state="REPORTED" datetime="2001-10-05">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
      <committee name="House Committee on Ways and Means"/>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-10-16T18:16:00-04:00">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 107-244.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2001-10-16T18:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" number="149">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 149.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T09:44:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T09:45:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8953-8960, H8970-8971" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T09:45:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3008.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T10:32:00-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE" datetime="2001-12-06T11:47:00-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="477" type="vote" where="h" suspension="1">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 420 - 3, 1 Present (Roll no. 477).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8953-8954" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T11:47:00-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06T11:47:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2001-12-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3009"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="h" number="3009"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="107" type="s" number="1209"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/6/2001--Passed House amended.
Title I: Reauthorization of Trade Adjustment Assistance Program; Related Provisions - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations to the Department of Labor through FY 2003 for: (1) trade adjustment assistance for displaced workers and for firms; and (2) the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) Transitional Adjustment Assistance Program.Increases from 104 to 130 the maximum number of weeks an adversely affected worker who requires a program of remedial education may receive trade readjustment allowances.Reduces from 60 to 40 days the time within which the Secretary of Labor must respond to petitions for certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance.Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary, in conjunction with the States, should provide workers with more specific information about benefits, training, and other employment services, and procedures for obtaining them, under the trade adjustment assistance program.Title II: Adjustment Assistance Program for Workers Separated from Employment Due to the Terrorist Attacks of September 11, 2001 - Directs the Secretary to establish a program to provide adjustment assistance for workers separated from employment due to the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, in the same manner and to the same extent as assistance provided under NAFTA. Sets forth criteria governing when groups of workers may petition for a certification of eligibility to apply for such adjustment assistance, including that: (1) a significant number or proportion of workers have become separated or threatened with separation from employment; (2) sales or production have decreased absolutely; and (3) the events of September 11, 2001, contributed importantly to such separation and decline.Authorizes appropriations for FY 2002 and 2003.</summary>
</bill>
