<bill session="104" type="h" number="2521" updated="2013-07-14T18:47:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1995-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1995-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1995-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title as="introduced" type="short">Statistical Consolidation Act of 1995</title>
    <title as="introduced" type="official">To establish a Federal Statistical Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400506"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400012" joined="1996-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402524" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400098" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400119" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400128" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400180" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400225" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="407226" joined="1996-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400264" joined="1996-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400273" joined="1996-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="1995-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400608" joined="1996-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1996-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400385" joined="1996-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10696, E2001"/>
    </action>
    <action state="REFERRED" datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform and Oversight, and in addition to the Committee on Economic and Educational Opportunities, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Government Reform and Oversight</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-24">
      <text>Referred to House Economic and Educational Opportunities</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-10-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Information and Technology.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1995-11-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
      <committee name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1996-03-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
      <committee name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Reform and Oversight" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="National Security, International Affairs and Criminal Justice" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSGO12" subcommittee="Government Management, Information and Technology" name="House Government Reform and Oversight"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Employer-Employee Relations" name="House Economic and Educational Opportunities"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economic statistics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Population statistics"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Statistical services"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/24/1995--Introduced.
TABLE OF CONTENTS: Title I: General Provisions Title II: Establishment of the Federal Statistical Service Title III: Transfers of Functions and Offices Title IV: Administrative Provisions Subtitle A: Personnel Provisions Subtitle B: General Administrative Provisions Title V: Transitional, Savings, and Conforming Provisions Statistical Consolidation Act of 1995 - Title I: General Provisions - Sets forth congressional findings and expresses the sense of the Congress with regard to the Chief Statistician of the Office of Management and Budget, confidentiality provisions of statistical agencies, and budget and functions of the Bureau of the Census relating to decennial population censuses. Title II: Establishment of the Federal Statistical Service - Establishes an independent Federal Statistical Service (FSS) in the executive branch, headed by an Administrator, and made up of the Bureaus transferred to it by title III. Establishes within the FSS the Federal Council on Statistical Policy, which shall: (1) serve as an advisory body to the Chief Statistician on confidentiality issues; (2) set forth a Governmentwide statistical policy; and (3) study and report to the Congress on certain economic- and census-related matters. Title III: Transfers of Functions and Offices - Transfers the following entities to the Service along with all of their functions and offices: (1) the Bureau of Census of the Department of Commerce; (2) the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce; and (3) the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor. Title IV: Administrative Provisions - Subtitle A: Personnel Provisions - Specifies authorities with respect to Service officers and employees, experts and consultants, and acceptance of voluntary services. Subtitle B: General Administrative Provisions - Sets forth general administrative authorities pertaining to various specified Service matters. Title V: Transitional, Savings, and Conforming Provisions - Sets forth transitional, savings, conforming, and other specified miscellaneous provisions.</summary>
</bill>
